<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Australia" date="06-1996">
	<entry date="20-06-1996">
		<p>Having attended the previous night's Leaver's Dinner, I was left rather tired after getting up at 7.30 this morning. I got myself ready and Dad, Mum, Steven and I set off for the airport with little time to spare. We had barely begun our journey when fortunately Mum asked me to check that I had my passport. I did have a passport, but it was not mine! Luckily we had time to return and swap Mum's passport for mine.</p>
		<p>We arrived at Heathrow at 10.00 - exactly two hours before we were due to board. Adam was already in the queue, and we went straight through to book our seats. All of the check-in counters were busy, so we were sent to check in at the First Class counter. Unfortunately, we still only got Economy seats! We then met our families upstairs and found a cafe in which to have a light snack. I also needed to get a book for the flight. They did not have the one that I wanted (Arthur C. Clarke's 'Rama II'), so I got 'The Light Fantastic' by Terry Pratchett.</p>
		<p>The time came for us to go off alone, so after our farewell hugs we passed through the X-ray machines and entered the no-mans land between countries which they call the Duty Free. Adam bought some new batteries for his camera, and I found a box of chocolates to give to Aunty Nelli.</p>
		<p>At 11.30 we made our way to the departure lounge. As I was putting my passport back, the strap broke off my neck pouch, and I had to make some makeshift repairs. Once we had found our seats, we studied very carefully the operation of 'KrisVision' - Singapore Airline's interactive personal monitors. Each seat had a monitor built into the back on which it was possible to watch television, listen to music, and most importantly to play Super Nintendo games such as 'Super Mario Brothers'. For some reason however, and to our disappointment, the games were not working on this flight.</p>
		<p>Adam sat next to the window, and I sat next to him, so we both had a good view of the takeoff. During the flight, I watched a lot of television, including the films 'Broken Arrow' starring John Travolta and Christian Slater, 'The Birdcage' with Robin Williams, and the American sit-com 'Friends' three times. I couldn't manage to sleep on the plane, but I did not feel too tired when we arrived. During the flight, I ate fish for lunch and chicken for breakfast.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="01-07-1996">
		<p>We touched down at 8.30 am in Changi airport, and by 9.00 were through immigration. We each took turns to guard the luggage while the other went to the toilet, and then we found some telephones and phoned Aunty Nelli. She came from work to pick us up.</p>
		<p>As we walked out of the airport we were greeted by that familiar burst of heat and smell of Singapore. Aunty Nelli arrived and drove us to her flat where we were staying, pointing out anything interesting along the way. When we got to her flat we found out that we would be keeping fit, as we had to climb five flights of stairs to reach it.</p>
		<p>She left us at the flat, so we changed into shorts and walked to the Novena MRT station. From there we caught a train to Orchard Road, and after a bit of searching we found Scotts Shopping Center for lunch. I had won tun soup noodles with char sue and a watermelon drink, and Adam had chicken fried noodles. After lunch we went along Orchard Road to the SIA shop to reconfirm our next flight. We then looked around some of the shops. I was interested in looking at walkmen, but the shop keepers hassled me so much that I gave up. We went back to the MRT station and I had to put an extra $10 on my pass. Then we caught the train to City Hall. Here we found Nelli's office, and she pointed out places like the Convent (Mum's old school), the Singapore river and City Hall. Adam and I then went to explore.</p>
		<p>We took the glass lift up outside the Pan Pacific hotel, and then we were so hot and tired that we found a foodcourt to sit in, where I had an Ice Kachung. Afterwards, we made our way down to the river's edge and sat in a park for a while, then we gradually made our way back to Nelli's office. We were both extremely tired, so we had an early dinner at about 6.30.</p>
		<p>Nelli took us to Newton Circus for dinner. We had oluak and satay, and some noodles which were all quite spicy. We also had some coconut and sugar cane to drink. We then went back to the flat to sleep.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="02-07-1996">
		<p>We woke up late, about eleven thirty in the morning, and as we wanted to do quite a lot today we had a quick breakfast of Chelsea buns and Earl Grey tea, then left the flat.</p>
		<p>We caught the MRT to City Hall and then the bus to the World Trade Centre, from where we were planning to take a cable car across to Sentosa. As we alighted from the bus we must have looked like tourists, for an Indian man came up and asked if he could join up with us. We agreed, so we all wandered over to the cable cars. Unfortunately, maintenance was being carried out on them, so we had to catch the ferry instead. When we eventually found the ferry terminal we made our journey over to Sentosa.</p>
		<p>The first order of the day was to find some lunch over which to plan the rest of our time there. Adam had a longing for 'normal' food, so we dined at Burger King. I still managed to get some foreign flavours, however, as I had a rendang burger! It was very nice, so I actually had another one on the way back later!</p>
		<p>Our Indian friend had a flight to catch this evening, so he would have to leave us early. Therefore, we agreed to visit Underwater World first, from where he could get a bus back to the mainland over the recently constructed bridge. I had been there before, but it was still interesting. Firstly, there was the large turtle pool where huge turtles paddled lazily by. Then we saw the touching pool and I held a starfish. After this there were many fish tanks with descriptions of the fish, and then we went into the glass tunnel under the water. I remembered seeing the huge rays with their strange mouths on the bottom of their heads from my last visit. Finally we saw a short film about the coral reefs.  The Indian man then introduced himself as Richard, and promptly left.</p>
		<p>I bought a souvenir from the gift shop: a large cuddly penguin which makes burbling noises when you squeeze it. At the moment it is intended as a present for Steven, but it is so cuddly that I am thinking of keeping it for myself to take to Oxford.</p>
		<p>After Underwater World we headed for Volcano Land. We decided to walk, but it turned out to be rather further than we expected. We made it there at last, but it probably took so long because we were walking slowly. I’m beginning to get used to the heat, but it’s still uncomfortably hot outside. I don’t remember it being so oppressive last time I was here. It feels more like Bangkok!</p>
		<p>Anyway, back to Volcano Land. The map promised us a multimedia experience of the journey to the centre of the Earth, but it was a bit disappointing. Firstly some people came out dressed as Mayans and danced around the place, breathing fire and showering water everywhere. Then we went into a theme park ride a bit like ‘The Fifth Element’ at Chessington, were you walk through deserted mines and a recording tells you a story. At the end of the tunnels we sat in a large room and watched a short film supposed to be depicting the formation of the planets and the evolution of life on Earth. Then we were interrupted by a huge voice claiming to be the god of fire, who ruled this domain and didn’t take kindly to tourists from the surface. The effect was spoiled slightly by Chinese subtitles on the screen!</p>
		<p>Then came the promised earthquake. I was expecting something at least as violent as the old earthquake simulator at the Geology museum in London. However, it was more of a mild tremor which would hardly be detectable on the Richter scale. One good part of Volcano Land was when a Mayan high priestess called Crystal asked us if we would like to have our pictures taken with a snake. She waited until it was around our necks before she revealed that it was not venomous but a constrictor. She told us that it wouldn't bite us; it would strangle us instead!</p>
		<p>After that brief encounter we saw the musical fountain dancing to 'In the hall of the Mountain King'. Even though it was in daylight it was very good. Then we went to the new Merlion attraction. It is this huge Merlion in the middle of the island from the top of which we could survey the whole of Sentosa. At night it is supposed to blow smoke out of its mouth and shoot lasers out of its eyes! We then got lost as we tried to find the food court, and spent over an hour walking all the way over to the other side of the island and back. At least we had worked up an appetite! We went to the Sentosa Food Court for dinner, where we both had chicken rice. I had a papaya juice drink, but it was very weak. On the way back to the ferry terminal I had another rendang burger.</p>
		<p>We caught the ferry back at about ten to eight, and then got the bus to the zoo. Here, we went on the night safari. A tram took us around the zoo while a commentator pointed out the animals. They let us off at one point to follow a walking trail by ourselves. We saw some leopards and rhinos and many other animals up close. Unfortunately, flash photography was not allowed so I could not take any pictures. I tried one shot by sticking a plaster over the flash, but it did not work, so I didn't take any more.</p>
		<p>Aunty Nelli came and picked us up from the zoo at about midnight, and I did not get to bed until I finished writing this at 2.23 and 20 seconds a.m.</p>
		<p>PS: I bought and wrote out a postcard for Mum, Dad and Steven from Sentosa's Volcano Land.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="03-07-1996">
		<p>We got up at nine o'clock and had raisin bread for breakfast. We then went to the Westin Stanford at City Hall to meet our chauffeur called Don. He was Aunty Nancy's chauffeur, and so would take us around for the day.</p>
		<p>Firstly he took us to the Omnimax theatre at the Science Centre. He knew a lot about the buildings and areas that we passed through, so he gave us lots of information and talked a great deal. It rained during the morning, but as we were inside most of the time it did not really affect us. It was also much cooler today, although still hotter than England. At the theatre we saw a film about thunderstorms. It was more of a documentary than a film that showed off the 3D effects, but it was still good.</p>
		<p>After this we met Don again and he took us to lunch at a hawker centre opposite the Tiger Balm Gardens. Adam and I had char siew noodles with won tun soup, and Don gave us some mutton curry and some fried chicken's lung to try. The lungs tasted like spare ribs. We also had some fruit - papaya, mango, watermelon and honeydew melon.</p>
		<p>We were then taken to Jurong bird park. We had a quick look at the pelicans and hawks before we went to the' Jurong Bird Park All Star Bird Show'. They had parrots racing on bikes and talking a lot, and lots of other birds doing tricks like flying across to a member of the audience to give him a free coupon. The show was very good, and afterwards we looked at the penguins and watched them being fed. They could not eat by themselves, so the keepers had to hold their mouths open and push fish down their throats. Then we quickly had a look around the World of Darkness. However, it was so dark that we could barely make out the birds! When we had finished there, we rushed across to see the birds of prey show. The presenter had to keep on stopping because lots of loud fighter jets were flying overhead.</p>
		<p>After going to the shop, where Adam kept trying to persuade me to buy another penguin, we met Don again outside. He took us to the Tiger Balm Gardens (Haw Par Villa), but it was quite late and it was shutting soon, so we didn't bother going in. Instead, we were taken to Little India, driving past Muthus where they do banana leaf curry, to a department store where I bought my walkman for $140, or £65. We then went to Newton Circus where we had spring rolls and I had an A&amp;W root beer. When we had finished eating, we were taken to the Pine Tree Club for dinner. We were almost thrown out because they have a dress code and we were only wearing shorts and T-shirts, but then Brendan and Gabriel showed up and took us to another restaurant round the back. Neither Aunty Nancy nor Nelli were there yet, so we ordered our food. The satay arrived at the same time as my aunts.</p>
		<p>For the main course I decided to be brave and have a Singapore Laksa. It was very hot, but I managed to finish it all, and it was very nice. Adam tried some of mine and said it wasn't that hot! After this I had an Ice Kachung, and then we left. We met Uncle James very briefly outside, and Aunty Nancy gave me an um pow with $50. Then we returned to the flat and watched the X-Files. They are all avid watchers over here, and they are a series ahead of us.</p>
		<p>Aunty Nelli was very surprised to find out that I liked durians and has said that tomorrow we shall get one. She wants to see the expression on Adam's face when he tries it. She's not the only one!</p>
		<p>My postcard to my family went off today. I hope it reaches them before they leave for Perth on the tenth.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="04-07-1996">
		<p>It was our last day in Singapore, and we didn't really have any plans for the day. We met Don again outside the Westin Stanford at eleven o'clock. From there he took us to the Haw Par Villa as we would have more time to look around today.</p>
		<p>Firstly, we looked around the Ten Courts of Hell, which were inside a huge dragon. Then we went on the log flume ride. We went on it four times, and it seemed to get faster every time! It wasn't so hot today, and as we were going on the ride for the third time it poured down. Combined with the splashes from the ride, we got totally soaked.</p>
		<p>We left the Haw Par Villa at two thirty and went for lunch at a hawker centre, where I had chicken rice and oluak. After lunch, Don drove us around Arab Street to see the mosque, and then to a Malay village. He used to work as a tour guide, and knew a lot about the country. We had some pisang goreng (fried banana) which he had bought earlier, but had gone cold and tasted more like rubber. Then he took us to a durian shop. I had been telling everyone how much I liked durians, and now came my time to prove it. It tasted alright, but I didn't actually like it, and could not eat much. Adam felt the same way about it. I must have convinced myself that I liked it last time because everyone was saying how much I would hate it, and when I didn't mind it I had to prove them wrong, and said that I loved it. Oh well, at least I'll know better next time! We also had a mangosteen, which I thought was quite sour. We took some rambutans and the remains of the durian back to Aunty Nelli's.</p>
		<p>Because we thought finding a durian in her flat would not be a particularly pleasant going away present, we hung it outside the window. Don's car, however, still stank of it when we came down after changing to go to the airport. Apparently, the only thing that can clear the stench is coffee beans.</p>
		<p>We got to the airport right on time and checked in. Then I had some A&amp;W curly fries and a root beer before we boarded. I bought a new book - Rama II – and finished off The Light Fantastic on the flight. I had chicken rice for dinner, but it was nowhere near as good as the hawker stalls. I must have eaten something bad in the past few days, or maybe I wasn't used to the heat of the laksa, but I have to keep going to the toilet. I don't feel particularly ill, but I have a light diarrhoea.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="05-07-1996">
		<p>We arrived at Brisbane airport before dawn, so we waited at the airport for a while so that when we arrived in Brisbane the shops would be open. While we waited we had breakfast. I had a sausage roll which was very big. Then we caught the bus into town. The bus drivers here are almost as impatient as in Singapore. We didn't know, of course, that you can buy bus tickets from the airport so that everyone gets on the bus faster. He had a go at us for paying on the bus!</p>
		<p>We got off at Brisbane Transit Centre, where there were loads of stalls selling tours and giving information. We went to the backpackers information desk, and found out that we had left it rather late to book a room. There was only one room left, in a hostel about twenty five minutes walk from the centre of town. When we got there we found out that their Visa machine was broken, so we had to use cash. We also spent some time looking at activities leaflets and watching 'A Country Practice'. The only adverts they seemed to have were for exercise machines, or for psychics and astrologers!</p>
		<p>We made our way into town and explored a bit, then we had lunch. I had a ham sandwich and a banana. Then we went to the Transit Centre again to look for activities to do. We wanted to go to 'Wet 'n' Wild' but it was too expensive and too far away. We decided that we would like to go to the zoo to see the koalas, and to go on a riverboat tour of the city. But first we had to change some money as we were running out of cash and the banks closed over the weekend.</p>
		<p>The Transit Centre sent us to the Commonwealth bank, who said there was an American Express nearby that could change Adam's money commission free. However, it turned out to be a wild goose chase, and we couldn't find the bank. By now it was getting too late to go to the zoo, so we went to the cinema to see 'Mission: Impossible' with Tom Cruise, which was very good.</p>
		<p>After this we made our way back to the hostel, intending to find the 24 hour supermarket on the way. However, we found it to be a small Chinese supermarket, so we didn't go in. Instead, we had spaghetti bolognaise and garlic bread from an Italian cafe. We then had an early night. I had felt a bit ill throughout the whole day and had to go to the toilet nine times in various public lavatories! That must be a record.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="06-07-1996">
		<p>We needed some groceries today and we also had to get some more money. But as it is Saturday all the banks are shut. We visited the General Store at the top of the road and bought some food. We then went down the hill to a supermarket and got some chicken thighs and hair gel for me. We managed to pay with travellers cheques and so got some more cash. After dumping the groceries back at the hostel we walked to the town and got some lunch in a food centre. I had a large lamb kebab with garlic and sour cream sauce. I must be better!</p>
		<p>We then went to the Transit Centre and booked up a date with Rainforest Rob on Monday. We booked our ticket on the Greyhound buses for $159, entitling us to travel all the way up to Port Douglas if we want. We also tried booking a hostel at Bunderburg which is our next stop, but they said that they may not even have a place for us to stay, so we have to phone again on the morning we are going. If we do get a room, it will be in a dormitory (at the moment we are staying in a twin room).</p>
		<p>After all this we walked back to the hostel. We keep meaning to go on a river cruise and to visit the Lone Pine Koala Sanctuary, but we got up too late today. The squawking chickens of Singapore's pelican crossings are nothing compared to those in Brisbane. Here, the chicken clucks softly but constantly, maintaining a slow, consistent rhythm. You press the button and wait in eager anticipation. Suddenly, the chicken erupts as though it has had a long, sharp object thrust into its nether regions. It gives one piercing shriek, and then clucks maniacally until the lights change again.</p>
		<p>We got back to the hostel and I nodded off while reading. I woke up periodically to tell Adam my strange dreams about Mr Craig and puffy faced men! Eventually, Adam got me up and I cooked some chicken noodles. Adam repaid the favour by washing up. I then read until I fell asleep (or rather, I will read until I fall asleep).</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="07-07-1996">
		<p>We caught the bus to North Quay to try to go on a river cruise. Unfortunately, all the boats had already left. Therefore, we went to the Myer Centre for lunch. We bought some postcards, then we went to the basement of the Myer Centre, to the Koala stop, to catch a bus to the Lone Pine Koala Sanctuary.</p>
		<p>At the Koala Sanctuary I fed some kangaroos in the Kangaroo area where they are allowed to roam free. There were also some emus there, but no sign of Rod Hull. Then we looked at the koalas. At first they were quite difficult to spot, especially as most of them were asleep, but a few were eating. I held a koala called Vader, who has two brothers called Darth and Yoda! He was quite heavy and his claws stuck into my shoulders a bit.</p>
		<p>After catching the bus back, Adam phoned home from a call box using his Chargecard, but mine wouldn't work because it was not an international card. I tried for about half an hour to phone England using coins, but it would not accept '44' as the dialling code. Eventually I found out how to phone the information service who told me that you have to dial 0011 first. I used about four dollars to call home, but I could see the money running out as I talked, so we couldn't speak for long. I asked Mum to phone BT to make my Charge card international.</p>
		<p>We weren't very hungry, so we decided not to have dinner and to get an early night. We went to bed at seven o'clock, but I didn't get to sleep until 4 am because I was so restless. I could hear other guests watching television downstairs. They were watching the new Dr. Who movie with Paul Megan, but I had seen it before and so knew what was going on, and this kept me up. My bed was very uncomfortable with a huge dip in the middle.</p>
		<p>The weather had been beautiful today. It was very hot and there wasn't a cloud in the sky. We talked to an Australian couple at the bus stop while we waited for the bus. He had a very strong accent, so I could not make out everything he said. I did hear him say that I had a very Pommy tan though.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="08-07-1996">
		<p>We got up at seven o'clock this morning in order to meet 'Rainforest Rob' outside at eight. We waited for him for twenty minutes, then John, the owner of the hostel, came out and said that Rob phoned yesterday to tell us that he couldn't come today because his van was being serviced. Therefore, we booked in with him again for tomorrow, and also booked a tour of the Castlemaine XXXX brewery at one o'clock this afternoon.</p>
		<p>First of all we went to the Myer Centre again for lunch. I had a 'torpedo' which was like a rolled up pizza base filled with chicken and asparagus with cheese on top. There was a live pianist in the food court who entertained us. There was also a lot of screaming coming from the top of the building, where a small roller coaster ride ran above the food court!</p>
		<p>We then walked across town to the brewery, getting there just in time for the tour. It was very interesting, but noisy in the packing area, and smelly in other areas. It smelt strongly of malt. We then had a free beer tasting (the whole tour was free)! They said we could try four beers but not to get excited because they were only small tasters. Each 'small taster' turned out to be half a pint. They didn't have the XXXX lager that we have in England. Instead I had two bitters, one XXXX Gold and one Ice bitter. I was slightly charged afterwards as they say over here! It is called Castlemaine because that is the area in Victoria where the brothers came from who originally brewed it. The four Xs are due to the monks who used to brew beer, giving it a number of Xs according to its quality. Four of them is the best you can get.</p>
		<p>After the tour we went home and did the washing and tumble drying. I called home again and Mum said that my Chargecard would now work. Then Adam cooked dinner - baked beans with fried barbecue chicken. The beans were a bit runny, but the chicken was good. I then did my ironing and watched most of Sister Act while I was at it. Then we went to bed.</p>
		<p>The weather was not too good today. It was cold and overcast and a couple of times we thought it was going to rain, but it didn't.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="09-07-1996">
		<p>Our last day in Brisbane. We got up early again to meet Rob who turned up this time. Adam and I were his only customers today, so we got a private tour and the best day so far. (By the way, I've actually been catching up on writing this diary after neglecting it for a couple of days by writing it on the Greyhound coach up to Bunderburg, where I got to at the end of today).</p>
		<p>First, we drove north up the coast for about an hour until we came to an Aboriginal site called a Bura ring. This was where they conducted special ceremonies and had their meetings. We could also see the Glasshouse mountains from here, and we were told how they represented a family consisting of father, mother and eleven kids. Then we drove to a lookout point to get a better look at the mountains, and we had morning tea and cakes.</p>
		<p>After this we drove on to Kondalilla National Park - subtropical rainforest. On arrival we had a barbecue lunch in the picnic area. There were lots of electrical barbecues around the site, and you put money in to make them work. I had four large sausages, fried onion, a slice of bread and lots of fresh salad. I must truly be better as my appetite is back!</p>
		<p>Then we went on a 4km walk around the forest. Rob was a very good guide and not only pointed out the various plants, but also told us what the Aborigines would have used them for. We saw an eighty metre waterfall, and after the walk I had a brief swim in the plunge pool. Adam was chicken, but probably sensible as it was absolutely freezing (about as cold as that pool in Hastings in the first year). Nevertheless, when I got out I felt invigorated and refreshed (at least, the parts of me I could still feel) and I was glad that I did it.</p>
		<p>On the way back to the Transit Centre we stopped off at a village and Rob got us some ice creams. Then, after writing a mammoth entry in his visitors book, he dropped us off. We had dinner at the Transit Centre, where I ate five pieces of KFC chicken and chips. I really have got my appetite back. After dinner we checked in with Greyhound, and then boarded our bus. From here we drove to Bunderberg, setting off from Brisbane at eight o'clock.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="10-07-1996">
		<p>We arrived in Bunderburg at 2 am and the woman running the hostel was surprisingly nice seeing as we woke her up at this time in the morning. Adam and I were put in separate dorms, and it was strange going to sleep in a room with four other people whom I hadn't even seen.</p>
		<p>When I woke up in the morning everyone had left, so I had to wait until later to find out who I was sharing with. Someone moved out today so Adam moved in. There were three other people in our dorm: a girl called Cassie who is the same age as me and lives near Brisbane; Trevor who comes from Norfolk; and Jaap who is from Holland. They are all backpacking and work most days, doing things like picking fruit and packing it. This pays for their rent and gives them a bit to save. They complain that their hours are not long enough in Bunderburg meaning they do not earn enough, but they say that other places provide much more work. They usually have to get up around six o'clock in the morning, before it is even light. Because it is winter at the moment it gets dark very quickly around five thirty in the afternoon, which surprised me.</p>
		<p>We went to the Coles supermarket round the corner today to get some food for breakfast and for dinner, then we noticed an advert for scuba diving at a place opposite the hostel, so we went to enquire about it. The course lasted four days and cost $149. Originally, we were planning to dive in Townsville or Cairns, but the courses there cost around $400, so we decided to book the course here. We would be saving so much money that we would be able to make a certified dive in Cairns later on and see a different part of the reef. When we booked up, we were given the PADI scuba diving manuals and told to read them and fill out the question sheets on the 5 modules. There were almost 300 pages in the book, but it was very interesting and I was excited, so I started reading it straight away. We booked our course to start tomorrow.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon we went on a tour of the Bunderburg Rum Distillery. We got a lift there from a lady who works at the hostel, but we had to walk back. The tour was very interesting, and I tasted some molasses, which is the waste product of the sugar cane and the starting material for the rum. It tasted a bit like liquorice, and it was foul! Adam didn't even finish licking his finger. In many parts of the place, electronic equipment could not be used (like cameras) because it was 78% alcohol and it could have ignited!</p>
		<p>After the tour there was, of course, the rum tasting. I had a "Dark and Stormy", which is rum with ginger beer, and then I had Adam's "Mishap" which he didn't like. It was lovely, tasting like fizzy Bailey's, but made of Bunderburg Royal Liquor, coke and cream.</p>
		<p>On the way back, we were misled by some (probably drunk) locals sitting on their front porch, but we found our way to the hostel eventually. I cooked spaghetti with prawns and a butter and garlic sauce. Another cook looked envious as she announced that this was a backpackers and real food wasn't allowed!</p>
		<p>Everyone else in the room has to get up really early, but they all talk until about midnight. We don't mind though, because we can sleep in a bit longer. When they are alone I can talk to them, but when they get together Adam and I feel a bit left out as they talk about work and the different places they have been backpacking, and the guys seem to talk about sex an awful lot! We find their talk interesting though, and are content to listen. The weather was hot and sunny today.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="11-07-1996">
		<p>We got up at eight o'clock and had some breakfast, and then we went over the road to start our diving course at nine o'clock. I forgot to mention something yesterday, so I will have to put it in here instead. At 7 pm on Wednesday we were taken to the doctor's for a medical before our diving. I was a bit worried about this, because asthma is a contra-indication to diving, and a chest X-ray could cost around $100. I couldn't believe the doctor though. When he got to where I put on my medical history that I had mild asthma, he said, "You don't have asthma, do you?" to which I replied, "It's only very mild." He then said again, "But you don't have asthma, do you?" and when I said that I didn't he promptly crossed out that section!</p>
		<p>Anyway, back to the 11th. Today was theory day. We watched videos of modules one to three, and between them answered questions on the modules. The questions were very easy, and I got all but one correct. We are doing the course with four other people - all Dutch backpackers. They are very friendly, but speak in Dutch most of the time. The session ended at 2.30, at which point we all left and had lunch. I had sausages and chips with fried eggs at a cafe. We didn't do anything else much until the evening when we played cards with Cassie. She showed us a game called Uke, which has the same basics as whist. We then showed her how to play whist, black Mariah, blackjack and cheat. The weather was hot and sunny again today.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="12-07-1996">
		<p>We got up at eight again, but this time I skipped breakfast. We went over the road at 9 a.m. and waited to be taken to the pool by our instructors. However, their van was being repaired, so we had to wait until half ten to be picked up. We haven't had much luck with vans, with Rob's van breaking down as well! We then went to their dive store which was behind a furniture shop, to select our wetsuits. I also got a brand new -4 prescription mask, so I could see!</p>
		<p>Then we went to the pool. We had to wait for quite some time at the dive shop until Roger's van was ready. Roger was one of our instructors, and the other was Julian Negri, who had brought us to the dive shop in this ancient 4x4 Jeep. When we got to the pool, we swam ten lengths. It was outdoors and freezing cold, so I couldn't put my head under water (I wasn't wearing my goggles either) so I swam quite slowly. After this, we assembled our gear, set up our tanks, regulators and BCDs and put everything on. The pool wasn't ideal for learning to scuba dive, as it was shallow from one end to the other, but we learnt to clear our regulators, adjust our buoyancy, clear our masks, take off our masks and put them on again, breathe through our buddy's octopus, and make a controlled emergency ascent going horizontally instead of vertically. The water was quite cold, and we were in for about two and a half hours, so I started shivering by the end.</p>
		<p>We then went back to the dive centre, got some lunch at McDonald’s, then did the module four theory, mainly about Recreational Dive Planners. After this, we went to the supermarket to get some dinner. I cooked sausages in breadcrumbs with beans, and we had a large salad as we had not been eating enough vegetables. Adam doesn't do any cooking, but it’s fair because he does the washing up, and I enjoy cooking anyway. It is quite hectic in the kitchen, but it's manageable.</p>
		<p>After dinner we watched Seinfeld and a program like Quantum Leap called Sliders. I then came up to the room to write my diary. Cassie suddenly pulled me outside on to the balcony to see a thunderstorm, and we talked for quite a while. Adam said later that I looked very funny leaning against the balcony. Then I finished my diary, had a shower and went to bed (probably - I haven't done it yet).</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="13-07-1996">
		<p>I made sure that I had some breakfast this morning after I almost starved yesterday. We went over the road and were picked up immediately today. One of the Dutch men had dropped out of the course yesterday, so we were down to five people. We went to the dive shop and picked up our gear, and then drove out to the beach. I had accidentally picked up the wrong equipment, but luckily it all fit me, although I did have to swap boots with Adam.</p>
		<p>It was sunny, but there was a strong wind making it very cold. It was horrible changing into wetsuits outside on a grassy field. It was freezing! We put on all our stuff except for our fins, and made our way down the rocky shore to the water's edge. This was the worst part - clambering over slippery rocks with a very heavy scuba tank strapped to my back There were a couple of times when I almost slipped and would have hurt myself quite badly. What made it even worse was that nobody else seemed to be having any trouble. Maybe it's because I'm taller and thinner than them. </p>
		<p>When we got in we swam out to the dive flag and then tried to descend. I say "tried" because I did not have enough weights on my weight belt. Roger and Julian came up and stuck more weights in my pockets, and eventually I went down. The colours are diminished under water, and we only went down about seven metres, but you can still see red corals and yellow and black striped fish. We were all very clumsy to begin with, and were crushing all the corals by sitting on them or kicking them with our fins. First, we all knelt down in a sandy clearing on the bottom and did some exercises. Julian would do them first, then we would copy him. We did things like taking out our regulators and recovering them, partially flooding our masks and clearing them, and floating above the bottom with our fins touching the sea bed.</p>
        <p>We then went for a swim. However, as soon as I started kicking I bobbed up to the surface, so I spent most of the first dive looking down at things. Also, the strap between my legs was much too tight, and it caused excruciating pain whenever I kicked hard. The water also got very cold by the end. I didn't think it was as good as it was made out to be. The booklet said that the feeling of weightlessness was unlike anything you've felt before, but it was just like floating in a swimming pool. I suppose the real enjoyment comes from exploring confidently rather than just doing exercises and then floundering around.</p>
		<p>We got out and climbed the perilous beach back to the vans, expecting to have some lunch, but we only had about 20 minutes rest before we climbed back down and went in again. We did some more exercises, like completely flooding the mask and clearing it, and buddy breathing, then we went for another look around. This time I didn't do up the strap between my legs, and I had more weight, so it was much more enjoyable. I can see the merit in learning in Cairns though - it would be so much warmer. I saw lots of coral, which was not that interesting, but there were large schools of fish that all moved in synchrony when you approached. There were also yellow and black striped fish which Adam called 'zebra fish', and long fish with pointed snouts. We then got out, got changed and returned to the dive shop where we had to rinse off all our stuff and hang up the wetsuits.</p>
		<p>We were allowed half an hour to get lunch at McDonald's again before we went back to learn module five and do the big 50 question test. I got one wrong; so naturally I was disappointed! We ended up having McDonald's for dinner as well, seeing as Cassie and Trevor were going. The trouble is that it is too close to the hostel, so the temptation is just too great!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="14-07-1996">
		<p>The last day of the course. After this we will be qualified scuba divers! I got up at eight, and so had an hour to get ready, phone Greyhound to book our coach to Yeppoon, book a hostel in Yeppoon, and check out of this hostel. Somehow I just about managed it.</p>
		<p>We went to the dive shop, picked up our stuff, and then returned to the dive site. Roger was not diving today because he has a cold. It was even worse putting on the wetsuits today because they were already slightly wet and clammy from yesterday. I was really dreading the first dive, because I knew we would have to completely remove our masks and then replace them again. If you start breathing in through your nose, you've had it! I started choking while doing it in the pool, but here we would be 7 metres down. I surprised myself though and did it perfectly. </p>
		<p>We followed the same procedure as yesterday: exercises, swim around, get out, get back in for the last dive. For the final dive we started off doing snorkelling and duck diving, and then we put the scuba gear back on. We did some compass work and then went for a tour of the reef. It was a bit sparse, because it was only just starting this far south. We did see a giant turtle though. It was resting under a ledge.</p>
		<p>When we got back, we had showers and then walked to the chemists to have some passport photos taken for our certificates. Out of the six that had started, only three remained. Two of the Dutch girls had also dropped out. I was glad that it was over and I was certified. I would much prefer diving off a boat into warm waters. It was a good experience though.</p>
		<p>That evening we said goodbye to our room mates. Adam did his best at matchmaking me and Cassie, saying that I had written in my diary that I fancy her, and that she wrote the same thing in her diary. But alas, the plan failed. She took both our addresses though.</p>
		<p>We caught the coach at 7 pm I didn't bother watching the film - it was some Western - so I listened to my Walkman instead and tried to sleep. I didn't manage to drift off though. We arrived in Rockhampton at 11 o'clock and were taken by minibus to the hostel in Yeppoon. We were driving through the countryside and there were no street light, so all the stars were visible. I couldn't believe how many there were. It was as though the whole sky was alight.</p>
		<p>We checked in to the hostel at Yeppoon and went to bed at midnight. The rooms have really thin walls, and the walls don't connect to the ceiling, so you can hear everything that everyone is saying. An unusual decoration was a hang-glider suspended from the ceiling. It was quite cold tonight, even though they gave us sheets and blankets.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="15-07-1996">
		<p>I woke up with a splitting headache so I took some paracetamol. It was probably something to do with the diving, because my ears and sinuses hurt. Anyway, the paracetamol worked, and I soon felt better.</p>
		<p>We went down to reception and booked a two night package on Great Keppel island for $69. The coach left at 2 pm so we had some time to buy some groceries. It is much warmer here than in Bunderburg, and not as windy. The sky is cloudless, and the sea is a beautiful deep blue. After we finished shopping we went back to the hostel, and I sat out on the porch relaxing in the sun for about half an hour. Then the coach came and took us to the harbour. I bought a drink and another film from the shop there. Then we boarded the 'Spirit of Keppel' - the catamaran that took us over to the island. The sea was very calm, and the journey took half an hour. We were then surprised by the way the boat docked on the island. It ran itself aground on the sandy beach! (It was supposed to do this).</p>
		<p>We booked in to the Keppel Haven at the reception, where they gave us linen and cutlery, and also a map. We were staying in a tent about five minutes walk from the reception area, where there was also a bar/bistro and the telephones. The tent was very nice, with proper beds and an electric light. We were close to the kitchen and amenities block. There was only one place we could get drinking water, and this was out of a huge yellow tank next to the kitchen.</p>
		<p>We then went for a walk on the beach as the sun was setting. It was a lovely view, as the sun disappeared behind a small island and all around us was clear blue sea. Unfortunately, we had not got our cameras with us.</p>
		<p>We went to the bar at five thirty, because this was when happy hour started. In all I had a can of XXXX bitter, a bottle of Carlton Cold Filtered (which was disgusting), a Blue Lagoon cocktail, and two jugs of XXXX gold which I shared with Adam. We were both very merry, but I think Adam was slightly more affected as he was trying to take photos of me going to the loo from over the top of the cubicle!</p>
		<p>We managed to cook cup noodles for dinner. I also had some cashew nuts at the bar. Then we went back to the tent. Adam wrote his diary, which was probably not a good idea given the state he was in. Then we went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="16-07-1996">
		<p>I had a headache again this morning. I must have been not equalising properly during the diving. The alcohol probably didn't help much. I've also got a large blister on my right index finger. I thought there was a splinter in it, so I decided to burst it, but nothing came out.</p>
		<p>We had toast with chicken spread and crab spread and tuna for breakfast. We then went down to the beach for our free cruise which started at 10 am It went on for two hours, during which time people did boom-netting and snorkelling. I didn't do either, because the water was too cold and I didn't want my head to get any worse. Besides, there will be plenty of time for me to do it later on. Adam did the snorkelling though.</p>
		<p>For lunch we had chicken cup-a-soup and crab spread sandwiches and a carrot. I also had an apple. Then we went on a walk. It was supposed to take two hours, but we took a wrong turn and it ended up taking nearer three. We visited Shelving beach, Monkey beach and Long beach. The beaches were all beautiful. They were long, white and deserted, and looked like they had been plucked right out of an episode of 'Wish You Were Here' .</p>
		<p>While we were walking we were constantly harassed by flies. They always seemed to try and fly right into my ears. This was very annoying and a lot of energy was expended trying to swat them away. When we got back, we showered and went to the bar again for happy hour. (We had a game of pool yesterday. The tables have blue felt and are really nice. Adam beat me when it was all on the black).</p>
		<p>For dinner we had a tin of spaghetti bolognaise and some canned vegetables. Afterwards I finished 'Rama II’. I've got nothing to read now, so I'll have to get the next one in the series.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="17-07-1996">
		<p>We had to check out by nine o'clock, so we got up at eight, and to our surprise found that our bread had been eaten. It must have been a possum. It's quite amazing how many animals there are all over the place. At night you have to watch out that you don't tread on a possum, and during the day rainbow coloured macaws land on your table and lick the ice cream off your wrapper.</p>
		<p>We gave all the linen and cutlery in and got our deposit back. I changed my last travellers cheque for cash, and bought some crisps and a KitKat for breakfast. We had phoned Greyhound last night and were booked on the 11.55 pm coach from Rockhampton to Airlie Beach. Today I phoned a hostel at Airlie Beach and booked us in. Then we started another walk. I had put on insect repellent this morning, but it didn't seem to bother the flies. </p>
		<p>We did the Leeke's Beach Circuit which was supposed to take two hours. At Leeke's Beach I went into the undergrowth to relieve my bowels. Luckily, I had toilet paper in my bag, which I had taken from the hostel in Brisbane. However, as soon as it hit the ground, huge swarms of bluebottles were all over it. I got out of there as quickly as I could! Then we both went for a swim in the sea. It was cold at first, but got nice after a while. We dried out on the beach in the sun.</p>
		<p>We finished our walk earlier than expected, as we walked the wrong way down Leeke's Beach and so ended up at the beginning again. I must have been holding the map the wrong way round! We showered, then had lunch in the bar. Adam had fish and chips, and I had a Haven Burger. It was the biggest burger I had ever seen. It was so tall they had to stick a skewer through the middle of it to stop it falling apart! There was a toasted roll, beef burger, bacon, egg, pineapple slice and loads of vegetables, plus lots of chips. I was hungry after that walk though, so I finished it off. We wanted to save our cash, so I put it on my VISA. However, we had to make it up to at least $20, so we had two drinks each. I had an orange squash and an iced chocolate, which was a delicious chocolate milkshake with cream on top. I also bought some more cashew nuts.</p>
		<p>Then we caught the ferry back to the mainland, and from there the coach took us back to the hostel in Yeppoon. We had a couple of hours before they were going to take us to the coach stop, so we walked out to the high street. I wanted to find another book to read, but there wasn't anything interesting. The high street was very small, and there were no good shops to look in. I did get a big ice cream though. It was passion fruit and mango, and the passion fruit was very sour.</p>
		<p>We then returned to the hostel, and I lay beside the pool, sunbathing and listening to my Walkman until the coach was ready to leave. It was very crowded on the coach (it was actually a minibus) and I ended up sitting on the floor, but the trip was not too long. We got to Rockhampton at about a quarter to six, and so had six hours to wait.</p>
		<p>We went to the Red Rooster restaurant for dinner and I had a quarter of a chicken, chips, corn on the cob and coleslaw. We then sat in the fast food cafe/ coach stop until the coach arrived.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="18-07-1996">
		<p>I tried in vain to sleep on the coach, but there wasn’t enough room for my legs. However, I wasn't too tired when we arrived in Airlie Beach at 6 am We got off the coach, and there were a row of stalls advertising hostels. We had already booked in to Bush Village Backpackers, and were supposed to be given a lift there, but we didn't know where to get the lift from, so I went to a stall to ask. Unfortunately, I had forgotten the name of the hostel we were staying at, so I asked at the wrong desk. He tried to get me to book into his hostel, until I told him that we had already booked in somewhere else, at which point he just looked at me strangely.</p>
		<p>I looked in my copy of TNT to check where we staying, and found the right desk. There were only three of us being taken back to the hostel - Adam and I and a weird Chinese bloke who looked a bit psychotic. He was stomping around in army boots, wearing army trousers with rainbow coloured knee caps and chewing gum very loudly.</p>
		<p>We got back to the hostel, and breakfast wasn't being served for another hour, so the driver put some female aerobics on the TV to get himself 'warmed up'! I flicked through some brochures, and Adam read his book. I really need to get another book, but the only places I can find that sell books are the Golden Casket newsagents, and they don't have a great selection.</p>
		<p>For breakfast we had cereal with a pear slice in it, and a cold American pancake with honey. We then watched a promotional video for the area on a small cinema projection screen in the lounge. The narrator couldn't seem to read from the script though. He kept changing his mind about what he was saying! We had nothing else to do while we waited for our room to be vacated, so we watched it twice through. Then we had a game of darts. We played 'killer' and Adam won.</p>
		<p>After the darts we went into the office and looked through leaflets about things to do here. The owners were very helpful, and discussed it all with us, then booked the activities for us. At first there was too much to choose from, with leaflets strewn all over the place so that we could compare them. In the end we made up our minds. Today we would do parasailing at 4.30; tomorrow we would go sailing; and on Saturday we would visit Reefworld.</p>
		<p>We went down to settle in our room. It is very nice. All the rooms are in self contained cabins, with bathroom and kitchen. The couple who are sharing our cabin come from Biggin Hill and West Wickham. In fact, Andy lives about 5 minutes walk from Adam!</p>
		<p>After recovering from our astonishment we went to the supermarket to get groceries. We stopped off along the way for lunch. I had a burger and chips and a very nice banana smoothy. I couldn't really come all the way to Australia and not try a smoothy!</p>
		<p>In the afternoon, we got the courtesy bus down to the town for a look around. We found a book shop and I bought a Star Trek book - Rogue Saucer. We sat on the beach and I read my new book. There was a topless woman sunbathing on the beach, but she was a bit fat. Then we caught the courtesy bus to the marina for our parasailing. It was really good fun. We were winched up very high for what seemed like ages and then he would slow the boat so that we floated down until our legs were in the water. He would start the boat again just before we reached the water so that we were pulled back out again. However, he did not count on me being so light! He stopped the boat, and I just hovered in mid air and would not sink! Anyway, at last I finally dropped down, so he gave me an extra good soaking, and got my shorts wet.</p>
		<p>The view from the air was brilliant, and it was slightly cold on the legs when you had just been dunked in the water. Adam had been saying that he was going to do it hanging upside down, but at the last moment he chickened out. One man did it upside down though, and had his whole head dunked under water! The sun set while we were out, and suddenly everyone stopped watching the person parasailing and started taking photos of the sunset.</p>
		<p>For dinner I cooked a beef casserole with potatoes, carrots and onion.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="19-07-1996">
		<p>We had to get up early today as we were being picked up at a quarter past eight. We waited out the front on a grassy verge with another couple going sailing. We found out that they were from Switzerland when we introduced ourselves, but I can't remember what their names are!</p>
		<p>The minibus arrived and when we boarded we found that a few other passengers had been picked up already. We then went to pick up our hostess. However, the road was blocked at one end because of roadworks, so we had to go all the way round the other end. She seemed about thirty, and her name was Tracy. As we went to pick up other passengers, she told us a bit about what we were going to do today and registered us.</p>
		<p>The Maxi Ragamuffin was moored at Shute Harbour, about 11 km from Airlie Beach. She was a very large, white sailing ship, weighing about 45 tonnes. I had to take my shoes off when I got on board because they had black soles, which I later realised were probably non-marking. Adam and I had booked a combined sailing and diving trip to save money, but I was a bit anxious when I found out that they didn't have any prescription masks. They said, however, that if I couldn't see and had to get out then they would refund my money.</p>
		<p>We all went below deck to stow our bags and read the safety procedures, then we got under way. It was a beautiful day. In fact, it was probably the perfect day for diving. However, this meant that it was absolutely calm and not enough wind to sail by. We made our way halfway to Blue Pearl Bay using the motor. Then they put up the mainsail. They needed four volunteers for this. It just so happened that only men volunteered, so he said that it would be an all women team on the way back, to promote equal rights for women. None of the women seemed to want equal rights though! They split them into two pairs; Adam was paired up with an older man. Each pair went to a grinder, one on the port side, and one on the starboard, and had to turn it as fast as they could to lift the sail. Adam's pair almost stopped by the time they got to the top. He said it was very hard work.</p>
		<p>There was still not enough wind to carry us along, so he left the motor on. As we got nearer to the bay, the divers went below to register and try on equipment. Adam and I were put with another man to make up a threesome. It was quite awkward trying to move about, because the boat was tilted over quite far to the port, and we kept falling about the place! At last everything seemed to fit me. Nothing was too tight!</p>
		<p>We arrived at the bay, and a motor boat took us to shore. The shore was not made of sand, but of dead pieces of coral, which they said could be quite uncomfortable to tread on. Therefore, I kept my trainers on. However, to get to the shore we had to jump out of the boat into the sea, so I got my shoes wet. I still had to walk up and down the shore a few times to put my bag down, and then put my glasses away when I forgot to take them off. I went into the sea and tried to put my fins on, but even this was tricky, as the waves kept pushing against me, and lots of coral kept getting inside them. Eventually we were all prepared. We were told that our maximum bottom time was 35 minutes, and away we went. </p>
		<p>This dive was incredible. Even as we stood on the shore putting our fins on there were dozens of fish swimming around our legs. I could actually see very well with a normal mask. Things looked a little blurred around the edges, but it was definitely better than out of the water. The reef here contrasted strongly with that at Bundaberg. There was much more coral, and very few patches of bare ground. There were so many different highly coloured fish, and one looked like a parrot, although apparently it wasn't a parrot fish. When we got down to six metres, my ears started to hurt, so I gave the signals and ascended.</p>
		<p>After resting on the surface for a few minutes I felt recovered. The other man in the group asked me how deep I felt I could go, and I said about four metres, so we determined to stay at that depth. However, we were gradually making our way out to sea, and before I knew it we were at twelve metres! My ears, and the visibility, were fine. I found that I had much better buoyancy control, and so managed to avoid hitting the corals. Adam seemed to keep on swimming straight across me, cutting me up and kicking me with his fins. However, he said afterwards that I had been doing the same to him. I think rear view mirrors would have been a great help!</p>
		<p>When it was time to head back we ascended to get our bearings, and then resubmerged and made our way towards the shore. After swimming for about ten minutes we surfaced again. The shore looked no closer! We did it again, but still we seemed to be getting nowhere. In the end we just swam back along the surface, to make sure we were going in the right direction. We eventually got back, fifteen minutes late, but with plenty of air still in our tanks, so there was no problem. We sat on the beach sunbathing for a while, until the boat came to take us back on board for lunch. There was a large smorgasbord, with salad, pasta, slices of cold meat and chicken drumsticks. I also had a coke and a Snickers. After this fabulous lunch we began to make our way back.</p>
		<p>On the way they put up a spinnaker, which gave us some extra speed. The sea was calm and we weren't going all that fast, so the ride was very smooth. We didn't feel as if we were really sailing. Nevertheless, I talked to a German couple about our holiday and university. When we got back to the dock, we thanked the crew of five (there were usually twenty six when they used to race) and caught the bus back to town to look for our parasailing photos. Unfortunately, the shop was closed, so we got the courtesy bus back to the hostel.</p>
		<p>For dinner we made a salad with pork pies. We were planning to watch the Tarantino film "Killing Zoe" in the lounge tonight, but while we were eating "Cannon Ball Fever" with John Candy came on TV. We ended up watching this instead, and I had my small bottle of Bundy rum. The only things that seem to be on the television here are Seinfeld, The Simpson's, Sliders (like Quantum Leap), and the adverts. They have a commercial break about every ten minutes, and the break goes on for five. Most of the adverts are absolute rubbish as well; such as a grumpy old man coming on and telling us the joys of buying furniture from him, or the cringe-worthy advert for "The Grotty Horror Show". If you can't remember this, then it's probably worth forgetting. By far the most annoying advert though is for a discount store. It flashes up pictures of objects for sale with the price, while a voice over runs a commentary at breakneck speed which goes something like, " ... pack of rubber bands two dollars hair bands one dollar each paper clips twenty five cents ... etc ... and 20% off all Manchester!" What on Earth is Manchester?!</p>
		<p>The Australians are very patriotic. On all Australian products it says "100% Australian made, 100% Australian owned". </p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="20-07-1996">
		<p>We had to get up even earlier this morning, as we were being picked up at ten to eight at the Croc Club next door. We were taken back to Shute harbour by bus, where we boarded the Fantasea cruiser. As we were pulling out of the harbour, the Ragamuffin pulled in, so I got a photo of her from the side.</p>
		<p>We began to make our way out to the reef at high speed. We were going to the outer barrier reef, to a floating platform called Reefworld. The trip took a couple of hours, including the time to pick up some more passengers from one of the island resorts. On the way we had a complimentary cup of tea, and I bought a packet of peanuts. A group of people were quickly taught how to scuba dive off to one side of the ship, and we booked up a ten minute helicopter flight for $65. There was then a talk by a marine biologist, and I booked a snorkel tour with her for $20. This included hire of a wet suit which would have cost $6 otherwise, and I thought my dives would be more interesting if I knew what I was seeing.</p>
		<p>When we arrived, I was pressed for time, because my snorkel tour was in an hour. Therefore, we quickly made our way over to the semi-submersible boat which took us out over the coral. I couldn't take pictures, because I could not turn my flash off, so Adam took all the photos. On the way back someone dropped their hat in the water, so we had to go back and fish it out! After this little excitement we had lunch. It was a smorgasbord again, but larger than yesterday’s. They had large mussels, salad, cold meats, pasta and chicken drumsticks.</p>
		<p>After lunch, I went out and got a wetsuit. At first it felt fine, but while I was in the water, surprise surprise, it got much too tight to swim properly. The water was also quite cold, so I was shivering by the time I got out. The tour was very good though. I had a -5 prescription mask, so I could see everything perfectly. She told us about the hard and soft corals, different fish, and she duck dived and brought up specimens such as a mushroom coral, starfish, and an elk horn coral. It was blue at the bottom of the reef, but as she brought it up it suddenly turned purple as red light reached it.</p>
		<p>After my snorkel, we got dressed then met the helicopter lady with whom we had booked our flight. We got on a boat (it was actually just a platform with a motor) which took us out to a floating helipad. As we approached, a helicopter appeared in the distance, zoomed towards us, banked sharply and landed. She said Adam and I would have to fight over who went in the front, so I let Adam go. He said the view was brilliant because most of the floor in the front was transparent. There were two very young girls with us who kept using the intercom system to fight over who was going to take photographs. They were very annoying! We flew at around 500 feet, and from here the reef looked green and blue. We flew over to heart reef, which looks just like a heart. It was all over so fast, although I did check my watch, and we did get our 10 minutes.</p>
		<p>Then we returned to the ship to go back to the mainland. We left at about 2.45, having spent three hours on Reefworld. During the trip I had a lager and they played Mr Bean videos on the TV screens. There was the one where he was at a horror movie, and then went to a magic show with his girlfriend and mucked up the act. The old ones are amusing.</p>
		<p>When we got back we went to the high street and got some money out of the ANZ (the only bank we've found that will accept our VISA) and then had dinner at the famous Hog's Breath Cafe - a sort of equivalent to Hard Rock Cafe - it has branches all over Australia. I had a peppered steak with chips and corn on the cob. We then went back to the hostel and to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="21-07-1996">
		<p>As this was our last day in Airlie Beach we had to check out by nine. We also found out the name of the hostel at Ayers Rock that 'Big' Greg had booked us into yesterday. It was, however, the only hostel at Ayers Rock, and because of this it could charge quite high prices such as $115 for a twin room. We were booked into a dorm which cost $20 for the first night, then $12 for every night thereafter.</p>
		<p>The next bus to town was at 10 am, so we played darts for a while. We drew at killer, and I won round robin, so overall we're even. We left our luggage at Bush Village and went into town to look for souvenirs, like T-shirts. There were lots of souvenir shops along the road, so first I got a chicken baguette for breakfast. There were lots of good T-shirts all for about $25 - 30. Right at the end of the road though was a design-your-own T-shirt shop. I wasn't really interested, but Adam wanted to have a look.</p>
		<p>There were lots of cartoon character T-shirts, but on the way out I noticed that it was only $20 to have a personalised T-shirt of your Australia tour, showing all the places you had been, and what you had done there, plus you got a cuddly toy and a poster and some postcards. This sounded like a good deal, so I took it. While the owner was printing the names of places on the T-shirt, I cut out all the icons I wanted. The end result was very good, but I put on a couple of places which I probably won't go to (Alice Springs and Canberra) to fill it out.</p>
		<p>We had a quick lunch at a burger place which doubled up as a night-club in the evenings, then we got the courtesy bus back to the hostel to pick up our stuff. We then caught another bus back to the coach stop. The driver took ages loading everyone's baggage, and there was someone sitting in Adam's seat, so we moved to another row.</p>
		<p>We arrived in Townsville at 6.30 pm and had dinner in the transit centre. I had some grim spaghetti bolognaise and a lime and pineapple Bounty, then we were picked up and taken to our hostel -the Civic Backpackers. We were in a dorm with four other people, but as soon as we had settled in we went down to the TV room. The Olympics were on, then a big fat Northerner changed channels to watch Platoon. He pretended that a snooker cue was a gun and shot everyone! Bizarre. The film was good, but it was very depressing. Not the kind of thing to watch on holiday if you're trying to enjoy yourself. I then went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="22-07-1996">
		<p>I woke up early and had a shower. We then went out into Townsville and walked to the aquarium and Omnimax theatre. We acquired tickets for two shows at the Omnimax and entry to the aquarium. Before the first film we looked around some of the tourist shops in the complex. The first film was called Titanica and was about how the Titanic sank, and how they explored the wreck. It was a bit morbid. The Omnimax was smaller than the one in Singapore, but they seemed more interested in showing us films that showed off the surround vision than documentaries.</p>
		<p>We then went into the aquarium and watched baby turtles being fed. We saw a presentation in the touch pool, and afterwards Adam asked the presenter for a definition of a coral, but was not satisfied with the answer. We saw another presentation, this time about the reef, and went to a talk on marine dangers such as box jellyfish. There was also a shark talk given by a woman with a lisp who seemed to have memorised her speech and was just reeling it off.</p>
		<p>After this we went to the second film, called The Living Sea. It was narrated by Meryl Streep, and was very good, especially when they were flying around in a helicopter.</p>
		<p>When we got back to the hostel we were asked if we wanted to go to a beach club for dinner, to meet up with other residents who had been playing volleyball on the beach. We were taken there in a minibus. It was a very nice club, and we had to sign to get in. We had a few drinks by the window overlooking the sea, and then got dinner. For $7.50 I had soup, salad cart, roast pork and dessert. We sat at a table with two ladies. One of them was extremely boring and just talked about how fit she was, cycling round Australia. She was so incredibly boring that when I went to the toilet Adam followed me just so he wouldn't be left alone with her.</p>
		<p>When we got back Adam watched some rugby, and I went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="23-07-1996">
		<p>We wanted to go to Magnetic Island today, so we packed our bags and checked out. We asked the woman at the desk to book us in for two nights on Magnetic for $50. We had to hurry though, because the bus was just coming. We caught it just as it arrived. The bus driver was called Marty and was very friendly – he looked like one of the Chuckle brothers.</p>
		<p>We caught the ferry from the aquarium and it took us over to Picnic Bay on the island. We caught the bus to Nelly Bay where our hostel was - Magnetic Island Tropical Resort. It was the only place with a five backpacks rating, but afterwards we found out that Geoff s place is supposed to be the best. We were staying in huts with very steep roofs, six beds to a hut, and no lock on the bathroom door. There were two girls in our hut, but we didn't really see them as they were out all day, and then checked out.</p>
		<p>We had lunch at the bakers - bacon, egg, sausage and toast, followed by a chocolate éclair! Then we caught the bus back to Picnic Bay and hired some mountain bikes. I had to put the saddle up a long way, so I was forced to lean forward a lot, which hurt after a while. We rode back to the hostel to pick up our swimming stuff, and then rode the 7 km to Horseshoe Bay. It was quite a hilly road, and on one particular hill I didn't pace myself and had to walk up it. I was joined by a few other walkers who couldn't make it. On the way back I paced myself and did it quite easily, even thought the saddle was cutting into me. </p>
		<p>When we got there, we found that all the watersports had just finished! We consoled ourselves with an ice-cream there, then headed back before it got dark. We had dinner in the bistro attached to the hostel. I had garlic bread and paella. It was very good - a large portion with huge prawns and mussels and lots of other seafood. Then we went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="24-07-1996">
		<p>I got up early and had a shower, then went outside, took some photos, and wrote my diary until Adam got up. I also wrote all my postcards. I decided that my backside hurt so much that I could hardly sit down, let alone ride back to the watersports, so Adam went on a bike ride, and I rode slowly back to Picnic Bay to return my bike. However, I forgot to take back my helmet, so I would have to take it back tomorrow to get my deposit back. I had lunch at a cafe - beef pie with salad and chips - while this man next to me was discussing political strategies with other people.</p>
		<p>Adam arrived panting and red just in time to catch the bus to Horseshoe Bay. Here we hired out a jet ski for $50 for half an hour. It was a two seater, but definitely not as fun for the person behind, desperately trying to hang on. Adam drove first, and almost threw me out of the back, but he kindly listened to my entreaties and didn't spin it round too fast. However, when it was my go I did throw him out of the back and almost turned the jet ski over. It was absolutely brilliant, and there was a huge adrenaline rush as you slowed down, did a hard turn and jammed on the throttle, almost flipping the thing over!</p>
		<p>Unfortunately, we couldn't do waterskiing because the boat was being repaired, so we sunbathed for a while, then had an ice-cream (a berry bomb) and got the bus back. We went to the supermarket and I spent all my change on things like Pert shampoo, and Moo Choos for Adam. We started to worry a bit, because the bank was in Picnic Bay and was closed now, and we didn't have enough money for the bus or even to phone Greyhound. We waited until the next day to get our key deposit money back. We also worried a little about how much money we had left in the bank.</p>
		<p>After dinner we went for a walk down to the beach, and ran around in the dark shining torches at each other. Then we played cards while possums kept climbing on the table trying to eat the Moo Choos. There are loads of mosquitoes around, so I am using my spray quite liberally.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="25-07-1996">
		<p>We checked out of the hostel, phoned Greyhound, and booked our hostel in Cairns. We then went back to the mainland, had lunch in the transit centre, and caught the coach at 2 pm The sound system on the coach was not working, so we couldn't watch the film which was going to be Protocol with Goldie Hawn. Instead, the driver kept us entertained by asking us lots of riddles. I suspect he was a March Hare in disguise. For one of them he gave us time to think about it, then didn't give us the answer for about 2 hours!</p>
		<p>We arrived in Cairns at 7.30 pm. We were supposed to be picked up at the Trinity Wharf Transit Centre, but the bus didn't come, so I had to phone the hostel. Someone else who was booked in to the same hostel couldn't wait, so went off to another hostel.</p>
		<p>We were staying at the International hostel. It had really shabby furnishings and looked more like a prison, with all the rooms lined up along a balcony. We were then moved rooms, as someone else had checked out. We were only planning to stay for one night, but she said that she would give us a couple of dollars off if we stayed another night because of the inconvenience of having to switch rooms. In the end, it wasn't such a bad hostel, so we booked in five more nights. </p>
		<p>We had dinner at the McDonald's just round the corner, and then went to bed. I was in the top bunk, and there was a ceiling fan just above my bed, so I was half afraid of sitting up in the night and having my head lopped off!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-07-1996">
		<p>The morning was taken up by doing the washing and booking up things to do. We managed to slip out and have breakfast at McDonald's while the clothes were washing. I had to dry them twice though, because they were still very damp after the first dry. We then went out to look around Cairns. We primarily wanted to go to the transit centre to find out how many more kilometres we had on our pass, go to the post office to send Adam's postcards, and to look for the Reef Teach at the library. We also kept an eye out for Charlie's restaurant which had been recommended to me by people back home. </p>
		<p>On the way we popped into a couple of didjeridoo shops, and after playing with them for a long time (a few hours) I bought one for $180 plus $50 for postage back to England and insurance. Next in line was the Reef Teach talk. It had moved from the library to the Bolan Centre. It was done by a mad Irish man called Paddy Conwell, and was very good although a bit strange. I can see why people say he's like Billy Connolly. They also gave us tea and lots of biscuits. Yummy!</p>
		<p>After Reef Teach we went back to the hostel and asked where Charlie' s was. Even though we found out that it was 2 km away down the Esplanade, we decided to walk. There was a buffet for $17.50 which was very nice. I had some fresh oysters for starters, and there was a distinct Chinese flavour to the main course dishes - I had broccoli! For dessert I had a chocolate mousse, and a cappuccino. It was worth the money - very filling.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-07-1996">
		<p>I got up early and had a shower. The shower on our floor doesn't have a curtain, downstairs there is a curtain, but I went upstairs where there were cubicles. There was little hot water left, so I had a cold shower. I spent most of the rest of the morning catching up on my diary and wondering whether I'm going to fit the rest of the holiday in. I also wrote a postcard home.</p>
		<p>Our hostel is on the Esplanade, which runs alongside the sea. There are plenty of cafes, restaurants, and tour booking agencies along here, and we're only five minutes walk from the centre of Cairns. </p>
		<p>During the day we had a walk through Cairns, to some of the outer parts of the city. We walked through a large open air market which looked like something straight out of Indiana Jones. It was hot and humid, and the climate was getting close to that of Singapore. We had lunch at a cafe called "Jimmy's at the Movies" which was attached to a cinema. I had a cisko burger (nothing to do with DS9!) which had a lot of chilli sauce in it. In the afternoon Adam went back to have a nap while I returned to the didjeridoo shop to practice. The salesman was around 21 and helped me learn to circular breathe (I can do the basics now) and also talked for ages about women and his girlfriend. He even chatted up a woman who walked into the shop to show me how easy it was! I think he managed to frighten her away quite successfully!</p>
		<p>In the evening we were picked up to go on our night rainforest expedition. There were eight of us going, all the rest older than us, but very friendly. We drove to the wildlife sanctuary where we had a barbecue dinner which was excellent. We saw a few bandicoots and a water rat by the pool. We then drove a long way up into the Atherton Tablelands. We each had spotlights which we shone out of the minibus to catch the eye shine of creatures such as possums. We then got out and walked around with hand held spotlights. Unfortunately, there were hardly any animals around, probably because there was a very bright moon. We had tea and coffee with slices of cake on the top of this mountain, and then got back at 1 am.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="28-07-1996">
		<p>We were picked up by the rap jumpers at 10.45. We all crammed into this tiny minibus until we reached a service station where we got some food, and signed our lives away! It seemed a bit dodgy, because they couldn't be held liable for anything, even if they were negligent. Anyway, we then got in a car and Frazer drove us up to Kuranda along the same road as yesterday, except he took it slightly faster!</p>
		<p>When we got to the site we hiked along a train track and over a weir to reach the cliff edge. They only come here once a week; they usually go to a 40m cliff, but we had a 100m cliff -lucky us! The scariest bit though was lying on the edge of the cliff looking over. I was one of the last to go, and all the people before had taken ages going over the edge, so I was getting a little nervous, but then I reminded myself that it's just like abseiling except you can see where you're going. It was actually easier going over the edge than abseiling, although Adam didn't think so. The tricky part was trying to keep perpendicular to the cliff face while jumping. My legs kept dropping down, and I bounced about quite a lot on my bum! I've got bruises all over me, but it was really good fun The rock climbing back up was good as well.</p>
		<p>When we got back we all put on our free black rap jumping T shirts and went to a couple of pubs/ night-clubs where we watched the video of the day, danced on the tables, and drank too much. We got to bed very late (or should I say early?), and we had to get up for white water rafting at 6.20 tomorrow morning. Hmm...</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="29-07-1996">
		<p>Needless to say, we didn't get up in time for the rafting. I leapt out of bed at 7.20 and rushed downstairs to phone Raging Thunder. Luckily, they said we could do it tomorrow instead. Then I asked Sarah at reception to phone the hang gliders, and I managed to change it to today.</p>
		<p>Warwick, the hang gliding instructor picked me up at 9.30, then we picked up Mark and Ian. We travelled back up to the Tablelands along Gilly's Road which was very windy. It took about an hour to get to a little homestead in the middle of nowhere.</p>
		<p>When we got there we set up the hang glider and attached it to the back of his car via a special trailer. Because there was not much wind we would take turns being strapped to the hang glider while the car was driven down a runway at about 45 kph.	When it wasn't my go I stood on the trailer with Warwick.</p>
		<p>After this interesting experience I found that I had worked up quite an appetite, so luckily it was time for lunch. We had a cold salad prepared by the homestead which was actually a cafe. Because there was a northerly breeze we drove to another hill after lunch and tried flying without the trailer. We would wait until there was enough wind and then run down the slope as fast as possible, and take off for a few seconds. This wasn't very long, but it was a great feeling while it lasted. </p>
		<p>When I got back, Adam and I had dinner at an Italian place on the Esplanade. I had a Marinara pasta which was too rich for me to finish.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="30-07-1996">
		<p>We got up in time today. We were picked up by a Raging Thunder minibus which took us to their HQ where we transferred to a bigger bus. We had an hour and a half drive up to Tully where we stopped for breakfast at the Raging Thunder cafe. I had a meat pie. Here, seven of us split off from the main group because we were going white water kayaking instead of rafting. It was cheaper than the rafting, and supposed to be much better because you have more control. We then drove to the depot and picked up all our equipment before heading for the Tully river.</p>
		<p>Unfortunately we couldn't take photos during the day because the camera would have got wet. I got in the kayak and he pushed it over the edge of this small cliff (a couple of metres drop), then Adam jumped in the water and climbed into the boat. I was sitting at the back for the whole day which meant that I had more control over the steering, while Adam provided the power.</p>
		<p>We practised capsizing the boat and then climbing back into it, then we were off. We generally just followed the guides (Jeffro and Sean) through the rapids, but on the tricky ones we would stop before it and they would guide us through one at a time. I managed to stay in the boat the whole time, though I still got soaked, especially when the boat virtually sank. Adam fell out three times, once when he was standing up as we went down the rapids! He got sucked all the way down and joined up with the boat at the bottom.</p>
		<p>We stopped for a cold salad lunch, using the overturned boats as tables, and then continued. Near the end we did a rock jump into the water, and then when we finished we went for a swim in the river. After we had packed up we went back to the Raging Thunder cafe where we watched the video of the rafters and had some soup and potatoes. Then we headed back home. We had McDonald's for dinner.</p>
		<p>PS: I kept forgetting to write about my coral poisoning. I must have scratched a coral in Bundaberg, because I got a huge blister on my finger. I kept bursting it, and it kept refilling. It has only just cleared up.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="01-08-1996">
		<p>We checked out of the hostel and went into town. I bought another film and used up all my change, so we went to the ANZ to draw out some more money, where I found out to my horror that I had no money left in my account. I had a brief panic and wondered whether to call Mum in Singapore, but I didn't have any money for the call, and my Chargecard can’t phone Singapore. I didn't have any lunch, and planned to eat on the plane instead.</p>
		<p>When we got to the airport, I changed my remaining Singaporean notes to Australian. I got it commission free with my ISIC card. I now had a total of $22. On the plane they served a slice of pizza and salad, and then cheese and biscuits and a cake. I also had a beer which I thought would be free seeing as he offered it to me, but it cost $3. Down to $19 left. We stopped off at Alice Springs for 20 minutes, then continued on to Ayers Rock.</p>
		<p>When we got there we caught the free coach to the Outback Pioneer Hostel and checked in. We then went to the supermarket to get dinner. I bought something similar to Pot Noodles, and some biscuits for breakfast and lunch. It cost $3.15. After dinner we went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="30-07-1996">
		<p>We went to the tour desk this morning and booked up a tour for today and one to Ayers Rock tomorrow. Then we tried to book another night, but they said they couldn't guarantee us a room, and we would have to try again at 8 pm. We then went to the shopping centre and I bought a meat pie and an apricot Danish for lunch. We also shopped for tomorrow's lunch.</p>
		<p>We were picked up by AAT Kings at 2.25 for our tour of the Olgas, also called Kata Tjuta, or "many heads". It was quite cold and overcast, and there were light showers, so they weren't sure if the walk would be safe, but it turned out to be alright. We did a 6 km walk to the Valley of the Winds which was quite beautiful, especially as the clouds cleared as we were looking at it.</p>
		<p>We then went to the barbecue area and watched the sunset at the Olgas while drinking champagne and Bucks Fizz. The meal was very good. I had two steaks, three pieces of kangaroo (which tasted like liver), a sausage and lots of pasta and salad. We then had a star watch in which we saw Jupiter, lots of constellations, a few satellites and a shooting star! When we got back we booked in again and were put in the same beds as before.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="02-08-1996">
		<p>We got up early this morning (around five o'clock) to see the sun rise at Ayers Rock (Uluru). We were taken to the sunrise lookout area, which was just a stretch of road with areas for the coaches to park, and we took some photos as the sun came up. The colour change was not as dramatic as we had been led to believe, going from a dark shade of red to a light shade of red. We were then taken to the base of the monolith for the climb. </p>
		<p>It was supposed to take two hours, and it didn't look that far to begin with. However, just when we thought we were near the end, another bit would reveal itself, and it was so steep that they had to provide a handrail for people to hold on to. We stopped now and then for short rests, but unlike some people there we made it all the way. At the top there was a book to sign, chained to a pedestal. There were so many people crowded round it that we didn't bother to add our names.</p>
		<p>Being super fit we managed to get there and back in one and a half hours, and although it was cool on the way up, by the time we got back down it was boiling. At the top I helped a Japanese girl who was trying to take a short cut, but couldn't pull herself up.</p>
		<p>When we reached the bottom, the ranger was supposed to take us on a guided tour along the base. We waited for him for three quarters of an hour, and when he didn't turn up we did the base walk without him. It was a 9 km walk and was very hot. The Aborigines thought parts of the rock looked like animals, but we were surprised to see that they had missed some quite obvious ones, such as a whole rock face looking like a whale, or the Jabba the Hut shaped rock!</p>
		<p>After the walk we had lunch. I traded some of my chips for one of Adam's oranges. There were some very crude toilets there: basically just holes built over giant cess tanks. The stench was unbearable, and there were loads of huge flies swarming around. Because we finished the walk faster than we had expected, we had to wait a while to be picked up. I lay on a bench and listened to my Walkman.</p>
		<p>We were taken to the cultural centre, where we found out a bit of the Aboriginal 'Law', or Creation Story. There was also a video of different Aboriginal dances, all of which looked pretty much the same.</p>
		<p>I had two Pot Noodles for dinner, and we were put in different beds tonight.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="03-08-1996">
		<p>We were lucky to get on the coach to the airport, because the first two coaches didn't turn up. They almost left my bag behind as well, but I managed to get off the coach and grab it. The flight was pretty uneventful; it left 15 minutes late, and got to Sydney 15 minutes early! We had to wait for Douglas at the airport. He then took us back to his house in Woronora.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon we went in a three man canoe on the Woronora river. We paddled up to a beach where we left the canoe, and then we climbed a cliff and had some wine and chips looking out over the Woronora valley. By the time we went back the tide had gone out quite a bit, so the boat kept almost getting grounded on the river bed! After the canoeing we went back and had a shower.</p>
		<p>When I finished in the shower, Doug's friend James had arrived. He was 15 years old. We went to an eat-all-you-can place for dinner, and we certainly ate all we could! Then Doug took us to Kings Cross, where we were asked if we wanted to see a peep show, and James got very excited because he thought he had seen his first transvestite!</p>
		<p>We ended up walking down to Sydney Harbour, and found ourselves outside the Opera House at 11 pm. Doug then rang home for me on his mobile phone, and I had a talk to Steven. It was a strange phone call! We then caught a taxi back to Doug's car, and he took us home.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="04-08-1996">
		<p>Doug took us to the Blue Mountains today. They are about a two hour drive away. We stopped off at a picnic area for a lunch of chicken drumsticks, rolls, chips (sorry - crisps. I must be thinking in Australian!) and wine. It was very windy, and the rolls kept getting blown away.</p>
		<p>After lunch we drove to another area, where we parked the car and then went on a huge bush walk through the rainforest. It wasn't that far - only about four miles, but that doesn't take into account all the ups and downs. There were more steps than I could count! For some inexplicable reason we ran most of the way, and when we got to the end we were confronted by the Giant's Staircase - 900 unmade steps hewn out of the cliff face. We had a rest and then raced up it. I ran the first two hundred steps, walked the next hundred, then virtually crawled the last two thirds of the way! I still got there first though. Doug says that Adam and I make him look like an old man!</p>
		<p>After recovering our breath we looked around the tourist shop at the top, and watched some parrots feeding. Then we had to walk back to the car along the road. On the way back home a cyclist rode right in front of the car and got knocked off his bike, but he was all right. We stopped off in a little town on the way back where Doug had hostelled before, and went into a pub for a quiet drink. We then went home.</p>
		<p>A lot of the time in Sydney was taken up by watching Doug's collection of Simpson's videos. I got hooked on them, and even stayed up 'til four in the morning one day to watch them.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="05-08-1996">
		<p>We caught the train to Redfern (a dodgy, Brixton-like area) to meet Aunty Eng Sim and her daughter, Chiu Hsia (who looked incredibly like Frances). We all caught the train (a double decker) to Circular Quay station, which is right by the harbour. </p>
		<p>Adam and I decided that we wanted to see something at the Opera House before we left, so they took us to the Half Tixs in Town Hall to see if they had any reduced tickets. Unfortunately, they didn't sell tickets for the Opera House.</p>
		<p>We were planning to go to China Town for lunch, but went to Planet Hollywood instead, which was very good. I had chicken fajitas, which was nice but rather messy! After lunch we went back to the Opera House. I wanted to see an opera, but it was too expensive, and there were no good seats left, so we booked some tickets for the Sydney Symphony Orchestra tonight. We then went on a ferry across to Manly, but it wasn't very interesting, and we didn't look around Manly because we had to catch the same ferry back in order to go on the Opera House tour. Aunty Eng Sim and Chiu Hsia didn't go on the tour with us. It was very interesting, and told us the history of the Opera House, and how it was designed to give the best sound.</p>
		<p>After the tour, we caught the train back to Aunty Eng Sim's house where she gave us a large dinner. Uncle Shang Fook happened to phone while I was there, so I talked to him. Then Chiu Hsia's friend gave us a lift back to the Opera House. We were sitting behind the orchestra, but I thought they were very good seats, because you could see the conductor. The orchestra played Mendelssohn's Hebrides overture, Schubert's Symphony No.5, and Mahler's 1st. All of them were excellent, and I thoroughly enjoyed myself, even though I almost went into spasms trying not to cough while they were playing.</p>
		<p>Afterwards, we weren't quite sure how the train system worked, so we thought we had to catch a train back to Redfern first, and then back to Sutherland. When we got to Redfern, it looked like we had missed the last train home, so we called Doug to pick us up. We hung around for half an hour trying to look inconspicuous, in which time the guard came round and put all the clocks forward. We hadn't missed the last train after all!</p>
	</entry>
</diary>