<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Big Holiday" date="01-2004">
	<entry date="25-01-2004">
		<p>I drove to Wynyard to pick up Mum and Dad in the morning. Mum was the first off the plane, with a big grin on her face. We drove back to Burnie hospital, and they settled in to their room (I had to move into the single room!)</p>
		<p>We went back to Wynyard for lunch at Buckaneers restaurant, where we had very nice oysters, both battered and natural. We then drove up to Table Cape lookout, and to Fossil Bluff. The tide was in, so we couldn’t walk along the bluff, but the weather was very nice. It had been cold and wet recently, so Mum and Dad had obviously brought some good weather with them!
In the afternoon Mum and Dad had a sleep, and it was very difficult to wake them up. We went to Peter Brumby’s house for a Hellyer Chorale barbeque in the evening. It was very nice for my parents to meet friends I’d made over the last six months.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-01-2004">
		<p>We had poached eggs and smoked salmon for breakfast, then set off for Cradle Mountain. It was pretty good weather again, and seeing that it rains at Cradle for three hundred days of the year, we were lucky that it stayed dry. We started off by looking at the photographs in the Wilderness Gallery. The ticket lady let us in for free, as it was Australia Day.</p>
		<p>We had lunch over the road at the hotel, then drove up to Dove Lake. I had decided to walk anticlockwise around the lake, which turned out to be a good idea, as it was quite busy and everyone else was walking around in the other direction.</p>
		<p>After the walk, we drove down to Strahan. I had booked us in to a motel on the way to Ocean Beach, but it turned out to be quite dingy. We had our own apartment, but I’m sure there were bed bugs, as I was bitten over night. We climbed up to a restaurant on the hillside to look at the menu, but decided we didn’t like the buffet, so had to come all the way back down again. We ended up eating at the Gallery restaurant by the water’s edge, which was very good.</p>
		<p>We had a few beers back at the motel, watching the Australian Open tennis.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-01-2004">
		<p>We had breakfast at Banjo’s café before boarding the Lady Jane Franklin II for the Gordon River cruise. This was the second time I had been on the cruise, but as opposed to the first time when the rainforest had been shrouded in mist, this time the sky was clear, and there were picture-perfect reflections on the water. We sailed out to the open sea via Hell’s Gates, then saw the salmon and trout farms in the harbour, and cruised up the Gordon to Heritage Landing. At this point we had a short walk around the rainforest, with a talk by one of the guides. On the way to Sarah Island, we had a buffet lunch on board. We had a nice walk around the island, with a tour guide.</p>
		<p>We had been planning to go to Hobart next, but once we got back to the car we decided to head back to Burnie, as it would have been too much of a rush. We had dinner at Rialtos in town. The waiter remembered me from my Birthday dinner – I think it may be due to the large tip I left last time!</p>
		<p>The weather broke this evening, and a huge storm started as we were heading out to dinner. I thought the apartment was going to blow down during the night!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="28-01-2004">
		<p>This was a rather lazy day. The weather was still bad, so we stayed in to pack, and had a walk around town. I went into the Emergency Department to say goodbye to people, and to get some more medical provisions for my trip!</p>
		<p>In the evening, we went over to Mark and Corinne’s house in Riana. We had a very nice dinner, and the Arviers came over to see me off.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="29-01-2004">
		<p>We had a very early start, with the taxi picking us up at 5.30 am. Unfortunately, I’d had to give back the hospital Toyota!  So we flew out of Wynyard in the dark, driving rain – not quite the nicest send-off.</p>
		<p>We stopped over in Melbourne, where we had time to get our rescheduled flight tickets printed. We had no chance to leave the airport, so we continued straight on to Christchurch. We were hiring a car from one of Dad’s work contacts, called ‘Dave Dave’, apparently so called because one ‘Dave’ would not be enough to cover his huge bulk. However, there was a bit of a mix up, so we had to wait half an hour for him.</p>
		<p>Dave Dave was not as gargantuan as I had been hoping for. He drove us into town where we picked up our hire car – a Mazda Familia. Now we were set to go, and Dad drove us up to Kaikoura. The sky was pretty grey, and there wasn’t much to see, so I ended up sleeping most of the way.</p>
		<p>We stayed at a bed and breakfast just out of town called the Old Convent, which as you can imagine used to be a convent. The hosts, Judith and Gordon, were very friendly. We decided to have dinner there – a nice four course meal with whole crayfish. Kaikoura means ‘to eat crayfish’ in Maori.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="30-01-2004">
		<p>We had arranged to go whale watching this morning, so after a quick breakfast of bacon and eggs we headed off to the whale watch centre. We got a little lost on the way, so turned up just as the trip was about to begin.</p>
		<p>The trip was excellent, and although it was very cloudy it was mainly dry. Our guide, Rob, kept us entertained throughout the 3 hour boat trip, especially with his funky, computer generated presentations. We saw three sperm whales, a junior albatross, and a pod of Hectors dolphins.</p>
		<p>We had lunch at the Mussel Boys restaurant. I had steamed mussels in a chilli and coriander sauce – yum! Mum wasn’t feeling too well, so she went back for a sleep while I went on a walk in the bush with Dad. It was supposed to be a reasonably long walk of 45 minutes, but we finished it in just 15! We went to the Olive Branch for dinner, while poor Mum had toast with jam back at the motel.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="31-01-2004">
		<p>I went scuba diving this morning with a local dive centre. There was another English man from Exeter, and two Polish guys. The water was cold, but didn’t feel too bad with 7mm wetsuits. However, the visibility was pretty poor, which was a shame. We had two boat dives throughout the morning, and saw an octopus and some crayfish in an alcove. There were some seals on the nearby rocks while we had a hot chocolate on the boat, but they didn’t swim with us.</p>
		<p>After a quick lunch at the Mussel Brothers we headed back down towards Christchurch. We stopped off at a small beach on the way, which one of the guests had recommended to Dad. It wasn’t anything special though. Before getting all the way back to Christchurch we turned off towards Oxford, and stopped for a drink and cheesecake in Rangiora. Mum had booked us into a lovely bed and breakfast called Waimakariri Lodge. We were the only guests there, and the hosts Sharon and Ian were very nice. Dad was interested in an old Citroen they had. There were also two nice dogs. Apparently, on a clear day they have great views of the mountains, but during our stay they were hidden by the clouds and rain.</p>
		<p>We drove out to a small town called Darfield for dinner, and just about the only place to eat was a pizza shop. They did very nice gourmet pizzas though. We had a nice sleep in some really comfortable beds.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="01-02-2004">
		<p>Today we drove through Arthur’s Pass, hoping for some spectacular scenery. Unfortunately, we couldn’t see very much because of the awful weather. It was really raining hard today. The locals are very appreciative of the rain though, as there has been a recent drought.</p>
		<p>After a brief stop in the Arthur’s Pass Visitor Centre, where there were some photographs and details of various walks, we continued on to Hokitika. This is a smallish town on the west coast, where we managed to find a pretty good Indian curry house for lunch. My first Indian in six months! We then spent a while in Ecoworld, which consisted mainly of aquariums and a kiwi habitat. I got to feed some giant eels, and we saw two kiwis in their virtually pitch-black habitat.</p>
		<p>We spent the night in Fox Glacier.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="02-02-2004">
		<p>It was an early start this morning for our glacier walk. We collected our hiking boots from the centre, and were driven up to the base of the glacier. Jim, our guide, led us up to the glacier via some native bush. It was quite a steep climb, so we all got a good workout. We were extremely lucky with the weather – there was a break in the rain for the whole morning, and the sun was even out during our walk.</p>
		<p>Before we walked out on to the glacier itself, we had to strap crampons to the bottom of our boots. The guides were out with ice axes, cutting steps into the ice for us. They have to do this every day, as the steps tend to melt overnight! The glacial ice was very blue, due to the air being compressed out of it. We spent about an hour on the glacier, and climbed up to see an ice cave. Fox Glacier is apparently moving very fast. It takes about 80 years for ice to travel from the top to the bottom. It had receded by about 100 metres in the five years Jim had been working there.</p>
		<p>As we returned to the coach it started pouring with rain again. We had lunch in the town, and then drove down to Wanaka. As we went through a pass in the mountains the grey skies cleared, and we had beautiful sunshine for most of the journey.</p>
		<p>We had dinner at a Japanese restaurant with fabulous views over Lake Wanaka. The sashimi was great, especially the blue cod with ginger and spring onions. We ran into Mark Tuthill, who worked as a house officer with me in Northampton. He said that he’d run into one of the A&amp;E nurses last week. It almost feels like home!</p>
		<p>Our motel for tonight was called the Fairway Motel, and was just out of town. It was reasonably comfortable, but the best feature was that I got my own room – no more parental snoring to keep me awake!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="03-02-2004">
		<p>This morning we visited Stuart Landsborough’s Puzzling World. It was pretty interesting. It started off with a display of various holograms, then had several optical illusions, such as three dimensional faces that seem to follow you around the room, and a false perspective room where you look really big standing in one corner, and really small in the other. We had to have a look in the Roman toilets too.</p>
		<p>We had pizza for lunch, and then went for a walk at Diamond Lake. It was quite a steep and muddy track though, so we gave up halfway there! We spent the rest of the afternoon doing a bit of shopping, and then had dinner at a nice restaurant with origami models hung up around the ceiling. It turned out that previous customers had made them, so I made a few for them to add to the collection.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="04-02-2004">
		<p>We drove to Mount Cook this morning, stopping off at Twizel (yes, a real place!) for a mid-morning coffee. We passed a family moving house on the highway – they had the whole house on the back of a truck! The weather was great, so I got some good photos of the mountain as we arrived. We had lunch in the hotel coffee shop, and then booked on a guided tour around Lake Tasman to see the Tasman glacier.</p>
		<p>This tour was excellent, and very informative. Dad was excited about seeing an MG Magnette in the car park. We had a short walk to the lake, and then went around in small groups. Our guide was called Sybil, and she showed us some mini icebergs, some of which we could see rolling over in the water. She picked up some basal ice for us to hold, which is ice that had broken off from the bottom of the lake. Apparently, chunks the size of a hotel can break off and shoot to the surface! We drove up to the glacier, and the other guide had a swim in the water. It was only 3 degrees, so I think he was a bit crazy! We raced back in the power boats, which was good fun.</p>
		<p>When we finished, we drove on to Lake Tekapo for the night. We stayed at a motel with a view out over the lake. There was a Morgan car club staying there, so Dad liked looking at all the Morgans. Dinner was at a very good Chinese restaurant.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="05-02-2004">
		<p>We had breakfast in the Observatory Café, which had inflatable aliens behind the bar. Then we drove to Timaru where we had a Thai buffet for lunch. The sales were on for Waitangi day tomorrow, so Mum spent some time in the shops, and I bought some more clothes.</p>
		<p>We got down to Oamaru in the afternoon, and booked into a motel. In the evening we went to see the yellow-eyed penguins. These are the rarest species of penguin, and are only found on the south east coast of New Zealand. We drove up to a penguin hide on the side of a cliff, to watch the penguins coming out of the sea. As they come up to the beach, they swim around on the surface looking like a duck, and sometimes leaping out of the water. Then they stand on the beach for a while, drying themselves in the sun, before climbing up the cliff to their nests. It was amazing how far up the cliff they could climb.</p>
		<p>We had a guide, called Jim, who had been looking after and tagging the penguins for over twenty years. He was very interesting and really enthusiastic about his work. He took us along the cliff to see a couple of penguin nests, and we could get right up to the penguins without them seeming to be disturbed.  There were only twenty three penguins living on this stretch of beach. We saw the oldest male, and his infant in the nest.</p>
		<p>After the penguins, we drove around town looking for somewhere to eat. However, there didn’t seem to be many restaurants at all, so we eventually went into the only place we could find. It was in the old post office, called the Last Post, and I had a very nice steak. They gave us huge portions though!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="06-02-2004">
		<p>We drove back up the coast to Christchurch, stopping off in Timaru for lunch. We had trouble finding a motel with vacancies in Christchurch, and we were lucky to stop off at a duty motel, who phoned around to find us a place. However, we couldn’t find it, but managed to get the last room in a cheaper motel.</p>
		<p>We dropped the car back to Dave Dave, who gave us a lift into the town. On the way we saw an interesting sight – a mad looking man wandering around with just a loose t-shirt on. He was mooning everyone he passed, and it was hilarious to watch their reactions! Dave left us in the cathedral square, next to the tourist information building. Dad asked about going to a Maori Hangi in the evening, but it looked too commercialised, so we decided against it. We had a walk around the cathedral, which had lots of burial plaques for people from Oxford University. They had an impressive looking organ, and I expect the acoustics would be nice to sing in. However, there was no concert arranged while we were in Christchurch.</p>
		<p>We went to a Japanese restaurant called Sala Sala for dinner. They were very busy, so we had to sit at the sushi bar, but the food was excellent. We had loads of sashimi, a big portion of fried chicken, and then moved on to some sushi, all washed down with a couple of Sapporo beers. An American couple sitting next to us were quite friendly, and started up a conversation. I sent a text message to Chris Chopdar along the lines of, “I’m sitting in a great restaurant in Christchurch eating sashimi and drinking Sapporo beer”. He later told me that he felt very envious reading the message in the dark, cold weather of an Oxford winter.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="07-02-2004">
		<p>After all the glorious weather of the past week, we came full circle and had rain again. We walked into town and had a mid-morning snack in the Arts Centre. There was a small market which we had a brief look around, although it wasn’t very interesting. They had a stretch of road with people selling paintings.</p>
		<p>We had lunch in an Asian food court, where I had a pretty good Singapore Laksa. I’m still waiting for the real thing in a few days time though! We spent the afternoon shopping for mosquito nets and a Paksafe for my rucksack, then had a rest back at the motel until dinner.</p>
		<p>We went to the Curators House restaurant, which was on the edge of the botanical gardens. It was a very nice place, and we were sat in the garden area. This would normally be in the open air, but they had closed the side windows so we were inside. I had ostrich steak to start, and then paella. Mum was a bit worried about a cat which was roaming around the restaurant.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="08-02-2004">
		<p>We left the bags at the motel and wandered into town for breakfast. I had eggs Benedict in a department store. It started pouring down, so we caught a taxi to the airport a little early. Our flight left at around lunch time, and we got into Sydney by mid-afternoon, where Douglas picked us up. I wondered what car he would now have, and was not surprised to see a flashy new Mercedes! We just about managed to get all our luggage in, and then he drove us back to his house in Woronora. The house was just as I remembered it from 8 years ago, and Dad was just impressed with his home bar as I had been!</p>
		<p>We had a quick swim in his pool before dinner. It was much hotter than New Zealand, and so we came to be very grateful for the pool. We had a drink in his bar, and then drove out to a Chinese restaurant in Miranda for dinner. The food was very authentic, and it helped that Doug knew the owners.</p>
		<p>Douglas’ friend, Heidi came over after dinner. She was a Dutch woman, whom I had met on my visit here in 1996.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="09-02-2004">
		<p>Doug cooked us eggs and bacon for breakfast, which we ate on his veranda. We had a couple of unexpected guests – two Rainbow Lorikeets came to the table, and ate some bread from Dad’s hand.</p>
		<p>After breakfast, Doug gave us a lift to the station. We caught a train in to the city, and Heidi left to catch a plane back to Brisbane. Sam and Lynette were waiting for us at the station. They had been in Sydney for over a week, waiting for their Indian Visas to be issued, so they were getting quite bored on their own.</p>
		<p>We walked around town, and went to the Tourist Information centre, because I wanted to find the nearest Bendigo Bank to close my account. It happened to be quite far out of town, so I decided to write to them instead. It was very hot and stuffy, especially on the crowded streets, so we kept ducking into shops for the air conditioning. We walked through the Botanical Gardens, and had a cold drink in the café, sitting beneath trees full of screeching bats! We then walked over to the Opera House, and saw lots of crazy people jogging in the park – it’s far too hot to exercise!</p>
		<p>We had a rest in the Opera House, but unfortunately there were no performances we could get to. We all went back to Doug’s in the afternoon, to go swimming. However, we had to walk back from the station, as Doug was working. We bought a crate of beer and some wine from the bottle shop by the station, and then had to lug it all the way back to his place. The walk took 45 minutes, including the time it took us getting lost! Luckily, it was still very light, as I remember what it was like stumbling down that path in the dark.</p>
		<p>Typically, the instant we got into the pool the sun went in. The water was pretty cold, but we sat in the water drinking cold beers nonetheless. Doug got home from work at 6pm and joined us in the pool, and then we went out for dinner. We couldn’t all fit in Doug’s Merc, so I drove Lynette in his BMW Z3 – very nice! It took me a while to get used to driving a manual transmission though, so Lyn was a bit shaky by the time we arrived!</p>
		<p>We went to an Italian place, run by Chinese, that specialised in seafood. Doug said the portions were very large, but I was sceptical when he only ordered a bruschetta, a Caesar salad, and a ‘seafood special for two’, to feed all six of us. However, we couldn’t manage to finish it between us! It was the biggest plate of seafood I had ever seen, and as Doug said, we must have eaten a whole ecosystem.</p>
		<p>Sam and Lynette stayed over in Doug’s lounge.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="10-02-2004">
		<p>Douglas went to work this morning, but left us the Mercedes to drive around in. We took the girls back to the station, as they had to go to the Indian Embassy to pick up their Visas. We then drove back to Miranda, to go to the Chinese restaurant for lunch. Unfortunately, it was closed today, so we ate in the food court of the shopping centre – reputedly the largest shopping centre in the southern hemisphere.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon, we drove over to Crenulla Bay to have a walk around. I had a haircut, then we drove over to the Mazda dealer to have a look at the new RX-8s. They were pretty cool, and I’m quite tempted to get one when I get back!</p>
		<p>We had a swim in the afternoon, and then two of Doug’s friends, Mark and Janice came over for dinner. We walked down the road to Dijons, where I had oysters and a chicken risotto. This was where I had lambs brains eight years ago, but the menu was a bit more normal now.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="11-02-2004">
		<p>We packed our bags into Doug’s car, and drove down to the Sydney fish market for breakfast. I had never imagined eating sashimi for breakfast before, but we ate so much raw fish and oysters that I felt quite ill! Douglas had a sashimi preparation course, so we walked around the city for a couple of hours while we waited for him.</p>
		<p>We packed our bags into Doug’s car, and drove down to the Sydney fish market for breakfast. I had never imagined eating sashimi for breakfast before, but we ate so much raw fish and oysters that I felt quite ill! Douglas had a sashimi preparation course, so we walked around the city for a couple of hours while we waited for him.</p>
		<p>When we arrived at Changi airport, Aunty Claire and Brandon came to pick us up. It was hard to remember to call her Claire rather than Nancy. Brandon drove us to Newton Circus for some late dinner. Dad was so happy, that he had two plates of olwak! We went back to Aunty Nellie’s house, feeling very stuffed. We stood outside the house for quite some time, as we couldn’t work out how to open the door. In the end, it turned out that we just had to give it a good shove.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="12-02-2004">
		<p>We had some curry puffs for breakfast at Aunty Nellie’s and then caught the bus down to Orchard Road. I had to book some accommodation for Sam and Lynette, so we walked around looking for a hostel. I eventually booked them a dorm at the YMCA for one night. After that we would all move into a room at Hotel 81 on Bencoolen Street.</p>
		<p>We had lunch at a hawker centre, where Dad and I had chicken rice, and then I got some Bobo Hitam.</p>
		<p>After walking around Orchard Road for the afternoon, we ended up in Scotts Plaza, where I had Yong Tau Fu soup, and Mum had Ais Kachang. In the evening, we caught a bus over to visit Uncle Steven and Aunty Anna, with Uncle Jimmy, Aunty Rosa, their children, and Grandma who had arrived yesterday. It was quite a full house. Everyone seemed very surprised at how tall I was, and how old – they thought I was only 20!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="13-02-2004">
		<p>Rodney the cabbie picked us up this morning, and took us to the Malaysian tourist information office, so I could get some brochures about Malaysia. We also went to the coach office, to enquire about coaches to Kuala Lumpur. We met Aunty Claire for a late breakfast of Kaya toast and poached eggs, and then we went shopping, as Mum needed some new hand luggage. She managed to haggle the price down from $70 to $42!</p>
		<p>We had lunch at the People’s Park hawker centre, where I had grilled dumplings and noodle soup. We went back to Aunty Nellie’s to have a shower, before catching a taxi back to town to meet up with Sam and Lynette. We had a buffet dinner at the Phoenix Hotel, with Grandma, Suk Por, Aunties Nellie and Claire and Uncle James.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="14-02-2004">
		<p>Mum’s friend Veronica came to pick us up this morning. She was taking Mum and Dad out for the day, and so she dropped me off with my luggage at Hotel 81. The girls had already checked in, and as I was getting hungry we had a walk down Orchard Road to Scott's for lunch. The girls had an Indian curry, and I got some Char Kwae Teow, with some Popia and Kwae Pi Te. We slowly made our way back to the hotel, stopping off to buy some new, cheap clothes. I caught up on writing my diary before I’d have to give my laptop to Mum and Dad to take back home, and then we lounged around until dinner. Aunty Claire is supposed to be taking us all to Newton Circus, and then I’ll go to the airport to see Mum and Dad off.</p>
		<p>With a bit of luck, I’ll have the rest of my diary in paper format when I get back!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="15-02-2004">
		<p>Mum and Dad left last night after a good meal at Newton Circus – we ordered far too much satay though!</p>
		<p>We wanted to visit Haw Par Villa this morning, but while we were looking lost in the MRT station a Singaporean lady approached us and asked if we needed any help. Her name was Andrea, and she worked as a medical researcher. She was very talkative, and took us on a walking tour of the CBD. We went into a Buddhist temple and saw people praying for their ancestors, leaving food and simulated money. The air was thick with jos-stick smoke.</p>
		<p>After leaving Andrea, we caught a couple of buses to Haw Par Villa. Admission was free, but to my disappointment the ten courts of hell were closed for renovations. It was very hot, and the water flume rides I had enjoyed with Adam many years ago had been closed down long ago, so after wandering around for a while we had a drink and an ice cream in the café. Sam and Lynette were amused that according to the Chinese zodiac their mum was described as ‘cantankerous’! They had to send her a text message to let her know, of course.</p>
		<p>We caught the bus to Chinatown and had lunch in People’s Plaza. I had a good laksa and some otak. After lunch we walked down Smith Street, which had more of the older style of Chinese shops that the girls had been expecting. We bought some loose fitting light trousers, for keeping mosquitoes away at night, but I was very unsuccessful at haggling.</p>
		<p>As we walked down towards Raffles Hotel, we stopped off in the Funan Centre for a coffee, and I also had some Kaya toast even though I wasn’t particularly hungry. I know how to eat for the sake of eating! There was an Acer computer show in the lobby, and I had to drag myself away. When we got to Raffles, I felt a bit of a fraud walking around talking photos inside, but a lot of other tourists were doing the same. We sat up at the bar in the courtyard and had some Singapore Slings. A European lady came up and asked me if I knew the location of the bar where people throw peanuts on the floor. At the time I didn’t realise that this was the practice in the Long Bar upstairs, so I thought she was a bit crazy.</p>
		<p>Sam and Lynette went to check their e-mails, while I returned to our room. I called home, and caught my parents just as they were walking through the door. They had had a reasonable flight, but complained that the temperature was only 6 degrees over there!</p>
		<p>Sam had a sleep while Lynette and I had dinner at the hawker centre over the road. We then had a couple of beers and watched Moulin Rouge on the TV before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="16-02-2004">
		<p>We woke up pretty late this morning, so took our leisurely time getting ready. Veronica picked us up at 12.30 and took us to a hotel for lunch. There was a buffet, with a variety of Malaysian and Nonya food. Needless to say, we stuffed ourselves silly! There was even an ais kachang machine to make your own, but the sauces didn’t taste right.</p>
		<p>After lunch we staggered back to the car, and Veronica drove us to the Esplanade. We parked in the hedgehog building. It’s actually a concert hall and theatre, but the locals call it the hedgehog, or less kindly, the durian, according to its very spiky appearance.</p>
		<p>We walked out to the Esplanade, and took a few photos of the Merlion on the river bank. It was pretty hot in the sun, so we went into a café for a cool drink. Veronica then dropped us off back at the hotel, and I called Aunty Claire to arrange dinner. We still couldn’t face the thought of more food!</p>
		<p>I went to check my e-mail, and to send off my CV to apply for a job. We changed into slightly smarter clothes, then walked to Raffles Plaza to meet Aunty Claire. As we were waiting in the hotel lobby, we noticed that there were lots of airline pilots checking in.</p>
		<p>Claire took us to the Equinox restaurant in the old Westin Stamford hotel. It was on the 70th floor, and the views over the city were fabulous. It was a very upmarket restaurant, and we had a lovely meal. I had roast duck with fois gras salad to start, and then pot roasted peppered lobster. They left me to choose the wine, so I ordered a Cabernet Sauvignon from Malborough, NZ. Luckily it turned out to be quite nice.</p>
		<p>After dinner Claire left us, and on the way back we walked over to the Pan Pacific hotel to ride up in the bubble lift.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="17-02-2004">
		<p>A shrill alarm woke us up this morning at 8am. We were in two minds as to whether we should evacuate the building, so I phoned reception, who told us that it was a fault. It felt like being back in college for fire drills. We decided to try and sleep for another hour or so, but unsurprisingly we woke up three hours later!</p>
		<p>Having had a quick shower, we were all feeling quite hungry, so went to the Kopitiam food court over the road. I had some chicken rice and papaya juice. With satisfied stomachs we made our way to Harbour Front MRT, to catch the cable car to Sentosa. While we were waiting, I bought a pair of flip flops. I got a good bargain without even trying – the salesman said, “let me see what’s the best price I can do,” and reduced them by $5.</p>
		<p>I found the cable car ride quite fun but Lynette got very sweaty palms, and kept telling Sam and I, “Don’t shake the cabin!” It was very hot again today, and was a little uncomfortable wandering around in the open, but none the less we was the Merlion and the gardens. We caught the monorail to Underwaterworld, and found out that there was an opening to dive with the sharks. I signed up immediately, and after a bit a cajoling Sam agreed to come along.</p>
		<p>The dive was fantastic fun. We didn’t have fins, so we walked around the tank, with everyone in the tunnel watching us. We saw Lynette there, taking lots of pictures of us. It felt very nice walking around, like walking on the moon. We got to see, and touch a Moray eel, leopard sharks, a dugong, and we fed the Eagle rays. They sucked cockles out of our hands, then we could hear them crunching them up before spitting out the shells.</p>
		<p>By the time we left Underwaterworld it and become quite overcast, and felt like it was going to storm. We found our way to Burger King and had some Swiss mushroom burgers. No rending burger this time. We decided to take a chance with the weather and went to watch the Musical Fountain. It had got even more tacky than last time, and it was difficult to sit all the way through it. I was still impressed with the Merlion’s ocular lasers though, and at least it stayed dry.</p>
		<p>We caught the most overcrowded coach back to the mainland. It was like being a sardine in a tin. We had a couple of beers and watched some television before retiring.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="18-02-2004">
		<p>I spent the morning filling out a job application, and then Sam and I went for lunch with Aunty Claire. Lynette was feeling ill, so she went to the room for a rest.</p>
		<p>Claire took us to a restaurant for dim sum, and let me choose the food. We had spring rolls, char siew pows, sharks fin soup, steamed park and prawn dumplings, glutinous rice and two separate vegetable dishes. Needless to say, we couldn’t manage any desert!</p>
		<p>We are really just killing time now, as we have two more weeks to wait until we meet Mike in Kuala Lumpur. We did some e-mailing this afternoon, and read our books. I’ve started Bill Bryson’s ‘A Walk in the Woods’. It seems appropriate to read travel books while travelling. I’ve got a book about eight men and a duck crossing the Pacific on a reed boat to look forward to, although I doubt any of our experiences will reflect that.</p>
		<p>Lynette and I went over to the Kopitiam for dinner. I had a chicken biryani, and a very large bottle of Tiger beer.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="19-02-2004">
		<p>We went looking for a laundrette this morning, but could only find one that takes four days to wash clothes. I think we’ll try and wait until we reach Malaysia. After lunch we spent an hour or so wandering around Little India. There were lots of typical shops and stalls, selling touristy trinkets and groceries, and a few shops seemingly for the locals, selling furniture and small family shrines.</p>
		<p>In the evening we caught the MRT over to Serangoon for dinner at Aunty Claire’s house. We sat outside, and had a very nice meal of noodles, chicken curry, beef rendang, kwae pie tee and yong tau foo. Grandma and Sook-poh were there, as were Uncle Willy, Aunt Jenny and their daughter Grace. Brendon came home later, as he was at camp for his National Service.</p>
		<p>After dinner, I played the piano and ended up singing. Brendon was quite impressed, and got his camcorder to film me. It was a pretty late night, so they gave us a lift back to our hotel at midnight.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="20-02-2004">
		<p>I was a bit ill today with diarrhoea, so we didn’t do much at all. I didn’t have any lunch, and sat with a bottle of water while Sam and Lynette had some Western food at the café next door. Sam is already fed up with Chinese food, and keeps asking for something ‘normal’.</p>
		<p>We spent the afternoon reading, and then went to Pizza Hut for dinner. I only had some soup and onion rings. It was quite an early dinner, so we wandered around the shopping centre afterwards. The girls wanted to get their photos put on CD, so we had to wait around for an hour. A lot of shops had sales on, so I got some more t-shirts at ridiculously low prices.</p>
		<p>We watched Harry Potter on TV, and I got hungry again, so I went over the road to get some wanton soup noodles.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="21-02-2004">
		<p>After a breakfast of Kaya toast and soft boiled eggs, we walked over to the Golden Mile centre to buy our bus tickets to Melaka. It was a very nice walk, and felt good to get some fresh air and exercise. On the way I bought a telephoto converter lens for my camera from the Sim Lim centre.</p>
		<p>The ticket seller was very friendly and helpful. Our tickets to Melaka cost $15, which is about ￡5. We had lunch at a little coffee shop in the shopping centre, where whey were showing a Chinese Kung Fu movie on the television. I had Hong Kong Mee, and some chrysanthemum tea.</p>
		<p>We walked back to the hotel, and watched Saturday Night Fever before dinner. I entertained the girls with lots of John Travolta impressions afterwards! For some reason, none of us could get to sleep, so we ended up trying to remember bad jokes, and the girls fought each other in bed. I read a little before eventually drifting off to sleep.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="22-02-2004">
		<p>We went to Centrepoint shopping centre for lunch with Aunty Claire and her friend Robert. He is the choirmaster at her church, and he wanted to meet me after hearing that I was a singer. I gave him a few tips on where to find some anthems and masses. The lunch was very nice – dim sum, some ma po tau foo, and meatball chook.</p>
		<p>After lunch I went to the bookshop to get some Malay phrase books. I’m going to try and learn enough to get by. Aunty Claire bought some avocado mocha desserts for us to try, which I didn’t really like. We then went to the supermarket to get some durian for the girls to try. They actually thought it wasn’t too bad, but couldn’t eat very much. I didn’t try any at all!</p>
		<p>The rest of the afternoon was spent packing our bags – it was a struggle to get them closed. We had dinner at the Kopitiam. The girls had a vegetable curry in a laksa gravy, but they didn’t really like it as they thought it tasted of fish.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="23-02-2004">
		<p>We woke up early (well, early for us) and went down to meet Rodney the cabbie at 8.30. However, he wasn’t there. It turns out that he had gone to the wrong Hotel 81. After a short wait, he picked us up and took us to a coffee shop around the corner for some roti paratha. Unfortunately, the mutton wasn’t cooked yet, so we had to make do with the curry sauce on its own. We then dropped into a bakery to pick up some buns for lunch.</p>
		<p>We arrived at the bus station over an hour early, so after registering ourselves the girls left me with the bags and wandered off to find a toilet. They were gone for forty minutes, and I was starting to get slightly anxious by the time they got back.</p>
		<p>The bus to Melaka was very comfortable, and air conditioned, although it did have squeaky suspension. Passing through customs was painless, with no need to wait. I spent the trip trying to learn some Malay. We had a mid way stop at a food court, where I had some ho fun. The food is extremely cheap, especially with the current exchange rate of 7.1 Ringgit to the pound.</p>
		<p>When we got to Melaka, there were a couple of people from local guest houses waiting at the stop, trying to entice customers. The Traveller’s Lodge looked clean and friendly, so we caught a taxi there. The driver was very chatty, and his grasp of English was excellent, although he kept apologising for how bad it was.</p>
		<p>It was nice to get out of the blazing heat and into an air conditioned room. The hostel is Muslim, which means we have to take off our shoes before entering, and no pork is allowed inside. The owners are young and very amiable. My first priority was laundry, as I had no clean clothes left. The owners washed them for me, then I had to hang them out to dry. There was not much hanging room, so I had socks in the bathroom, t-shirts on the rooftop garden, and pants hanging over the side of the building. Our room cost RM60 per night.</p>
		<p>We braved the sun for the few minutes it took to get into the large shopping centre over the road. I got a new SIM card for my phone which came with a ‘free attractive flask’. Very handy. The girls were hungry despite their buns, so they ordered some Big Mac meals from McDonald's. They accidentally gave them three meals rather than two so I helped them out. The girls spent some time clothes shopping, and I bought a new wallet, as my current one was falling apart.</p>
		<p>Back in the hostel we watched Austin Powers in the café area. Sam and I got hungry, so we left halfway through the film to find some dinner. There was a hawker centre nearby, where we had some very spicy nasi goring, which included bits of prawn with their shells still on. The meals were cheap at RM2.5, but the small cans of Tiger beer were expensive – RM6.2.</p>
		<p>It was still very hot and muggy well into the evening, as there was no breeze. We took a few beers back with us, and sat on the roof to drink them.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="24-02-2004">
		<p>Last night we had made a pact to get up really early, at 6.30am (we weren’t that drunk either)! The idea was to get out and see things before the day got too hot. I dutifully jumped out of bed at the agreed time, and Sam got up after I had finished my shower. There was no chance of rousing Lynette though, so we left her to sleep.</p>
		<p>It was definitely worth getting up early. The temperature was pleasantly cool, and the sun had just risen. We stopped of at a kedai kopi on the way into town, and had some nasi lemak. I really enjoyed it, but seeing as Sam doesn’t like fish all the anchovies put her off. I also had a very sickly kopi, which I almost brought back up while walking afterwards.</p>
		<p>As we got to town, and were standing around looking at the map and wondering what to do, a bicycle rickshaw approached us. He offered us a one hour tour of the city for RM40. I suppose we were expected to haggle, but it seemed a reasonable price. He indirectly complimented Sam by congratulating me on having such a lovely wife! I didn’t bother to correct him.</p>
		<p>The tour was very interesting, although I have never felt more like a tourist. Our guide was knowledgeable and talkative, but his accent often made it difficult to understand him. We were taken through Chinatown, and stopped off at several temples – an Islamic mosque, a Chinese and then a Thai Buddhist temple. We saw where two of the previous Sultans of Melaka were buried, and he even took us to the back of a very posh colonial-style hotel to see a small museum.</p>
		<p>After dropping us off where we started, Sam and I had a look around the Stadthuys museum, which was the seat of government during the Dutch rule. It was pretty big, with plenty of excellent displays. Melaka had a turbulent history, being controlled at various times by sultans, the Portuguese, the Dutch, the English, the Dutch again, and then back to the English, a Japanese occupation, and finally independence. As such, there were articles from each period to see. There was also a mock-up of a traditional Melakan house on stilts, and several rooms about Malay wedding ceremonies.</p>
		<p>We had worked up quite a thirst by now, so we sat at an outside café and had some water before making our way back to the hostel. It was just starting to get uncomfortably hot, and the time was 10.30am. Lynette was still in bed!</p>
		<p>I sat in the lounge area for a while to catch up on my diary. It’s nice to have a lot to write about now. The lounge was very hot, and all the seating was on cushions around the floor, which gave it a very relaxed atmosphere. Sam went to bed at lunchtime, so Lynette and I went out for lunch. We found a Pizza Hut in the adjacent shopping centre. The afternoon was too hot to be out and about, so we spent some time reading in the common room. In the evening we went for a walk to find some dinner. Sam didn’t want hawker food again, so we had quite a long walk away from town. It was a pleasant stroll though. In the end we ate at a KFC in a shopping plaza. I had my usual – five pieces of chicken, while the girls had some incredibly wilted burgers.</p>
		<p>We picked up a couple of Tiger beers on the way back and adjourned to our evening spot on the roof. We had some company this time – Carly from Norway, Jasper from Holland, and Moonah from France. It was good to chat to them, as they had all just come down from Thailand. We didn’t stay up too late, as I was planning another early start tomorrow.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="25-02-2004">
		<p>During the night Sam had to get up to be sick, so in the morning neither of the girls were much inclined to get out of bed. Nevertheless, I had a reasonably early start myself, leaving the hostel at 8.30. I found a short cut into town, through some nice gardens. There were only a few people about yet – the gardeners. And a couple of people catching some early morning exercise. I was surprised to come across an aeroplane and an old car on the far side of the gardens. I had brought my camera, and spent a good portion of the morning taking pictures. The sky seems quite hazy here most of the time, so the sunlight is very diffuse.</p>
		<p>At the exit to the gardens I found some stairs leading up to St Paul’s church, perched on the top of a small hill. I made it there just before a large group of Chinese tourists, so I was able to appreciate the ruins for a brief moment. There were lots of tombstones inside the roofless church, which made it quite atmospheric.</p>
		<p>I continued to wander around, and found myself outside the Melaka Political museum. Aside from lengthy displays about all of Melaka’s Prime Ministers, which was very dull, there were some interesting presentations on the carious political regimes throughout its history. On my way back to the hostel I stopped at the Islamic museum. I didn’t know much about Islam, so I decided to have a look. I thanked the admission clerk with a, “terima kasih”, who seemed surprised and asked whether I spoke Malay. I had been caught out, and had to admit that I couldn’t! There were interesting displays about the general principles behind Islam, and upstairs was a slightly dry history of Islam in Melaka.</p>
		<p>I stopped off at a coffee shop for some roti canai, then was slightly surprised to find the girls were awake when I got back. They had just got up, and were having beans on toast for breakfast in the hostel café. I had an early lunch in the same café, which consisted of a nice home cooked fish curry and rice.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon we watched Spiderman, but unfortunately the Part 2 VCD wasn’t working. That evening we walked the same way as last night and found a Nonya restaurant I had noticed in the Lonely Planet. We were the only customers. We let the waitress recommend the dishes for us, and so had some chicken rendang, chicken with Chinese mushrooms, some prawns in chilli, and some vegetables. I had a chendol for dessert, which was more like a mini ais kachang with the green jelly underneath. It was quite refreshing though.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-02-2004">
		<p>We all slept in quite late this morning. The girls had breakfast while I was getting ready, and then we all walked into town. This was the first time Lynette had been there! We had become used to breaking up the walk by cutting through the large air-conditioned shopping complex.</p>
		<p>We walked along Jalen Heng Jebat, formerly known as Jonker Street, which is famous for antiques. We didn’t go into any shops though, and a lot of it looked very touristy. We had no particular destination in mind, so we meandered around the narrow streets of Chinatown, trying to avoid all the cycles and vehicles pushing their way through. I found a coffee shop for lunch, although the girls weren’t hungry yet, having had a late breakfast. I had bee hoon soup noodles, which were nice, but very hot after I added extra chopped chillies! An elderly gentleman (or possibly a woman) at the next able started talking to us. His English was very broken, but we think he was offering to cook lunch for us next time we were around, and then repeatedly stated, “I’m very old, you know. I’m eighty three. Yes, very old!”</p>
		<p>After a quick exit, we went to tourist information to try and find out about bus times to Port Dickson. Unfortunately, it was closed for lunch. We made a short detour to see St Francis Xavier’s Church, where they were just starting a Mass, before heading back to the hostel.</p>
		<p>We had picked up a few new books today, and I read two of them – The Five People you meet in Heaven, and Big Fish – all in one afternoon. It’s going to be expensive if I keep reading this fast. Depressingly, I haven’t picked up the Malay language book again. I started on Moby Dick, and then we headed out for dinner. I had a craving for pizza, again!</p>
		<p>After dinner we went to the “Spectacular Sound and Light Show”. It was the most boring and awful piece of drivel. As a terrible voice over told us the history of Melaka, the ‘spectacular’ lights would occasionally illuminate a random tree, or a building. The whole story was told with a painfully obvious nationalistic bent. Awful!</p>
		<p>We read for a while before going to sleep.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-02-2004">
		<p>We checked out of the hostel and hefted our rucksacks over to the taxi rank by the shopping centre. It was the first time I had really had to carry it any distance, and in the heat I was soon sweating. The taxi took us to the bus station, where we caught a luxury bus to Seremban for RM6. It was a really nice bus with air conditioning, and the kind of seats that wouldn’t be out of place in an aeroplane’s business class.</p>
		<p>At Seremban we had to change to a local bus for the journey to Port Dickson. I grabbed a doughnut from Dunkin’ Donuts before we set off. This bus was dirty, cramped and hot – more like the proper backpacking experience!</p>
		<p>As soon as we arrived at Port Dickson we were approached by a local taxi driver offering to take us to a hotel. Somewhat unwisely, we hadn’t looked in the Lonely Planet to find anywhere to stay, so we naively went with him. He left us at a real dump of a hotel, with threadbare beds, broken air conditioning, and a filthy toilet, so we immediately left. The owners didn’t seem that surprised when we asked for our money back! After that shock, Lynette chose somewhere a bit nicer – the Corus Paradise Lagoon Hotel. We hailed another taxi, but it was a real struggle to get him to take us there, rather than to his mate’s apartment block, which apparently was a great bargain. Yeah right, we weren’t going to fall for it twice in one day!</p>
		<p>Paradise Lagoon is a very good description of the hotel. It has its own lagoon, corralled in by coconut palms, and compared to the last place it really was a paradise. Lynette’s eyes lit up when she saw it. The room was RM170 a night, with two very large double beds (no more sleeping on the floor for me!), TV, Air con, en-suite etc. There’s a beautiful pool overlooking the sea, which we spent the afternoon making good use of, after a quick lunch in the restaurant. After travelling in the heat, this was heaven.</p>
		<p>We had dinner in the hotel, and then curled up in the big, comfortable beds.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="28-02-2004">
		<p>I got some laundry done today. I had grease all over my shorts, probably from the dirty bus we sat in yesterday. We had a buffet breakfast, sitting next to the pool, and ten I read my book while the girls went for a swim.</p>
		<p>I had an excellent beef burger with cheese and an egg for lunch, and then spent the afternoon by the pool, swimming, enjoying the sun, and getting my diary up to date. While Lynette was checking her emails in the hotel office, she got chatting to the manager of the hotel, who contacted his friend in Kuala Lumpur, and got us a substantial discount at a hotel in the centre of town. Well done Lynette!</p>
		<p>I phoned home and had a nice talk with Mum, Dad and Steven. Dinner was on the beach by the lagoon. It was a nice buffet, with satay, and a steamboat that you had to cook up on the buffet table. After dinner we went to the hotel bar for a drink. There was a band who sang very out of tune, but one of the girls said I was a handsome young man, so I put up with the singing!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="29-02-2004">
		<p>The girls went for breakfast, while I had to put some pressure on the laundry service to get my clothes back before we had to leave. They finally delivered them, five minutes before we checked out.</p>
		<p>We caught a taxi back to the bus station, which cost us RM10. All the taxis we’ve caught so far have cost us RM10, so I think we’re being swindled. The bus wasn’t due for over an hour, so I left the girls with the bags and walked over the road to an Indian hawker stall. I had some murtabak, and a warm Coke, as I didn’t trust the ice. I was a bit put off the food by all the flies.</p>
		<p>The bus trip to Kuala Lumpur was pretty uneventful. It was very hot and the road was very rough. As we got into KL, we hit solid traffic, so we decided to get off the bus early. We found a taxi quite quickly, who charged us RM10 to take us to the hotel. His meter said RM2.70 though, but I was too hot to argue.</p>
		<p>We are staying at the Bintang Warisan Hotel on Jalan Bukit Bintang, which is pretty central. The room isn’t as nice as the last place, especially with Lynette’s wet laundry strung up all over the place, but it’s quite adequate. I was suffering with a bit of a cold, so I had a quick sleep while the girls went out the change some money. When they got back, Sam noticed something dirty in my bed. It looked like old, dried vomit over the sheets, which I hadn’t noticed. Yuck! I leapt in the shower, and Sam got housekeeping to change the sheets.</p>
		<p>We asked at hotel reception to direct us to a nearby bar, and after a bit of thought he said, “I know – Finnigan’s!” So we ended up at an Irish bar, sitting outside drinking Tiger beers. We got talking to a Swedish photographer called Hans, who was here working freelance. Several beers, and whiskies, later we staggered over to a hawker centre for some food. It was about 1 am. I had some olwak, which I vaguely remember being very good as post-drinking food. Unfortunately, we didn’t have enough money on us to pay for the food, so Hans made up the rest for us. I wanted to go to a karaoke bar, but fortunately there weren’t any on the way back!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="01-03-2004">
		<p>Oooh, didn’t feel very well this morning. Lynette had been up to vomit during the night. At least this time it wasn’t in my suitcase (see Vienna diary 2003).</p>
		<p>I left the girls feeling sorry for themselves in bed, and went out for some breakfast. It’s amazing what an apple Danish and a Starbucks coffee will do for a hangover. I took a couple of coffees back for the girls, and after a considerable amount of time getting ready we headed out into the fresh air. We made our way past the man selling bubble blowing guns on our street corner; he seems to be a permanent fixture, filling the road with soapy bubbles.</p>
		<p>It was in the shopping centre food court that I had ‘The Chilli Incident’. I had ordered a bowl of soup noodles, and sprinkled in some small pickled chillies. As I finished the soup the heat hit me, and kept getting progressively more intolerable. I was bright red and hyperventilating, enough to cause the girls some alarm. Lynette asked whether I was having palpitations. At that inopportune moment a lady arrived to clean our plates away. She stood at the side of our table with a bemused grin on her face as she watched me suffering! It took quite a while to get over it, and it had caused my hangover headache to return with full force.</p>
		<p>We had a gentle stroll around the shopping centre, and then spent the afternoon reading. I got hungry around mid-morning, so Sam and I went to get some McDonald's and brought some back for Lynette, who wasn’t coping with her hangover too well.</p>
		<p>Sam and I tried to find the hawker stall that we ate at last night while Lynette stayed in bed. However, the alcoholic haze clouding our memories prevented us from finding it. We ended up eating at a similar place, having dodged crowds of people insisting that we eat at their stalls. I had seafood noodles, and Sam had sweet and sour pork. There were lots of crabs in a cage by our table, and more of a surprise was to be found in the adjacent cage, which was full of big frogs. They brought a bowl of fresh chillies with the food, which I politely declined.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="02-03-2004">
		<p>A knock at the door woke us up at 8.45. Housekeeping were doing very early rounds today. We told them to come back later and slept on until 10am. We finally got out to have some breakfast at 11.30. I thought it was probably closer to lunchtime, so I had a tuna sandwich.</p>
		<p>The girls caught the train to the airport to meet Mike. There was some slight concern over the organisation of this meeting, as Mike didn’t have our phone numbers or know where we were staying, so if he had missed the girls it would have been a bit of a problem. While they were out, I went for quite a long walk. I went to Merdeka Square, where the Malaysian flag was first raised on the day of independence from Britain in 1957. There was a lot of interesting architecture to absorb, and I had a look around an impressive mosque. Because I was wearing shorts, I had to put on a big robe to cover myself up; I was extremely hot walking around. I then walked over to the Market Square, and from there made my way along the busy streets to the Menara Tower. This is a very vehicle-orientated city, with little time given to pedestrians to cross the roads. Even when the lights are red, you have to watch out for motorbikes, for whom the traffic signals don’t seem to apply.</p>
		<p>The view from the Menara Tower was spectacular, at 421 metres high. Because it is on a hill, it is actually at the same level as the Petronas Towers. There was a pretty informative audio guide to the sights, and although the sky was hazy it was possible to see out to the mountains surrounding the city.</p>
		<p>Afterwards, I walked back to the hotel. A taxi driver had offered to take me there for 15RM, which was an obvious rip-off. I had a shower, then checked my e-mails, and by the time I got back to the room the girls were just arriving with Mike. He had had a very long trip from America, but seemed quite energetic and keen to get out.</p>
		<p>We went for a walk back along the way I had gone this afternoon, and I had some pasta in a food court. We then walked over to the Petronas Towers. Unfortunately we were just too late to go up to the sky bridge, so we planned to return tomorrow.</p>
		<p>We needed to get some beer to welcome Mike, so we stopped off at a bar. We had only just sat down when a real monsoon-type rainfall started. Obviously we had to stay there and have a second drink, what with the rain and all. We were getting rather hungry though, so we had to brave the elements and dash across the road to a café. It looked like there were a couple of sharks swimming around in a fish tank, but we couldn’t work out whether or not they were real. The rain stopped while we were eating, so we managed to get back to the hotel reasonably dry, except for Mike who had spilled his drink over his lap.</p>
		<p>We had a couple of beers in the room, and then I tried lancing a fluctuant lump on my toe, which drew considerable interest from the crowds. I couldn’t get any pus out, so I’ll just take some antibiotics and see how it goes.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="03-03-2004">
		<p>We had an early start this morning and were down for breakfast by 8.30. We ate in the hotel’s café. Mike and I had nasi lemak, and Lynette had a slice of toast which she promptly threw back up. I was feeling quite nauseated after breakfast, and so had to walk quite slowly as we went over to the Petronas Towers. As we waited for our time to go up to the sky bridge we sat in Burger King and had a drink. Mike was impressed with the free Coke refills.</p>
		<p>We had an early start this morning and were down for breakfast by 8.30. We ate in the hotel’s café. Mike and I had nasi lemak, and Lynette had a slice of toast which she promptly threw back up. I was feeling quite nauseated after breakfast, and so had to walk quite slowly as we went over to the Petronas Towers. As we waited for our time to go up to the sky bridge we sat in Burger King and had a drink. Mike was impressed with the free Coke refills.</p>
		<p>We were feeling better after this, so once we had satisfied our urge to take pictures we caught a taxi over to the National Museum. We managed to get the driver to use his meter rather than charging us a flat rate of 10RM, although as the drive took longer and longer we wondered whether we would end up having to pay more.</p>
		<p>We didn’t go into the museum – we had just got the taxi to take us there because neither he nor the two previous cabbies we’d asked knew the way to the Planetarium or National Mosque. It was a reasonably short walk over to the mosque, and although it was currently closed we had a good look around the outside. By this time we were getting hungry, so we had to walk back into town. We got lunch in a café by Merdeka Square. Mike had ‘Kung Fu noodles’, which he really liked.</p>
		<p>We walked back to the planetarium through a light drizzle, which was quite refreshing. There was a Space Show on at 2pm, which it looked like we were going to be late for, so we got a bemused taxi driver to give us a two minute ride to the Planetarium. We were just in time for the show.</p>
		<p>We were ushered into a very dark corridor leading to the theatre, and none of us could see a thing. We weren’t sure where we were, or if the show had even started, so you can imagine how startling it was when right next to us there erupted a shocking scream! Lynette was so taken aback that she fell over backwards into us. The theatre was packed with small school children, who had unanimously decided to scream at the same time. We managed to stumble our way through the dark to find some seats, and watched an enjoyable show about the sun on the I-Max screen. The experience was very funny, due to the continual shouting of the kids. Whenever there was a close up of the sun, they all screamed. As our eyes got accustomed to the gloom we could see that most of them were clambering over the seats like monkeys. Their poor teacher wouldn’t have had a chance trying to control them.</p>
		<p>Fortunately they all left straight after the film, so we could explore the rest of the exhibits in peace. It was fun and interactive – sometimes painfully so. There was a plasma screen which a put my hand against. I then touched Sam on the arm and got a huge spark between us, followed by the small of singed flesh. I had made a small burn on her arm! My other favourite exhibit was a tilted room, similar to Wanaka’s Puzzling World. However, this was even worse, and I was staggering all over the place. It was very amusing though. We then caught a lift up to the observatory level and used the telescopes to look out over the city.</p>
		<p>Walking out of the air-conditioned Planetarium, it felt like being hit by a heat wave, so we decided to call it a day and caught a taxi back to the hotel. We each had a shower and then headed out for dinner. Sam remembered where we had eaten with Hans, so we went back there. I had olwah and mah poh tau fu; the owner seemed very impressed that I knew the names in Chinese. It was very nice, but quite expensive. We spent the rest of the evening playing cards.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="04-03-2004">
		<p>I went out and got a sausage and egg MacMuffin for breakfast while the others were getting ready. I couldn’t face nasi lemak again! I checked my emails while they were eating, as we’ve just exchanged contracts on the house in Oxford, so I needed to look out for messages from my solicitor.</p>
		<p>It was getting very hot by the time we walked over to Medan Pasar (the Old Market) to catch a bus to the Batu caves. We had to wait for a while in the sweltering hear, so by now we were all very sweaty – especially Mike, who was wearing jeans. The bus trip took about half an hour, but it took ages to get out of the city traffic.</p>
		<p>The Batu caves looked very impressive. They were found about one hundred years ago, and now days roughly a million pilgrims visit them every February for the Thaipusam festival, where devotees pierce themselves with hooks and hand ornaments from them. There was no sign of this recent festival today, with no obvious blood stains on the floor! A very enthusiastic Englishman convinced us to hire some audio guides, and then we hauled ourselves up the 272 steps to the main cave. The area itself was very impressive, with magnificently arching limestone formations. The few Hindu shrines and statues dotted around seemed to lessen the attractiveness though. We climber up some more steps to an open air chamber, where there were quite a few monkeys and cats looking for food. While we were standing around, we were shocked to witness a rock fall from the roof of the cave and smash into the floor. On further examination there were quite a few of these rocks scattered around the caves, any of which could have killed someone with a direct blow on the head. We quickly made our way back out to the open air!</p>
		<p>We had a cold drink at the café, and Mike produced some dodgy-looking sweet and sour prunes which turned his tongue luminous orange. We then had a look in the ‘art gallery’ – a smaller cave filled with paintings and Hindu statues. It was very attractive, and the cave acoustics were so nice that I was about to sing something when some other tourists came in and spoiled my fun!</p>
		<p>We had a fantastic lunch in an Indian café. We each had curry on a banana leaf, and then my masala dosai arrived which was absolutely enormous. The rest of the afternoon we spent in town. We played some more cards, then went into a music shop that Mike had seen, where he promptly plugged in a bass guitar and began happily playing away. I had Penang Laksa for dinner in one of the shopping centres. Lynette kindly pointed out that it looked like watery diarrhoea as I was just taking my first mouthful. It tasted nice, but she did have a point!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="05-03-2004">
		<p>Lynette and Mike got back very late last night after having a few drinks, and this morning Lynette was really suffering. I was woken up by Sam, asking if I had anything that could stop her being sick, as she had thrown up five times during the night. After a lot of cajoling she agreed to have an injection of metoclopramide in her bottom. She didn’t really enjoy the experience, but felt much better afterwards. She managed to stay in bed for the whole day though.</p>
		<p>Mike and I went out for breakfast. Mike ate two burgers and a luminous blue Sprite. We then walked over to the Petronas Towers to see if we could book tickets for the Philharmonic Orchestra concert tonight. However, they had a strict dress code, and we hadn’t had the foresight to pack shirt, jacket and formal shoes for our backpacking trip. I waved my foot over the counter and the clerk said my shoes wouldn’t be allowed. We left the ticket counter with the idea of finding some cheap shoes, and on the way out we got some A&amp;W root beers.</p>
		<p>We caught the train to Chinatown, where Mike bought some more t-shirts. He had only brought five with him, but hadn’t counted on changing shirts twice a day due to the heat. We explored a very busy market, and were amused by how loudly all the shopkeepers were shouting. I tried on some shoes which turned out to be too small. In the end Sam didn’t have any appropriate clothes, so we couldn’t have gone anyway.</p>
		<p>It was only about a half hour walk back to the hotel, but we were a bit lost so we asked a local man for directions. He asked whether we intended to catch the bus or the train, and when we told him that we were planning to walk he blinked in surprise and said, “Walk?!”, as though we must be mad. Nevertheless, he gave us good directions, and wished us luck!</p>
		<p>I had a shower and then went out with Sam to get some lunch. We went back to the food court where I had previously had an unfortunate encounter with some rather hot chillies. This time I was more careful with my seasoning. We spent a while looking around the shopping centre, mainly so as to stay in the cool air. We had a nice look at laptops and handheld computers, and Sam was encouraging me to make a rash buy. I resisted though! However, when Mike joined us we ended up looking at Gameboy SPs. He had bought one before he left home, but hadn’t used it yet as he was worried we might laugh at him. He was relieved, and surprised when Sam and I bought one each.</p>
		<p>We had dinner in the basement food court. All three of us had ho fun with beef and ginger, which was pretty good. Mike added some chilli to his, and was soon crying. Lynette had an interesting evening watching the three of us play with our new toys!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="06-03-2004">
		<p>We were due to check out today, so after some breakfast across the road we settled our bill, which turned out to involve them actually giving us some money back! We found a very talkative and quite amusing cabby to drive us to the train station for our journey to Penang. Unfortunately, the first available train was at 8pm, so we caught a taxi to the Pudaraya bus station back in town. The station was extremely busy, but we managed to battle our way through the crowds to our bus. It was another comfortable bus, with loads of leg room.</p>
		<p>The trip took a little under five hours, but seemed to pass very quickly. We drove over the long bridge to Penang, and got off in Georgetown. When we arrived we phoned a hostel that we had chosen from the Lonely Planet and booked a room. We then had to wait quite a while for a taxi, who then wasn’t sure where the hostel was, so he dropped us off in Little India. It was only a short walk to the Coral Hostel, where we had a small room with one double bed and two mattresses crammed on the floor. It was air-conditioned though, and the owner was very friendly.</p>
		<p>The bus hadn’t stopped for lunch, so we were all really hungry by now. We walked over to an Indian restaurant that our hostel manager had recommended to us. The food was excellent, especially as I was so hungry. I had mutton biryani, and a masala dosai. The restaurant was empty except for an Indian family. One of the little girls was so interested in us that she actually fell off her chair; she was staring so intently!</p>
		<p>Lynette was feeling queasy again, so she stayed in the room while the rest of us went out for a quick drink. We found a little bar playing cheesy music, with graffiti covering every last inch of the walls.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="07-03-2004">
		<p>I got up early this morning and managed to wake everyone else by shining my head torch around the room. They all stayed in bed though. Mike complained that he had felt things crawling on him all through the night, but thought that it was probably an over active imagination after Lynette found some fleas in the room last night. I had smothered myself in DEET, and didn’t feel any uninvited nocturnal visitors.</p>
		<p>I got out just after sunrise, and the air was lovely and cool. I had picked up a suggested walking trail around Georgetown, called the American Express Heritage Trail, which took me down to the old fort on the shore front, and past some nice colonial buildings. As I was walking past St. George’s church I realised that I was just in time for the 8.30 service. The church was a bit worn down inside, and in need of some renovating. I didn’t know most of them hymns, but joined in heartily for ‘When the Saints go marching in’!</p>
		<p>The trail then led me down the main street, and I stopped to look at several temples and mosques. There weren’t many tourists about yet, and it was nice to see people opening their hawker shops and burning incense in the temples.</p>
		<p>I caught up with the others in the State Museum, after they had just finished a giant buffet breakfast in a local hotel. The museum was excellent and very well presented. My favourite exhibition was a display of some of the locals who had been hawking or mending shoes in the town since the 1920s. Apparently some of them are still peddling their wares on the streets.</p>
		<p>I had loh mee and a char siew pow in a coffee shop for my lunch, and then we walked over to the train station to make enquires about a train to Krabi in Thailand. They only had overnight trains which arrive very early in the morning, so we thought we would try a bus instead.</p>
		<p>Most things were closed today, it being a Sunday, but we found a place for coffee looking over the luxurious Eastern and Oriental Hotel. On the way back to the room we found a place to book a bus to Krabi, leaving at 8.30 in the morning. The main reason we were going to Krabi was for Lynette to do some rock climbing. However, when we got back to the hostel we found out that the climbing is actually on an island near Krabi, called Ko Phi Phi. The 8.30 bus would get us to Krabi too late for the last ferry of the day, so we changed our schedule to leave at 5am!</p>
		<p>We had an early dinner, back at the same Indian restaurant. We had the place to ourselves tonight. The food was good, but I had trouble eating my crab curry as they hadn’t removed it from its shell. I got myself pretty messy with the effort, and not too much crab to show for it. I had a very early night in anticipation of our planned early start.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="08-03-2004">
		<p>The first thing we heard this morning was Lynette crying, “It’s four thirty! Four thirty!” in a panicky voice. We were all ready to go by five o’clock, but the minibus was late so we eventually got under way at about half past five. At first we thought we were going to have the bus all to ourselves so we spread out, but after picking up some more passengers the bus was completely full. On group started a very loud conversation in Chinese, which was a bit of a shock to the system that early in the morning!</p>
		<p>We passed through immigration very smoothly and had a quick stop for breakfast at the border.  I slept for a lot of the trip until we had to change buses at Hat Yai. While we were waiting we had a cup of coffee and a friendly local tried to help us learn some Thai. The second bus was just as full and the air conditioning didn’t seem to be working very efficiently, so it was just as well that the sky was overcast and drizzling. I sat next to two Japanese travellers, one of whom started telling us all about his experience of getting a burst lung while in Poland.</p>
		<p>We waited a little while on arriving in Krabi for a minibus to take us over the road. It was so close we could have walked, but not knowing this we sat anxiously in a café waiting for this bus, watching the minutes tick down until our boat was scheduled to leave. We had to change bus onto the slowest bus in the whole world, which took us to the port. The boat left an hour late. Mike and I managed to sit below decks after navigating around the piles of luggage that had been crammed aboard. We got talking to two Australian girls called Katie and Angela; there was a woman behind us with a cat on a leash; and they were playing dodgy Chinese movies, dubbed in Thai, with Chinese subtitles.</p>
		<p>Koh Phi Phi (the pronunciation being a source of great amusement to Mike and myself) is comprised of two islands – Leh and Don. We’re staying on Phi Phi Don, and it’s a fantastic place – such a nice change from staying in cities. The island is small enough to walk around, yet is really bustling with life. There are lots of bars, restaurants and dive shops, and wherever you look there is something going on: from a football game on the beach to Thai kick boxing in a bar. We’re staying in a basic bungalow by the beach called the Andaman Resort.</p>
		<p>I booked a dive trip for tomorrow, then we walked to a bar on the other side of the island for a drink. We each had spaghetti for dinner, which was pretty good, and I had a long island ice tea while the others had Singapore Slings. It was very relaxing to be watching the sun set over the sea whilst sipping cocktails.</p>
		<p>I had arranged to meet Katie and Angela in the Apache bar tonight but we hadn’t realised that it was lady-boy night, so I was a little shocked when the girls told me the awful truth about all the attractive women who had walked in! Mike was very excited, as it was his mission to get a photo with a lady-boy, so he coerced me into being official photographer. We had a few drinks but left before the show started as I had to be up early for diving tomorrow.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="09-03-2004">
		<p>I managed to wake everyone up with my stumbling around in the dark this morning. The diving was great fun. We took a big boat over to Phi Phi Leh and had two dives, with some fish curry for lunch in between. We went in a group of five plus an instructor. The water was nice and warm, even wearing a shorty wet suit. The visibility wasn’t great, but there was a lot to see including scorpion fish, lion fish, puffer fish, a lobster, a sea snake, lots of coral and lots of other divers. The others in the group used up their air very quickly each time, which was good because it meant I got an extra twenty minutes with just the guide. We had lunch at Ao Maya which is where The Beach was filmed. I hadn’t seen the film though, so it didn’t mean much to me. I got back to the room just as the others were about to go out for lunch. We went to a Thai restaurant, and then I went back for a much-needed shower.</p>
		<p>In the evening we walked to the main part of town to find some dinner. We discovered a restaurant with a fresh fish display at the front. As we were looking at the menu, one of the large fish began to open and close its mouth. When a lady went to take a closed look the fish tried to attack her, virtually leaping off the display! The woman screamed, but we couldn’t stop laughing because we had seen the man making the fish move via a string attached to its head. On the basis of this display we decided to eat here, and took a table near the front so we could watch any passers by getting shocked. I had shrimp sashimi, and then a rather tough steak.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="10-03-2004">
		<p>Mike, Lynette and I went rock climbing this morning with a friendly instructor called Id and his very pregnant German wife. She stayed on the solid ground thankfully. It was very hot today as the sun had finally decided to make an appearance. We walked along the beach to the cliff, and after some instructions we proceeded to scale the rock surface. I found it pretty hard going and often felt like I couldn’t go any further, but I was pleased that I managed to make it all the way up. The views were tremendous, but I was so tired that I could hardly appreciate them! We were able to relax on the way down, as we were lowered on a rope. We each took turns and climbed three different sections of the cliff. I had to give up on the last one as I couldn’t get past an overhang, but Lynette and Mike were very good. However, Mike didn’t quite make it to the top of the last climb as he fell off and squished his testicles in the harness. Lynette burst out laughing when he had told us what happened, and soon everyone was looking up at him and laughing – poor Mike!</p>
		<p>We spent about three hours climbing, and by then were so hot and sticky that we jumped straight into the sea on getting back to the resort. Having cooled off we went into town for some lunch at a café. Mike and Lynette both had very hot curries.</p>
		<p>After lunch I decided to get a Thai massage, as I knew my muscles were going to be really sore after the climbing. It was a pretty relaxing massage, and not too painful, even when she twisted me round and cracked my spine! She used a hot oil that felt like Deep Heat. At one point she pinched my cheek and told me I had skin like a lady – hmm, I’m not sure quite how to take that! She was quite chatty, telling me all about her six sisters and two brothers, and even showing me a picture of her sister’s graduation.</p>
		<p>We went over the road to the Hippie Bar for dinner, and sat looking out over the shore. Our waiter said things like, “Cheers pal” and, “How’re you doing mate?” to practice his English slang! I had a nice Thai green curry.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="11-03-2004">
		<p>I had to be up quite early today for another dive. This time we took a speedboat out to a wreck which was about midway between Phi Phi and Phuket. The ride was quite fun, but when the engine stopped the swell made me feel quite sick.</p>
		<p>There were two groups diving, some of whom were doing an Advanced Open Water course. I was buddied with Scott, from Scotland. He was on his gap year and asked if I had just finished school as well. He looked quite surprised when I told him that was eight years ago!</p>
		<p>We had to swim over to the descent line, but there was quite a strong current so we had to fin pretty hard to get there. We didn’t have much time to rest as one of the instructors told us to go down and sort out our groups on the bottom. It was quite chaotic, with our whole group of divers bunched up and clutching on to the line while the current tried to sweep us off. I almost felt a bit panicky for a minute.</p>
		<p>The visibility was very poor and we had to make sure we didn’t touch the wreck as it was covered with poisonous Scorpion fish. It was quite an interesting wreck of a car ferry called the King Cruiser, which had sunk in 1997. It would have been nice with better visibility, less current, and not quite so much danger of being poisoned!</p>
		<p>We had lunch on the way to our second dive site, called Shark Point. Disappointingly, and I’m sure you can guess what I’m going to say, we didn’t see any sharks. There were a few moray eels, puffer fish and lion fish, so it turned out to be quite a pleasant dive.</p>
		<p>When I got back I found that the others had gone out, so I had a shower then got some beef fried rice in town. They had spent the day island hopping on a water taxi, snorkelling and sunbathing. Unfortunately they all got a bit toasted in the sun, but nothing too serious though.</p>
		<p>I waited in the room for a phone call from Northampton hospital, as I was having a telephone interview for an A&amp;E job. I ended up getting a bit nervous while I was waiting, but it was nowhere near as bad as sitting in a room with other candidates. I think having the interview on my bed in my shorts helped me to come across as relaxed. At the end they told me they would let me know in three hours. I spent the time walking into town to meet the others, had a cold drink, and found a nice baby to play with. It was very cute, and started crying whenever I tried to walk away. The mother found me in a nearby shop and gave him to me to hold! I don’t think it was particularly impressed with how sweaty I was though!</p>
		<p>We went back to the Hippie Bar for dinner and found our friendly waiter there. I asked him to recommend something to eat and ended up with an exceptionally fiery curry. I was excused from finishing it though, as I received my call from Northampton offering me the job. What a relief! I was too excited to eat anymore, so the guys bought me cocktails to celebrate. They didn’t care which cocktails, so long as they were maximally alcoholic. I walked into town in a drunken state, and e-mailed the hospital to accept the job (I think).</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="12-03-2004">
		<p>My poor stomach wasn’t very happy this morning, but a little metoclopramide soon sorted me out. We checked out of the room and loaded our bags onto a trolley which someone pushed to the dock for us. Whenever anyone was in the way he would shout, “Beep beep!” in a manner reminiscent of Road Runner. This seemed to be the general cry of trolley handlers and cyclists, and when leaping out of the way you had to be careful not to step on a cat as there were almost as many felines as humans on the island. One of the nice things about Phi Phi is that there are no cars. The only motorised vehicles are the water taxis.</p>
		<p>We caught the 9am ferry to Phuket. There were no movies screened this time, but the crossing was smooth and fast. On arrival in Phuket we were approached by the usual gaggle of taxi drivers. We had checked the Lonely Planet on the way over and decided that Karon beach looked quite nice, so we asked a driver to take us there. He had an old, beaten up car with no seatbelts, and it took him a good while pumping the clutch to get it started!</p>
		<p>After a rather hair raising journey involving overtaking around blind corners and playing chicken with oncoming cars while driving on the wrong side of the road, we somehow managed to arrive at our destination in one piece. We stopped at a hotel called the Golden Sands, but found that it was a bit too expensive at 2,500 Baht per room. The receptionist was adamant that she couldn’t give us a discount, but once we left she ran after us and offered 2,000 Baht instead. This was reasonable, so we decided to stay and were relieved that we wouldn’t have to get in the taxi again.</p>
		<p>I shared a room with Mike, and the girls had another. They were very pleased to be sleeping in separate beds again. The rooms were air-conditioned with ensuite bathrooms, but were mosquito infested. Somehow I escaped with only one bite during our stay, and in exchange we must have squashed thirty mosquitoes, so we felt it was one up for us.</p>
		<p>We had a late lunch in the hotel restaurant and then walked over the road to watch the sun set over the sea – it was a very late lunch! The beach was quite quiet as it was rather cloudy, but owing to the vast number of deck chairs along the shore front you could imagine that it often got very busy.</p>
		<p>While we were swimming in the hotel pool I cut my foot on the pool ladder. I left a trail of blood all the way back to our room! After a quick field dressing we went out for dinner at an Italian restaurant. I had some garlic with clams then spaghetti al tonno, which was pretty tasty.</p>
		<p>Afterwards the girls went back to their room while Mike and I walked along the main street. There were lots of irritating salesmen outside the tailor shops, who would try and look friendly and shake your hand. I shook hands once, but learnt not to do it again when he wouldn’t let go and almost dragged me into his shop. It feels quite rude just ignoring them though.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="13-03-2004">
		<p>Lynette came bounding into our room this morning, claiming that she and Sam had already been for a jog and had a swim. Needless to say, we didn’t believe a word of it! We broke our fast at ten o’clock with a gigantic American breakfast for the girls and Mike, and a pork congee for me. Afterwards I booked myself in for an afternoon tour. The girls were planning a lazy day by the pool, and Mike wanted to go to Phuket town to organise a bus to Bangkok.</p>
		<p>I got on the tour bus at Karon beach, but it was another half an hour before we finished picking up passengers at Patong. I sat next to an American gentleman who observed that I looked a bit of a Dougie Howser when he discovered my profession. Our guide was a Thai lady called Jerd who taught us to say, “sawat-dii” and “khawp khun khrap”, which respectively mean ‘hello’ and ‘thank you’. The selling point of the trip was a visit to James Bond island in Phang-Nga, and so they showed us ‘The Man with the Golden Gun’ during the coach trip.</p>
		<p>Our first stop was at the Monkey Cave Temple. There was a golden reclining Buddha (made of concrete) and various other statues and shrines inside the cave. There was also a monk who was blessing people and handing out lucky pieces of string. Try as I might, I couldn’t see any monkeys inside the cave. However once I stepped back outside I saw monkeys just about everywhere. They were very tame, and people were feeding them bananas.</p>
		<p>The next stop was at the port in Phang-Nga where we all bundled aboard a longboat. A lady came by and took pictures of us, so I took a picture of her taking a picture of me for good measure. The boat ride was fun, and I only got splashed a couple of times. We stopped off at a Muslim fishing village and had a walk around visiting the mosque and the local school, but the rest of the village seemed to be devoted to either fishing or tourism. Lots of the houses were raised above the water on stilts. I had a photo shoot of me holding two baby gibbons, one of which was called Harry. They didn’t do very much, although I’m not sure what I was expecting.</p>
		<p>Once we had finished looking around the village we got back on board the longboat for the ride over to James Bond island. As we were leaving I noticed lots of expensive-looking seafood restaurants along the waterfront. Obviously the village must get lots of diners travelling over in the evenings. As we pulled up to the beach of James Bond island it started torrentially pouring with rain. Fortunately there were quite a few caves and overhangs to shelter in. No sign of Scaramanger’s secret lair though. There was a very impressive limestone formation thrusting from the water, from which the deadly solar energy collector emerged in the film.</p>
		<p>I got absolutely drenched on the trip back from the combination of rain and sea spray, so much so that I had to wring out my shirt. Luckily the rain died down as we arrived back in Phang-Nga. We were offered a souvenir (at 100 Baht) of a small plate with our picture in the middle. It was quite a good photo if I do say so myself, so I bought it; I’m not entirely sure it will make it back to England without mishap.</p>
		<p>The air-conditioned coach was very cold with wet clothes. We watched the end of the Bond film, and I was dropped off near the hotel at just gone seven o’clock. After a lovely hot shower we ventured out for dinner. I had wanted to try some seafood as Phuket is near the sea, so I had a small but tasty lobster thermidor. We went back to the girls’ room and watched the end of ‘Carlito’s Way’ in the TV.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="14-03-2004">
		<p>We had to check out today, but our bus to Bangkok wasn’t until 4pm, so we extended our checkout time to 2pm for the girls’ room and moved all our luggage in there. The girls had eaten an early breakfast, so Mike and I went back to the same restaurant as yesterday where I had a shrimp congee this time. Of course the girls got hungry again before us, so they had lunch in the hotel restaurant. We then caught a taxi to the bus station in Phuket town. At least this time we were in a new car and felt slightly safer with some seatbelts. Mike and I had lunch in a hawker centre near the bus station. The menu was all in Thai, so we asked for some pork curry. It was very nice having a more home cooked taste, but it wasn’t filling enough so we then ordered some noodles. The cook seemed very amused then I asked to take a picture of her frying something.</p>
		<p>The bus trip took twelve and a half hours, and at first was reasonably comfortable with plenty of leg room. I occupied myself by playing Pokemon on my Gameboy. We stopped at a service station at about ten o’clock where I got an omelette for dinner. Again the menu was all in Thai, but this time the staff didn’t speak any English so I had no idea what I was going to get until it was set in front of me.</p>
		<p>When the bus driver turned off the internal lights the man in front of Sam put his seat right back so that she was completely pinned in place. She had been suffering with oedematous ankles since a severe sunburn in Fiji, and not being able to move her legs made it very painful. I managed to stop the man in front of me from doing the same by jamming my knees up against the back of the seat. However, when I thought he had given up trying and gone to sleep I took an opportunity to shift position, and the next thing I knew his seat was right back as well. I couldn’t believe how inconsiderate these two guys were, but I did manage to get a few hours sleep though.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="15-03-2004">
		<p>The bus pulled into Bangkok bus station at half past four this morning, and so we emerged very bleary eyed. I don’t think the others got much sleep at all. Another American backpacker tried to get us to share a taxi with him to the main backpacker part of town, but Mike thought the hostels there would be a bit of a dump so we phoned a hotel instead called the Sarthorn Inn in Silom. We got a taxi to take us there, and Sam and Lynette were so tired that they paid a supplement to check in early so that they could get some sleep. Mike and I were too stingy for that, so we left our bags in the girls’ room and headed out for a walk.</p>
		<p>It was still dark, with very little traffic, and shopkeepers were beginning to set up their stalls for the day. It was my favourite time to go sightseeing. We walked past people selling freshly cooked noodles and fried sweet breads, and found ourselves standing at the foot of King Rama VI who was looking comical in a safari hat. His statue was at the entrance to Lumpini park, so we decided to have a look in. It was six in the morning and already the park was milling with people. Some younger people were doing aerobics to dance music, while tai chi seemed to be a favourite amongst the older generation. As we walked around we noticed lots of joggers circling in the opposite direction. There was a choir rehearsal taking place between little old ladies limbering up and other people meditating. There was even a couple taking a pedalo across the lake. I stopped to take lots of photos, but at one point I realised that I was being eaten alive by a load of ants that had climbed into my shoe. To the casual observer I must have seemed to be performing some very strange callisthenics as I hopped on one leg while swatting vigorously at my other ankle.</p>
		<p>We had a very pleasant walk around the perimeter of the park, and then stopped for some hawker food. I must admit that roast pork with rice is a little unusual for breakfast, but the crackling was superb!</p>
		<p>After breakfast we had a look at the map and decided that Chinatown seemed quite close. We set off, little realising that by the end of the morning we would five walked about five miles! At least it wasn’t too hot at this time of the day. We stopped to look at a Buddhist temple along the way, and eventually made it to Chinatown. By now the streets were really bustling with vendors and we had to watch out for wild tuk-tuks and motorbikes when crossing the road. We found ourselves in one part of Chinatown where all the shops sold coffins, which we thought was a bit disconcerting.</p>
		<p>As we had already walked so far we decided to press on and see Watphra Kaeo – the Grand Palace – which contains the Emerald Buddha. However as we were about to enter, a man informed us that all the temples were closed to non-Thai people until 1pm, as the monks pray on Monday mornings. He suggested that we see the lucky Buddha, as it was not in a temple, and he hailed a tuk-tuk for us. The tuk-tuks seem smaller than I remember, but then as I was only ten when I was last here I am now a considerable amount bigger! In fact I could hardly see where we were going as the roof was so low.</p>
		<p>We stopped at the lucky Buddha and our driver waited for us. As we were approaching it one of the locals came and introduced himself. He was a history teacher who had studied in India, and seemed to be very friendly. He suggested going to one of the silk tailor shops, and as Mike thought there would be a tour showing how the suits are made he asked out driver to take us there. However, it was just a shop, so it was quite embarrassing when neither of us wanted a suit. I did buy a silk tie for about ￡7 though, which I thought was reasonably good value.</p>
		<p>Once we had left we asked our driver to take us back to the hotel. He said he would charge is only 20 Baht if we would visit a jewellery shop first, as then he would get a free petrol coupon. This sounded like a good deal so we agreed. The jewellery shop was pretty boring, and they didn’t apply any pressure to buy anything. Mike pretended that he was interested in buying some jewellery though, and so both strung along the visit and the salesman. We left empty handed, but our driver got his coupon. However he did not take us back to the hotel but dropped us off at the sky train station. When we queried this he suddenly couldn’t speak any English, but 20 Baht was really cheap for the trip anyway.</p>
		<p>We caught the sky train back to the hotel and found that the girls were up and about. I went to get the room for Mike and myself, but while I was at reception the girls came down for breakfast, locking their bags and the room key in their room with Mike in the shower. I would have to wait for Mike to open the door before I could get a shower so I joined the girls for some food in the hotel café. I had minced pork and tofu soup.</p>
		<p>By the time we had eaten we were able to get back into the room. Mike and Lynette had been going out for a while, so they asked if they could share that room. Sam moved into the other room with me. I sent some laundry down and was very surprised to get it back in a couple of hours when I was expecting it to take a whole day. However when I had taken my clothes down the laundry lady was sitting around twiddling her thumbs, so I expect she had nothing else to do.</p>
		<p>Sam was tired and tried to sleep while I wrote my diary, but she kept exchanging text messages with her boyfriend Colin. It turns out that Colin will be flying into Bangkok tomorrow morning and joining us for a few days. The good news is that I’ll be getting the room to myself tomorrow.</p>
		<p>We went to the Madras Café for dinner, which was close to the hotel but down the end of a long dark alley. The food was good and cheap though.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="16-03-2004">
		<p>Sam went to the airport to pick up Colin, so Mike, Lynette and I had the day to ourselves. Little did we realise that this was likely to become a regular occurrence, but more on that later. We had breakfast at McDonald's and then rode the sky train to the city centre. Apparently the sky train is only about five years old, and has eased Bangkok’s traffic congestion by 40%. Looking at the grid locked traffic during the day, it’s hard to imagine it could have been much worse.</p>
		<p>We hailed a tuk-tuk to take us to the Grand Palace. The ride was scarier today, and what with Lynette’s repeated shouts of, “We’re all going to die!” I was glad that I couldn’t really see where we were going.</p>
		<p>It was a blazing hot day, and the palace looked magnificent with its gleaming spires. We hired a guide to show us around, and he turned out to be very good. His name was Tong, and he gave us a lot of information although at times he did drone on a bit. We saw the temple of the Emerald Buddha (which is actually made of Jade), and watched some women renovating the gold leaves and glass decorations on the walls. Tong told us that according to Buddha there are four types of person: the first is like a lotus flower in the mud, who have closed their minds and can not learn; the second is the lotus in the water, with slightly open minds who can see new ideas floating above the water; the third is the lotus between the water (I couldn’t quite imagine where this flower was supposed to be!); and the fourth is the person with the open mind, or the lotus above the water. Of course, he said that we were all above the water!</p>
		<p>I had to borrow some long trousers to walk around the temple, which was annoying as it was already so hot. We did manage to stay in the shade for most of the time though. After the tour we found a café over the road for some lunch. I had some minced pork green curry and a very refreshing chocolate milkshake with ice cream. We were walking along the outside walls of the palace heading for another temple when two locals started talking to us. They ended up hailing a tuk-tuk for us and organising a short tour, including a stop at a tailors! We went to see a temple which contained a lucky Buddha, and again got talking to one of the locals who was there to pray. He wanted to show us how to pray to Buddha, so the three of us were on our knees kow-towing to the Buddha! Mike said that he didn’t pray for anything, but Lynette had asked for a safe tuk-tuk ride home!</p>
		<p>The next stop was the tailor shop. I actually needed a new winter coat, so I ended up getting measured and will go to try it on in a couple of weeks. Mike and Lynette were quite amused that I had bought something. Afterwards our driver took us to see a reclining Buddha in another temple. I was a bit lost and so have no idea what the temples where called. Every time we go into a temple it seems that someone wants to chat to us. This time it was a government official who wanted to warn us of potential pitfalls for tourists. I have never heard anyone talk for so long without being able to get a word in!</p>
		<p>Our final stop was at Wat Pho, which was a very attractive temple made even nicer by the light of the late afternoon sun. As we entered the main temple building we heard chanting, and then saw all the monks praying. There were a couple of Westerners praying as well. However, one of the officials said that it was fine for us to look around. The monks left after a few minutes, so I went in to look at the giant five tonne gold Buddha. We then had a pleasant walk around the temple grounds, and saw the monks riding tuk-tuks and watering their gardens.</p>
		<p>Once we left the temple we found that our tuk-tuk driver had left. However, there were a couple more outside waiting for business. We got one of them to take us to the sky train station, but he insisted on visiting another tailor shop first. I had no intention of buying anything, but I soon found myself being measured up for a suit. With a bit of haggling I think I got a good deal, so now I’ve got some more clothes to try when we get back here. Mike and Lynette couldn’t stop themselves laughing when they realised that I’d made another impulse buy. Together with buying our flight tickets to Delhi, today has put a bit of a strain on my credit card!</p>
		<p>We had dinner in a shopping centre by the train station. I had some Japanese ramen with clams, but I’ve found that a lot of Thai curries have an overpowering taste of aniseed of which I’m not particularly fond. Mike and Lynette went to McDonald's.</p>
		<p>Back at the hotel I was checking my e-mails when Sam and Colin got back. We all met in their room for a quick, ‘nice to meet you’ chat before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="17-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="18-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="19-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="20-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="21-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="22-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="23-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="24-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="25-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="28-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="29-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="30-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="31-03-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="01-04-2004">
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
		<p></p>
	</entry>
</diary>
