<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Courchevel" date="01-2013">
	<entry date="20-01-2013">
		<p>We had a really early start today. Dad very kindly took us to Gatwick at 4am. There had been a lot of snow in London over the past few days, so we were a bit concerned that it might have been difficult to get to the airport, or that there might have been delays, but fortunately everything was fine. After checking in, Simon had a couple of pain au chocolat while I had something from McDonald's for breakfast. I think the staff hadn't quite woken up yet, as it took about fifteen minutes to get through the four people in my queue.</p>
		<p>We travelled with Monarch Airlines this time. When we got on the plane I was impressed with the amount of leg room between the seats. Unfortunately, as we walked further back to our seats the rows got dramatically more closely packed. It wasn't too bad for a short flight though. We took off about half an hour late, as all the planes had to be de-iced first. We landed in Grenoble at about 9.30, where we had to wait ages to pass through immigration. We thought that maybe the officials were on strike!</p>
		<p>After getting our bags we were met by the Mark Warner rep, who directed us to our coach. The trip to Courcheval took about two and a half hours. Simon tried to snooze most of the way, while I enjoyed watching the countryside go by. When we got to Meribel we had to change to minibuses for the final leg to Coucheval. In a way we were quite relieved to get off the coach though, as we had been sitting next to a woman with a hacking cough, and two men who wittered the whole way! The minibus dropped us off right at the front door of the Hotel Dahu.</p>
		<p>We got up to our room and stopped just long enough for Simon to unpack his ski socks, then ont of the reps walked us over to the ski hire shop. It was the same shop that we'd used several times before, next to the Isba chalet. It was sad to see the Isba desolate, with all its windows boarded up. The owner of the ski shop said that it had been empty for two years now. It was the place I stayed at the first time I ever went skiing. Happy memories.</p>
		<p>Simon went downstairs to get kitted out with boots and skis, while I asked the owner to adjust my bindings for my new boots. I had bought a pair from Snow and Rock in Croydon just before coming, as I'd finally had enough of my extremely tight, painful and expensive custom molded boots. The hire shop guy said that it looked like I needed a new pair of blades too. To be fair, I hadn't had any maintenance on them for five years, and they looked pretty scratched up. I asked the shop to refurbish them, which cost 40 Euros, and they said that they'd drop them round at the hotel in the morning.</p>
		<p>We hadn't had anything to eat since breakfast, so were both looked forward to afternoon tea at 3.30. We had a quick walk down to the Spar to see if we could get a sandwich, but it was closed for lunch and didn't open again until 3.30, so I had a chocolate bar instead. Afternoon tea was really good. We had ham and cheese sandwiches, soup, some lovely flapjacks, and a slice of chocolate cake. That certainly filled a hole!</p>
		<p>After tea we thought we'd have a snooze for a couple of hours, so we went back up to our room. However, Simon was horrified to find, while climbing into this bed, what looked like blood stains on his sheet. I looked like the sheet had been washed, but not enough to remove the stains. We let reception know, and a lady from housekeeping came up right away to change the sheets. The first sheet she tried also had a stain on it, so she went away for another. This was also stained, so she went to fetch yet another. This one was ripped, so off she went again. In the end, it was sixth time lucky! We also asked her to change the duvet cover. After she'd left, we noticed a small stain on it. We didn't have the heart to call her back again.</p>
		<p>We slept for an hour and a half, then went down to the lounge for some welcome drinks. We had a glass of bucks fizz and a few canapés. The hotel staff introduced themselves. All the staff were Mark Warner employees. When the head of housekeeping introduced herself she was looking a bit stressed. Straight after this we went in for dinner. The restaurant manager seated each guest individually. As we were one of the first we sat down immediately, but we could tell a bit of a queue was forming later on. The food was very good. We had smoked salmon tartare to start, then there was a buffet with beef en croute, three types of fish, and roast vegetables. I had ice cream for dessert. We also had a bottle of wine, which was included. We were really tired after a long day, so just watched a bit of television after dinner, then went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="21-01-2013">
		<p>Our first day on the slopes! The hotel is in a good position. Not quite ski-in, ski-out, but only about 100 m walk to the lifts at Le Croisette. It was pretty cloudy in the morning, so we decided to stay around the Courcheval valley today. This turned out to be a good idea, as it snowed rather heavily in the afternoon, so the conditions weren't great. Quite a few of the pistes hadn't been bashed either.</p>
		<p>We skied around most of the valley, and stopped for lunch in La Tania, where we shared a pepperoni pizza with lots of garlic. My new boots behaved well on their first outing. My feet were warm and comfortable all day. In the afternoon I was skiing down a connecting piste, and I noticed two very small children seemingly skiing on their own. They were part of a group, but the French instructor had gone on in front of them. I was just thinking that the little girl looked a bit unsteady, when the little boy skied right over the edge of the piste. It was quite a steep drop off the side, and he tumbled over a couple of times. I stopped and climbed down to help. He was pretty shaken up and didn't speak English, but seemed very grateful.</p>
		<p>By the end of the day my legs were really aching, so I decided to have a sports massage back at the hotel. They didn't feel a whole lot better afterwards, but I'm sure that it helped a bit. As I was climbing into the bath for a shower I slipped and bashed my knee on the floor, getting a nasty bruise. Luckily is wasn't too bad, so it didn't affect my skiing.</p>
		<p>The afternoon tea was good again. It's nice to have a good feed to look forward to while out on the mountain! We had duck for dinner, but abstained from the wine, as I'd kept Simon up with my snoring last night. We had a nice long talk after dinner, mainly about my job and my hopes of getting into management. We got to bed at about eleven o'clock.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="22-01-2013">
		<p>We had beautiful weather today. Plenty of sun and not a cloud in the sky. The snow was good, but there are definitely more moguls than usual. We started to wonder whether the bashers had gone on holiday. Maybe they can't afford to employ as many during the recession. We got out in good time today, and made our way over to Val Thorens.</p>
		<p>We planned to have lunch at our normal takeaway place in Val Thorens, but got separated on the way in. Luckily we both had our phones with us, so managed to meet up again. Taking the phone has been good. They've got good enough now to act as a proper camera and video recorder, so I left my compact camera at home.</p>
		<p>I had an expensive, undercooked burger for lunch. We weren't impressed. The place has put up its prices by almost 100%. I only ate around the edges of the burger, as it looked almost raw in the middle. My legs were still quite sore today, but I made it through until about 3pm when we headed back. We had afternoon tea, then watched Pointless on TV in our room. I had chicken for dinner, but should have had the chargrilled swordfish instead, which came with six inch tiger prawns! We played some board games in the lounge for a couple of hours before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="23-01-2013">
		<p>It was cloudy again today, but didn't snow. We spent most of the day skiing around the Meribel valley. On the way we passed the top of the Grand Couloir piste. We have a running joke that Simon always wants to try it, but I won't let him because I think it's too dangerous. This year they had erected a board warning you to try it only if you are a very good skier, and that the gradient gets to 80%. That's almost a sheer drop. Simon doesn't want to do it anymore!</p>
		<p>We had been thinking about staying in La Tania next time, but we chatted to a couple of people in a cable car who reminded us that there are no easy runs back there. As we're hoping to go with Adam and Somayeh next year, that's something to think about. I had a croque monsieur for lunch. I had quite fancied a cheese burger, but am a bit scared of eating meat from these piste-side takeaway places now.</p>
		<p>My legs were feeling a bit better today. The boots are still good. A little loose, but comfortable. I'm finding the blades quite hard work on compact snow. They've hardly got any grip, and I end up sliding around a lot. Maybe I'll go back to proper skis next time.</p>
		<p>After tea we watched Pointless again. The TV reception is really terrible, but we can just about make out the picture. I had a tuna steak for dinner, then we played Trivial Pursuit in the lounge. E thought it was quite easy, until we realised that we were using the baby cards!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="24-01-2013">
		<p>I put the news on while we were getting ready this morning. I thought I'd see if I could improve the reception, so I spent a while wiggling the aerial connection into the TV, until I realised that the other end of the aerial wasn't actually plugged in! The picture was much improved afterwards.</p>
		<p>The forecast was for cloud and snow today, but it actually turned out lovely. We had gorgeous sunshine the whole day. We stayed in the Coucheval valley, and had pizza in La Tania for lunch again. I was looking forward to a waffle for pudding, but they had run out.</p>
		<p>The pistes were better bashed today. Simon is enjoying practicing on moguls, so he often skied just of the side of the piste where the snow hadn't been groomed. He had a very small tumble while doing this, but we decided that it didn't really count as a fall! Towards the end of the day his back started hurting, which he thought was due to going over lots of little bumps.</p>
		<p>It was the chalet staff day off, so we went out for a fondue at La Fromagrie restaurant. We decided to go for a cheese fondue, after I had bad diarrhoea and vomiting following a meat fondue last year. It was very tasty, and included a salad, potatoes and cold meats. The restaurant had a nice atmosphere. I had Ouefs A La Neige for pudding, which sounded intriguing. It turned out to be a big lump of whisked egg whites in a crème Anglaise sauce.</p>
		<p>When we got back to our room Simon's stomach started to churn, then he had to rush to the toilet with diarrhoea. Five minutes later the same happened to me. We don't seem to be very lucky with fondues!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="25-01-2013">
		<p>Unfortunately Simon really didn't feel very well today. His stomach was bloated and he felt sick, so we had a day off from skiing. I still didn't feel quite right, but was pretty much ok. We spent most of the day in our room. Simon slept a lot, while I played Bad Piggies on my phone for hours. We didn't have any lunch. In the afternoon I brought the Trivial Pursuit set up from the lounge, and we had a game in our room. Despite feeling poorly Simon still won!</p>
		<p>I had some afternoon tea. Simon must have been feeling awful, as he said the sight of cake was turning his stomach. I thought nothing could put him off a pudding! We had a gentle walk around 1850 to get some fresh air, and enjoyed looking in the estate agent windows.</p>
		<p>I had a delicious started or crispy duck and watercress with a wasabi soy and roast peanut dressing, and then some lamb for dinner. Simon tried a little soup, but then felt ill and went back to the room. Our waiter Andy was happy that we cancelled Simon's main course, as the chef let him have it. When I got back to the room I found out that Simon hadn't quite made it to the toilet before being sick, so there was a bit of a mess. Someone from housekeeping came and cleaned it up very quickly for us. We had an early night.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-01-2013">
		<p>Simon was feeling much better, so we spent an easy day skiing around Courcheval, mainly sticking to green and blue runs. It was beautiful and sunny, and the pistes were pretty good. We found it a bit tricky when skiing from a sunny area into the shade, as it suddenly became hard to make out any details of the piste.</p>
		<p>While we were talking about where to go next on a chairlift, the guys next to us suggested the red piste called 'Mur', which they said was really steep. Once they had said we should only try it if we were good skiers, well we had to go for it after that! It was quite steep, and halfway down I saw Simon standing off the side of the piste covered in snow, his skis lying about six feet away. He'd managed to fall while crossing into a shady bit, and had slid right off the piste, ending up next to some trees. Luckily he was alright. Just shaken up with some bruises and grazes. We took it quite easy for the rest of the day.</p>
		<p>We shared a pizza for lunch at Marmottons restaurant back in La Tania. We actually thought it was better than Snow Food, and easier to get a seat. I got a bit nervous in the afternoon, as I hadn't fallen at all during the week, unlike every other skiing holiday. The more I thought about having a whole week without falling, the more unsteady I seemed to get! I did manage to stay upright until we got back though. After tea we packed out bags, had dinner, then an early night.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-01-2013">
		<p>We were up at 4.40 this morning, and had a quick breakfast before out coach left at 5.30. Simon managed to snooze on the coach, while I listened to some music. The coach driver took a wrong turn, and we got to Grenoble airport about an hour later than expected. We were getting a bit nervous about whether we'd be in time for our flight, but it turned out quite well. After checking in, we went straight through to the gate and boarded the plane. We left five minutes early.</p>
		<p>Simon's dad picked us up from Gatwick. We had a really lovely skiing holiday, and are now looking forward to a great beach holiday in St. Lucia in a couple of months!</p>
	</entry>
</diary>