<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Elective" date="03-2002">
	<entry date="25-03-2002">
		<p>After quite a busy day packing and buying last minute essentials, Mum, Dad and Steven came with me to Heathrow where we met up with Martin. We went to Arbuckles for dinner, and I had a rather large burger, which combined with my anti-malarials made me feel a little queasy. Never mind, it was a tasty burger! After saying goodbye, we hung around in duty free for a while, and bought some tea from Harrods for Aunty Nancy.</p>
		<p>It was a very full flight, so we were lucky to get two seats next to each other, let alone in a row with extra leg room. However, this time we chickened out of asking for the upgrade - maybe next flight. The trip was long (13 hours) and because we took off in the evening we spent almost the whole trip in darkness. I watched a couple of films - the Royal Tenenbaums and Bandits with Bruce Willis, but the rest of the time I tried to doze.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-03-2002">
		<p>We arrived in Singapore at 18:45, and after picking up our baggage we were met by Aunty Nancy. We heard an announcement for Chia Yeo to go to the lost baggage desk, but later found out that it was a different Chia. We met our taxi driver for the next few days, called Rodney, who drove us to Aunty Nancy's club, the Pine Tree. We were real pigs, of course, and ate Singapore laksa, hokkien mee, chicken rice, satay, chendol, and ice kachang! After this enormous meal we went back to Aunty Nelli's apartment and went for a very brief swim in her pool - the attendant turned out the lights after we'd been in about ten minutes! We were very tired, so we went straight to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-03-2002">
		<p>We got up at around 10 o'clock, and had been planning to go for a swim, but it was quite cloudy and not too warm (surprisingly). Instead, we just took a little longer to get ready, and met Rodney who took us to the Malaysian tourism board. We wanted to ask some questions about diving near Kuching, but the desk clerk just directed us to some leaflets. Looks like we'll have to see what's on offer when we arrive. We met Aunty Nancy, and went to People's Park shopping centre where Martin looked at some gold necklaces for Lis. We then went to the nearby hawker centre for lunch. We ate some very nice fried dumplings, Bakwa, some noodles with small fried fish, some soup with taufu and fishballs, and Martin had a coconut, while I had a glass of sugar cane drink.</p>
		<p>After lunch we went gadget shopping. I bought my new laptop from the Sim Lim centre - quite a bargain (I haven't found the catch yet!), and I got a new memory card for my camera from Holland Road. Then came Martin's test - durian eating! We were taken to a local stall and unfortunately I didn't get a picture of Martin's face as he chewed his first bite - it was an expression of disbelief! Even though he couldn't believe how bad it tasted (he likened it to chicken fat!), he still managed to eat about three bits. The worst bit was when we had both finished the open part and felt like that was definitely enough, and the owner came over and split open another chamber. I could just tell that he was going to do that! We had to eat that part not to be rude, but when he came back over again we politely declined any more!</p>
		<p>Rodney then dropped us off in Orchard Road for us to wander around. Martin shopped for a pair of swimming shorts and a towel but apart from that we just wandered around from shop to air-conditioned shop, and ended up having some won-ton soup in Scott's plaza.</p>
		<p>After dinner Rodney took us to the night safari. It was very entertaining. We took a tram ride around the safari, with a funny commentator, and all of the animals were out and visible. Only one of them looked drugged, and an owl looked like it was stuck down to its perch. One of the best bits was walking through the mangrove cage, where big fruit bats were flying around freely. Martin remarked that they looked like big guinea-pigs with rubber wings strapped on. Martin wouldn't survive very long in the jungle, as he couldn't really see the animals until we were almost upon them! However, we both had a really good time, and Aunty Nelli picked us up and took us back to her apartment. We were very tired and sat in front of the TV watching the Oscars for a while before we went to bed, still with the taste of durians in our mouths!</p>
		</entry>
	<entry date="28-03-2002">
		<p>A very early start!</p>
		<p>Rodney picked us up at 8.15 and took us to a local hawker centre for Roti Paratha breakfast. It was lovely. We had one egg paratha and two plain, with mutton curry and fish curry - delicious and quite filling. With our stomachs full of juicy curry we went to Jurong Bird Park. We were just in time to see the Hawk show which was excellent. A wild hawk joined in and got a bit to eat. It was very sunny today, and we strolled round the park, visiting the aviary where they had recreated a tropical rainforest environment complete with rainforest mist. There was a very tall waterfall - apparently the largest man made waterfall in the world. We also saw a peacock walking around right in front of us with its feathers all spread out. We got to the All Star Bird Show just as a parrot and a macaw were having a race to see which could put the most balls through mini basketball hoops, then there was a parrot who wouldn't fly through some hoops, and another one that refused to count in English, but would in Chinese, but wouldn't sing in Chinese, only in English - very strange!</p>
		<p>We met Aunty Nancy for lunch at a Thai restaurant in Centre Point. We had beef Rendang and some Chinese vegetables which were very nice. We also had fried whole baby squid which had caramelised and become very sweet, which wasn't so nice! We had some more chendol for dessert. Afterwards Martin bought some sun cream, which seemed a very sensible idea considering the heat, then we went off to the World Trade Centre to catch a cable car to Sentosa.</p>
		<p>The cable car was a little scary, and very surreal. There were some great views, but at one point it just stopped, and we didn't know if this was on purpose, or if it had broken. However, to keep us calm they piped some music over the internal speakers - a mixture of big band classics, and the ET theme tune with a definite Mexican bent to it! We were glad to touch down in Sentosa!</p>
		<p>The first thing we wanted to do was to visit Underwater World, so we did. We noticed a leaflet about diving with the sharks in one of the tanks, but unfortunately all the spaces were fully booked for the rest of the day. We still enjoyed travelling round the underwater tunnel, and stroking some dogfish and rays in the touch pool. After we stepped back out into the sun, we decided it was time to go swimming, so we wandered over to Silosa beach where there was a cordoned off lagoon. The beach was very busy, with lots of people playing volleyball, but the lagoon was virtually empty. The water was very nice and warm with some gentle waves, and we were very surprised at how shallow it was. All the way out to the mouth of the lagoon you could put your feet down and feel the slimy seaweed beneath you. We spent an hour or so swimming and sitting on the beach, and I managed to take a few photos, and to half bury Martin in the sand.</p>
		<p>Once we'd rinsed off we walked over to the food court, passing Volcanoland on the way, which I wouldn't let Martin waste his money on. Volcanoland indeed! We shared a plate of Char Kwae Teow and I had an Ice Kachang which was very refreshing. We then debated about whether to go or to wait an hour for the next show at the musical fountain. I'm really glad we waited, because the show was great! They've really upgraded it from last time, with fantastic laser effects and an interesting story. At the end the Merlion in the distance roared and shot huge green lasers out of its eyes to defeat the naughty dragon! Very impressive.</p>
		<p>We walked back to the cable car station, but I suppose if we knew what was in store for us, we may have decided to catch the monorail there instead. Once we got back to Singapore we found an enormous queue at the taxi rank. I said to Martin that we must be able to find a taxi quicker if we go walking - an hour (and many miles!) later we finally managed to hail an empty cab. By this time we thought better of going to East Coast Park for dinner, as we'd probably take another hour to find a taxi afterwards, so we asked the driver to take us back to Aunty Nelli's apartment. We made a decision to have a late start and a swim tomorrow, followed by a lazy day walking around Orchard Road, so I stayed up quite late to play with my new laptop and write my diary.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="29-03-2002">
		<p>Despite our good intentions, we ended up sleeping to past mid-day, and didn't get our morning swim. We made up for this by having a nice lunch at a hawker centre with Aunty Nelli. We tried local chicken rice, some fish paste wrapped in banana leaves, and oluak - mmm! After this nice start, we caught the MRT to Orchard Road. We walked up and down looking for HMV, and when we finally found it the centre it was in was packed full of people watching some Japanese people who seemed to be selling teddy bears. I couldn't resist buying a game to try out on my laptop, so I got Bridge Commander - that should keep me busy for a few days at least! I then got a flashcard reader for my laptop, but when I got back I couldn't get it to work.</p>
		<p>We walked around a bit more, and Martin got sucked into a small clothes shop by an insistent lady. He bought two Chinese style dressing gowns as presents, but we managed to fend off the woman's requests for us to buy shirts for ourselves, dresses for our mums, clothes for our children, bedsheets, and anything else she had in the shop! It rained quite a bit while we were out, and actually thundered.</p>
		<p>We had half an hour to spare before we were due to be picked up outside the Mandarin hotel, so we went for a drink in one of the shopping centres. We then met Aunty Nancy and Brendan, who's now almost as tall as me - but not quite! Uncle James then drove us to East Coast Park where we met up with Aunty Nelli and my great-aunt Suk-Por. She seemed very well, and commented that I looked like my mum, although she still didn't speak any English. We went to Jumbo restaurant for seafood, and sat upstairs in the air-conditioning. The food was lovely - we had satay, mee goreng, big prawns, some curried crab, deep fried squid and some Chinese vegetables. Martin had his first beer of the trip, which he said was lovely! He was a bit afraid of getting drunk in front of my relatives though! After dinner the weather was much less humid due to the earlier rain, so it was very nice walking back to the car.</p>
		<p>Back at Aunty Nelli's flat we played around with my computer a bit, watched some TV, then had to pack and get to bed as we had a very early start the next morning.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="30-03-2002">
		<p>We woke up at 6:15 - or rather I woke up. Martin fell straight back asleep again, and it took me two tries to wake him up! After getting ready we left for the airport in Aunty Nelli's BMW. We said goodbye and checked in. We were both quite hungry, so we found a place for breakfast and had chicken chook. We then didn't have much time to browse around duty free before we were called to board.</p>
		<p>The plane was quite small, a 737, but was very smooth. The flight was about an hour and a half to Kuching, and the food was much better than BA - I had some nice chicken and rice. There was no inflight entertainment, but I had a quick go at Bridge Commander. When we landed, Martin thought they had misplaced his suitcase, but after waiting around for a while by the baggage reclaim he noticed it just waiting on the conveyor belt. After this little excitement we met our driver, Zakariah, who took us on a little tour though Kuching on the way to our hotel. He stopped off by some gold merchants for Martin to look at jewellery for Lis, then took us to the Regalis Court hotel.</p>
		<p>Aunty Nancy had booked us in for three nights, but once we arrived we decided that we'd rather stay for the whole trip. It seems very close both to the hospital and to the centre of town - and it had air-conditioned rooms. It was incredibly hot outside today! They did a special rate for us as we were staying over three weeks - RM75 a night for a twin room, which is about £15. We actually slept for a while in the afternoon, then went out looking for dinner.</p>
		<p>There were lots of food stalls close to the hotel, but funnily enough we ended up having Singapore chicken rice! A meal for two, including drinks, cost less than £2. It was raining quite a lot, so we retired back to the hotel, hoping to sit in the bar with a few drinks. However, it looks like the bar has been closed down, or moved to a different street. In the end we went back to the room and watched some TV before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="31-03-2002">
		<p>We woke up at 8 o'clock with a phone call from Zakariah, asking if we wanted to go to Damai beach today. We had nothing else planned, so we accepted. We met him outside the hotel at 11 o'clock and he took us into town to get some lunch. We went to a food court in one of the shopping centres, and I had a Sarawak laksa, which was very similar to the Singapore variety, but a little less hot and not as much coconut.</p>
		<p>After lunch we drove the 30 or so kilometres to Damai beach on the Santabong peninsular. It was basically a group of holiday resorts which Zakariah got us to walk around - not that interesting. On the way back he drove us through a golf club so we could see the facilities. It wasn't the best use of an afternoon! Once we were delivered back to our hotel, we walked decided to walk into town. It probably took us about half an hour, and it wasn't too humid, so the walk was very pleasant.</p>
		<p>First of all we went to the visitor information centre, as we wanted to find out about diving in Sarawak. There were an Australian couple in front of us who wanted to visit Baku national park and see the orang utans, and they seemed to be asking every question under the sun about it - when's the best time to go, how much is a taxi there, how much to hire a car... When we eventually got to talk to the desk clerk he told us that there isn't really any diving in Sarawak, and that we'd be better off going to the tourist office to ask about other sites in Malaysia. As it was Sunday the tourist office was closed, so we just had a walk around town. Kuching is very different to Singapore - there are lots of markets and most of the shops are run for local people rather than tourists - hence lots of small food shops and clothes shops, and no high tech computer shops! Air conditioning could only be found in the big shopping centre.</p>
		<p>We had dinner in the same food court as before, and I had a selection of rice, one vegetable and two meat dishes for 60 pence. Then we caught a taxi back to the hotel, as I had a headache, and I tried to sleep it off. We had an early night to prepare ourselves for our first day of work tomorrow!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="01-04-2002">
		<p>We met Zachariah outside the hotel at 8:20 and he took us to the hospital where we shuttled around between a few people before we found out what we were supposed to be doing. We arranged to spend a week in general medicine, then possibly cardiology or emergency medicine, hopefully with a trip to a rural area at some point.</p>
		<p>To our horror the hospital had no air conditioning, and it was rather hot! The general medical ward was split into a male and a female side, and we were assigned to the latter. When we arrived the ward round was almost over, but we met the registrar Dr Chang, and another elective student, Evelyn, who was from New Zealand, but was originally Malaysian so she spoke a bit of Malay. The ward round was interrupted by the consultant, Dr Chew, who seemed a bit of a show-off. He strutted around in front of every one, trying to embarrass his registrar and impress the nurses, who all looked quite bored with it! A couple of visiting doctors were also there, as it was the local medical students' finals tomorrow and they were the external examiners. When they had left we finished the ward round, quite fast because the reg was now behind time, so there was no time for teaching. This was unfortunate, as none of the patients spoke any English, so we had no idea what they were talking about! After the round, we examined one lady with a pneumonia, just to practice finding signs. Evelyn was very handy at helping us to say, "take a deep breath", and "lean forward please".</p>
		<p>We had to go to the immigration office to get the correct visas, so we called Zachariah to take us there. Once this was sorted out we had lunch there, and then went back to the hotel to do some reading. I had another bad headache, which I think must be due to the heat, and I had to lie down and sleep for a while. Martin did quite a lot of work, and when I woke up I did some reading about renal disease and tried to learn some Malay. I have a feeling that we're not going to be able to communicate with the patients for the whole trip!</p>
		<p>We went out to find some dinner, and came upon a street behind the hotel that was full of hawker stalls. They all seemed to be selling the same dishes though! We picked a stall and I had some kwae teow goreng and supposedly a Sarsi, although it was in a glass, very concentrated at the bottom, and very dilute at the top - quite odd, and sickly. While we were wandering around we went into a local supermarket and bought some fruit - nothing exotic unfortunately, just plums!</p>
		<p>When we got back to the hotel I had a phone call from Mum which was very nice. It was a bank holiday at home so Dad was there as well. We then turned on the TV to watch the in house movie channel and got quite a surprise - all of the movies seemed to be pirated copies. We could tell this by the fact that people occasionally walked between the camera and the screen!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="02-04-2002">
		<p>We didn't do anything today! Zachariah called us at 7 in the morning and said he couldn't give us a lift to the hospital as his mother-in-law had died, so we went back to sleep. At midday we got up and went to KFC for lunch. We got a box with 12 pieces of chicken, but no fries. Luckily there were some scratch cards, and I won some fries. Martin won a pot of whipped potato, which didn't look very appetising. It probably didn't taste too good either, as he only had one mouthful.</p>
		<p>After lunch we went to the supermarket and bought some water and some paper. While we were there we also looked in a computer game shop. The PC games cost £1.40 each, but they were all quite old, and obviously pirated. There was nothing further to entice us there, so we went back to our room and spent the afternoon reading. In the evening we went back to the hawker centre from last night, and I ate mee hoon goreng, beef satay at 6p a stick, and had a honeydew melon drink. We came back to the hotel and played cards for a while before going to sleep.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="03-04-2002">
		<p>We went in to the hospital in the morning and followed the ward round. Then we examined a nice lady who had signs of heart failure. We ate lunch in the hospital canteen, where I saw a poster for Kickapoo Joy Juice! Unfortunately they didn't seem to be selling it. At least I have a holiday quest now! In the evening we ate dinner at a Chinese restaurant, as we noticed that they sold beer! We had some very nice chicken noodles and some vegetables, and some duck which was over cooked - and some beer! We then went back to our room where I beat Martin at Slam again!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="04-04-2002">
		<p>I had diarrhoea this morning so didn't go in to work. When I got up Martin was still at the hospital, so I did some revision. I know all about renal medicine now! I had some fruit for lunch and then Martin didn't feel very well, so he went to bed early. I had dinner at a local coffee shop behind the hotel, then went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="05-04-2002">
		<p>Today, Martin wasn't feeling too good, so he didn't come with me to the hospital in the morning. I decided to walk rather than get a taxi, as it wasn't too hot, and the hospital is actually really close. The ward round was quite interesting, with a girl with renal tubular acidosis who was acidotic and hypokalaemic with prolonged QT intervals. They were worried about her going into Toursades, so they were giving her potassium. There were also a couple of overdoses, one of paraquat, and the other a different weed killer. Martin arrived after the ward round in time to go to outpatients clinic. We sat in with a lady doctor and the first patient didn't speak any English, which was a shame because she was there for tuberculosis follow-up. We examined her though and found consolidation in her lung. The second patient spoke English, but he was just there for a routine diabetic check up, of the sort that would be carried out by the GP in England.</p>
		<p>We ate lunch in the hospital, then went back to the hotel to try and arrange some diving. We decided it would be a good idea to bring our flight forward to Singapore, then go diving in Tioman, just off the coast of mainland Malaysia. I e-mailed Aunty Nancy to see what she thought. We also found out that we could move rooms today, as Martin wasn't sleeping well in our current room, which was at the front of the hotel by the main road. We moved all our stuff across the corridor to our new room, which looked identical, but was much quieter, with a nicer view.</p>
		<p>In the evening we had dinner at Pizza Hut! Our eyes were definitely bigger than our stomachs, and the food was so cheap, that we ordered a large pizza each, with garlic bread for starters. The waitress asked if we were sure we meant large pizzas! In the end we only managed to eat one pizza between us, so we took the rest home. Martin wanted to eat the rest for breakfast, as he said cold pizza was delicious - hmmm.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="06-04-2002">
		<p>I tried a slice of cold pizza - not that great I must say. I just hope it doesn't give me food poisoning! We set out to see some of Kuching's sights today, and started with the Sarawak museum. The guide book stated that it had two wings, but when we got there it looked like the modern wing was closed down. However, the old wing was very interesting. It was set in a colonial style mansion, and the ground floor was composed of a taxidermy side, and a Shell-sponsored 'how do we extract oil from the ground' exhibition. It was actually quite informative, and made me realise just how much A level chemistry I'd forgotten! Upstairs was more about Sarawak, with displays of traditional crafts such as wood carving and weaving, some musical instruments, and the piece de resistance, a mock iban chief's house, complete with human skulls hanging from the ceiling, and an upstairs where the chief's lucky daughter would be kept, not being allowed downstairs until she was ready to marry.</p>
		<p>We tried going to the tourist centre after this, but it was shut as today was the first Saturday of the month. We walked further into town and had lunch on the Indian street. I had a chicken biryani, and Martin had mee goreng. We walked over to the main Mosque and had a peek inside, but by now the skies were starting to get grey and quite a wind had kicked up. It was rather nice really after all the heat. However, we read the warning signs correctly, and just got into a shopping centre as the heavens opened. There was a mighty storm, with huge claps of thunder and lightning. While we tried to wait out the rain, we explored the shopping centre and came upon a computer shop. We bought some games (obvious pirates, but only a pound each). I got Settlers IV, South Park Rally, and Emergency Room 2 - Disaster Strikes! We managed to get a cab from outside the shopping centre to take us back to the hotel.</p>
		<p>Once back, I tried loading my games, but was none too hopeful. As it turned out only one of the games worked - Emergency Room 2 of all things! The game itself was pretty hopeless though. One of Martin's CDs worked though - a compilation of different games, so we gave them a try.</p>
		<p>In the evening, we walked into town to find some dinner. We ate at a hawker centre where we had char siu pows, and kolo mee. I had been looking forward to this dish, after hearing reports of how it was cooked in pig lard! Sounds yummy! Unfortunately tonight it wasn't that good. It consisted of quite dry noodles topped with char siu. We were looking out for a bar on the way back, but neither of us have seen one in our whole time here. We did spy some glasses of beer in a hawker centre from across the street, so we ventured over and had a few Stellas, at 50p a can.</p>
		<p>After this merriment, I beat Martin at Slam again! He's just too slow! Ha ha ha!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="07-04-2002">
		<p>We went for lunch today at a nearby coffee shop which sold roti. It wasn't quite the same as roti paratha in Singapore, but it was similar. This time it had corned beef cooked inside it, and was served with curry ayam. It was very nice, and I had a hot Milo with it, which was like hot chocolate. After this we explored the Sunday market. At least, it was the only market we could find in the general area, but it didn't seem to be what we expected. The guide book described it as selling local handicrafts, but when we arrived they were just selling food. Lots of fresh vegetables and fish, which made Martin feel queasy as they were raw and grey. Also lots of spices. It wasn't that interesting though.</p>
		<p>After lunch we relaxed in the hotel before going out for a Pizza Hut dinner. We had learnt our lesson, and just had small pizzas each this time. I think the waitresses recognised us! We also had a salad, which was nice as we hadn't had any proper vegetables for a long time.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="08-04-2002">
		<p>We caught a taxi to the hospital this morning at Martin's insistence - just for the record I'm not the usual lazy one on this trip so far! We arranged to go on a rural visit over the next couple of days, then started cardiology. The cardiology block was brand new and very nice - and air conditioned! It seems pretty advanced too, with all investigation results available on computer, including ECGs, echoes and angiograms. All the doctors seemed very pleased to have us there, and we sat in with an outpatient consultation with an eighteen year old girl with a valvular lesion due to rheumatic fever. We listened to her murmur and discovered a mitral regurgitation. She was put on Frusemide and prophylactic penicillin, and was due to see the cardiothoracic surgeons next week for a valve replacement. We then watched doctor Sim, the head consultant (there were only two in total) performing an angiogram.</p>
		<p>We had a mid-morning snack at the hospital - kolo mee, which was much nicer then before. Still no Kickapoo though :-(. We went back to the hotel and had lunch of roti beef again! Then the hotel staff phoned Malaysian Airlines to reschedule our flight back to Singapore for our diving trip.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon we relaxed in our room, trying out one of Martin's game purchases, then we went out for dinner at Hornbill's Corner Cafe where we had steamboat. It was very nice, and in addition to the normal steamboat there was a  barbecue plate surrounding the water on which you put copious amounts of butter to fry the food in. Very tasty! We had lots of meat in different marinades, squid and prawns, a whole fish, some dim sum style dumplings, and finished off with some raspberry ripple ice-cream. After this hearty meal we walked back to the hotel.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="09-04-2002">
		<p>We left the Kuching today for a trip into the country. We had to leave the hotel in a rush to catch the 2pm bus, so had no time for lunch. We were going to a town called Lundu, about an hour and a half drive away. The bus trip was very hot and bouncy over roads that hadn't been well maintained. Just before getting to Lundu we had to cross a river on a ferry. As the coach got off the ferry though there was a horrific grating sound as the front caught on the ground and scraped up the ramp.</p>
		<p>When we got to Lundu the first order of business was to find some lunch, which we got by the bus station. I had some chicken rice. We then caught a taxi to take us to our hotel, the Gading. However, when we arrived there was some confusion until we realised that he had taken us to completely the wrong place - Gading national park! I thought it was a bit odd when we had to pay a toll to get to the hotel and an extra charge for bringing a camera. Luckily we got our money refunded and the taxi came back to take us to the right place. It might have been better to stay in the park though - the hotel was awful! The room was like a cell, and the décor seemed specifically designed to promote headaches, with garish purple walls. The toilet leaked on the floor when it was flushed, and the air conditioning rattled loudly. There was a TV, but it was mounted on the wall somewhere up near the ceiling, so you virtually had to lie down to see it. </p>
		<p>We had a few hours to kill before dinner, and there was nothing in the town, so I watched the TV while Martin tried to memorise a whole pack of cards. Once he had done this it was about time to eat, so we wandered out and found a nice place - the Happiness Seafood Cafe. It was very good indeed. We sat outside and had a few beers, then the food arrived. We had asked them to bring us a selection, and the first to arrive was a big plate of huge prawns, fried with their shells on in a lovely crispy marinade. We also had a whole fish in sweet and sour sauce, and a dish of pork and vegetables. The dinner was lovely, but provoked an ongoing argument as to how Martin can't understand why I don't eat fish tails and prawn shells - because it's disgusting! Martin did end up having quite a disturbing dream about fish tails that night, but I won't go into that.</p>
		<p>After dinner we went back to our 'hotel', and tried to get some sleep. This turned out to be quite a challenge, due to the noisy air con, a night club/karyoke bar right opposite our room, and about five in the morning a trio of cockerels greeting the dawn - about two hours too early.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="10-04-2002">
		<p>We got up early and checked out, then walked to the Lundu hospital, about ten minutes away. When we got there we met up with the health team who was going on a rural visit today. We left Lundu at around half past eight in a big land rover, went back over the river via the ferry, and on to our destination which was a small village half a hour's drive away. As we got close, the driver tooted his horn whenever we drove past a house to let them know we were coming. When we arrived the team set up a small GP surgery in one of the houses, which was a more like a hut. It was baking outside, but reasonably cool in the house. Almost immediately women started turning up (there was only one man the whole day), with their small children.</p>
		<p>It turned out that the day was mainly baby checks and prenatal visits. It was interesting for about half an hour. What I did approve of though was the snack break at 10:30, when we all went across to the local coffee shop and had curry noodles - just what I needed! I should try to instigate this practise back in the UK. They had a fish in a tank in the coffee shop which apparently would cost RM1000, which is £200. It looked a bit bored.</p>
		<p>When the clinic finished we were taken back to the bus station in time to catch the 2pm bus back to Kuching. When we arrived back, we got off in town and wandered around looking for postcards - we can't find them anywhere! We walked back to the hotel and played on the computer for a while, then had dinner at Pizza Hut again! The waitress definitely recognised us this time, and laughed when we ordered medium sized pizzas rather than large!</p>
		<p>Back at the hotel we watched Flubber on the TV, which wasn't that great! Halfway through I had some welcome relief from the film by a phone call from Mum. Dad then called me from work, and I made him jealous by telling him about the roti paratha place just next to the hotel!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="11-04-2002">
		<p>We decided not to go in to the hospital any more, as we weren't learning anything useful there, and we could do more productive work revising in the hotel. Today I read through cardiovascular medicine, and feel I'm starting to get a grip on things! I'll do endocrinology tomorrow.</p>
		<p>For lunch we went to the roti place, but the roti lady wasn’t there, so we had kolo mee and char siu pow instead. Nothing much happened in the afternoon, except the arrival of a Malaysian under 19 football team at the hotel. It seems like the place is going to be a bit busier in the next few days. On the way out for dinner we noticed that the hotel had opened up its bar area and was serving food, so we had dinner there. It was very nice, and tasted like home cooked food. We had rice with chicken curry, beef and potatoes in soya sauce, some nice vegetables and a fried fish, finished off with some watermelon.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="12-04-2002">
		<p>Finished endocrinology! We had a nice lunch at a local Japanese restaurant, although we weren't completely sure what to do with some of the food! I had sushi and sashimi, with some tempura prawns served with cold noodles and some soup (I think) and some other sauce. It was very tasty though. They were just closing up as we finished, so we didn't have a chance to try any sake.</p>
		<p>In the evening we had a delicious lamb biryani for dinner at a local coffee shop, and some ice cream. Martin bought a bottle of Oxford Landing, and I bought a couple of cans of Guinness. Back at the hotel, Martin tried opening his wine with his pen knife cork screw, but the cork broke, so he had to cut it out. The wine was quite nice, although very warm. The Guinness wasn't so nice warm.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="13-04-2002">
		<p>We got up early this morning to meet Zachariah, who was going to take us to Bako national park. First though we went for breakfast at a local coffee shop, where we had roti canai - very similar to roti paratha, but the curry wasn't as hot. We then drove the 30 km to Bako Bazzar where we met a few other tourists to share a boat across to the park. There were two Canadians, Sonny and Allison, two Australians, Martin and Ricki, and a Dutch guy called Eric. The boat trip was quite exciting - we had to wear life jackets, and the South China Sea was getting a bit choppy! The driver was a bit crazy, and seemed to enjoy crashing up and down the waves as much as possible. We were quite wet by the end, but it was exhilarating. The tide was out when we arrived, so we got our feet wet wading to the shore.</p>
		<p>After registering our arrival at the park, we decided to follow the Lintang trail which was a five and a half kilometre circuit. It didn't sound like that far, but it failed to tell us that we would be climbing up to the top of a small mountain and back! Thankfully it was quite cloudy today, although the humidity did nothing to help our sweating. The walk was really fun, but very tiring, and there were a few good lookout points with panoramic views across the park and the beach.</p>
		<p>We had been looking out for proboscis monkeys throughout the trail, but the most wildlife I had seen was a lizard and some big insects. However, right at the end of the circuit we walked through some mangrove trees and saw four monkeys sitting on a branch within touching distance. They were quite small and were probably babies or female as they didn't have the male's characteristic long nose for which they are named. They were very cute though.</p>
		<p>We went for lunch at the park canteen and met up with our friends from earlier. I had some noodles, and lots of water. While we were eating we saw another monkey creeping up. It looked furtively around, then dashed through an open window into the canteen, emerging seconds later with its paws full of food! Very cunning monkey! Apparently we had just missed seeing a huge bearded pig.</p>
		<p>After lunch we went on an easier trek for around half an hour, up to another lookout point with views across the bay. We then went back to the dock to be picked up by our boat. We were returning with Martin and Ricki, and the ride was much smoother going back. We had around 40 minutes to wait for Zachariah to arrive, so we had an ice cream and sat in a coffee shop. I went to get a drink, and unexpectedly my quest was fulfilled - tucked away in a corner of the fridge I found some cans of Kickapoo Joy Juice! Of course I had to buy one, and Martin bought three. While we drank our Joy Juice we watched some very hungry looking cats scrounging for food.</p>
		<p>Zachariah took us back to the hotel where we had a much needed shower, and just relaxed for a while. We went for dinner at the same place as yesterday, and Martin had lamb biryani again. I had some char kwei teow and then a bowl of Sarawak laksa. The coffee shop owners are very friendly and recognised us from yesterday. One of the women doesn't speak much English, but she pulled up a chair at our table and watched us eat, laughing every now and then and chatting to us in Malay. She would say something, laugh, and pat Martin on the shoulder! She reminded me of Grandma.</p>
		<p>After dinner we explored the Sunday Market. Obviously we had just caught the end of it last week, as tonight it was completely different. The market is set up on Saturday night, and the stall owners sleep at their stalls and start trading again in the morning. The market was absolutely huge, with endless rows of stalls under brightly coloured umbrellas. Most of the stalls sold fresh food: fish, fruit, vegetables, and things cooked on the spot like banana fritters. There were also stalls selling toys, handicrafts, and animals including cute rabbits and mice. The atmosphere was really nice, and even at 9:30 the place was packed with shoppers. It was more crowded than Oxford on a bank holiday. We ended up buying some wooden blowpipes as presents for Aunty Nancy and Nelli, and Martin got one for himself and his brother.</p>
		<p>As if this weren't enough for one day, we got back to our room to find the Guinness Book of Records on TV with the worlds fattest model (over half a ton), and a woman who performed self-trephination in order to let her brain pulsate and so get more blood. Weird stuff! In all this was a very enjoyable day.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="14-04-2002">
		<p>Zachariah was planning to go fishing today, so we couldn't get a lift from him. Instead we stayed in and did some revision. We had lunch in the hotel, and dinner at the roti shop. Unfortunately, the roti lady still wasn't back, so we had satay and mee goreng instead. Martin had a beef sandwich, and was very pleased to find a dollop of mayonnaise with it. We also had quite a lot of Tiger beer...</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="15-04-2002">
		<p>I woke up with a bit of a hangover. I think Martin felt a bit worse than I did. Zachariah picked us up at 9:30 and we went for some roti canai breakfast. We also shared a portion of chicken biryani - a very nice way to start the day! We then drove to Jong's crocodile farm, although Zachariah did get a bit lost and we drove back and forth a few times until we found it.</p>
		<p>We arrived just in time for the feeding. There were some large, innocuous looking lakes behind wire fences. Little did they give away the fact that they were full of killer crocs! A man stood on a raised platform above the lake and banged a gong to announce dinner, then he lobbed whole chicken carcasses into the water. Soon there were crocodiles everywhere, fighting for the food. The feeder seemed to be trying to hit the crocs between the eyes with the chickens.</p>
		<p>After the feeding, we walked around the rest of the farm. Next to the crocodile lake was a pen full of chickens - hmm, not so much for display I think! There were also some monkey cages and some of the monkeys seemed pretty inquisitive, coming right up to the cage to see us. One of the monkeys had somehow escaped from its cage, and didn't know how to get back. It was just a baby. We told the staff at the gate about it. There was also a Borneo gibbon, a leopard cat, some pythons, and some brightly coloured squirrels! On the way out we stopped to look at souvenirs, and we bought some postcards and some crocodile skin belts.</p>
		<p>We then drove to the Wildlife Sanctuary to visit the orang utan rehabilitation centre. It is an area of rainforest dedicated to help orang utans who had been illegally kept as pets to be able to live in the wild again. It currently has 18 orang utans, including three babies. We arrived while they were shut for lunch, but we were allowed to walk around a bit. While we were standing around near the entrance, one of the staff placed a loaf of bread out on the grass. The next thing we knew, there was a huge crashing noise coming from the forest, with big trees swaying around. Then we saw a huge orange orang utan coming out into the open. It was really massive, and so hairy! It took the bread back up its tree to eat.</p>
		<p>The orang utan feeding time was in a hour, so we went to have lunch ourselves. We drove to a nearby coffee shop and had some kolo mee. It was getting pretty hot by now. After our feeding, we went to see the orang utans. When we got back to the park, there were quite a lot of tourists already there, taking photos of three orang utans that had come out. The big male climbed down from a tree and sat on the path eating a papaya, and the mother with her baby was playing in a tree, swinging around. We walked along a path to the feeding observation area, but only one orang utan came out to eat. It had a whole bucket full of fruit to itself! However, while we were walking back down the path to the car, the mother was coming back up the other way with its baby on its back. We all stood to the side of the path, and she walked straight up between us. The baby looked at us as it went past. It was very exciting!</p>
		<p>After this we went back to the hotel to pack ready for our departure tomorrow. We went back to the biryani place for dinner, but the laughing lady wasn't there tonight. We went to the supermarket to get a present for Zachariah, and decided on a box of biscuits. I also bought some grape juice, which turned out to taste awful!</p>
		<p>Back at the hotel we watched some TV, Friends and a series called Ed, which is like a male Ally McBeal. There was also the Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon TV series in Mandarin. I got a phone call from Mum at about 11 o'clock, as it was her birthday. She was very pleased to have got my flowers, and I was pleased they had arrived.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="16-04-2002">
		<p>We flew back to Singapore at around lunch time, and were met by Aunty Nancy who had just returned from KL. We went back to her house, and I played on her nice baby grand piano for a while. Gabriel had some Rachmaninov and Chopin music, and quite a lot of jazz.</p>
		<p>Rodney then took us into town, after a few false starts where we had to go back to the house to pick things up, such as travellers cheques. He dropped Aunty Nancy off at work first, then took us to Peoples Place for Martin to buy jewellery for Lis. We walked around for three quarters of an hour, feeling quite confused as we couldn't seem to find the shop we had gone to before. Eventually Rodney came back, and showed us where it was - it was being renovated! We went to the shop next door and Martin bought a gold necklace. He also got a new camera, as he had misplaced his old one. We then went to the hawker centre nearby and had Yong Tau Fu soup with fishballs - very tasty!</p>
		<p>After this nice snack, we went to Holland Park so I could buy a flashcard reader for my camera. Unfortunately, after this we went to Orchard Road to try and get a refund on my 'faulty' card reader. The guy in the shop checked it for me, and it worked! A bit embarrassing - I had been putting the card in upside down! Never mind, I have two now in case one breaks! We then went to the bar outside the Marriott hotel and ordered a couple of beers. Little did we realise that these would be the most expensive beers we had ever bought - $16 each, which is around £6 a pint! Fortunately we could make these last until Aunty Nancy arrived to pick us up.</p>
		<p>Uncle James picked us up and took us to Newton Circus. On the way I phoned Chia to see if she could meet us, but unfortunately she had already made plans. We promised to meet in Australia though. Uncle James couldn't stay for dinner, so the three of us pigged out. We had some rojak, poh piah, oluak (yummy!), duck noodles, some cockles and some assorted food to dip in sauces, including Chinese sausage and octopus. Needless to say we couldn't quite finish everything. We did have some dessert though. Martin wanted an ice kachang, and I had some sea coconut with palm seeds.</p>
		<p>After this feast we caught a taxi back home, and packed our bags for tomorrow. We were only allowed 10 kg each, so we had to be quite strict. I e-mailed from Brendan’s computer, then we watched 'Bad Boys' in our room before going to sleep.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="17-04-2002">
		<p>We woke up this morning to a fantastic breakfast prepared by Nancy's maid, Deena. We had char siu pows, some nice boiled egg with soya sauce, some potato cakes, and a cup of coffee. I played the piano some more, then Rodney arrived to take us to the airport. We weren't flying from Changi airport, but from Seletar military air base. We had to show our passports to some soldiers at the gate before we could go in.</p>
		<p>As we waited to board our plane we watched a cool blue helicopter taking off from just outside. We then watched a variety of American cooking programs that were being shown in the departure room. We shared a smallish propeller plane (around 40 seats) with 8 other passengers, and the flight was quite fun as we stayed at only 10,000 ft the whole time, so you could see the world going past below. The landing was a bit hairy, as he touched down literally at the beginning of the runway. We thought we were going to crash into streams and telephone pylons as we flew past!</p>
		<p>After safely arriving, we went through immigration and got the bus to the resort. The Berjaya Resort is lovely! We are in our own little cabin, with air con, en suite, minibar, TV etc. We immediately made our way to the resort's dive centre, and were just in time to join the 2:30 dive. We hadn't brought all our stuff with us, so I got to ride back with one of them on the back of their motorbike to pick it up! On the way back to the centre we got stopped by a huge iguana sitting across the path. It seemed very lazy, and only moved aside after a lot of hooting!</p>
		<p>The dive was fantastic. Our dive leader was a guy called Francis, and he helped us sort out all our equipment. We were joined by a Japanese man called Kai, who had brought along a digital camera in a waterproof case. We rode out towards an island, a couple of minutes ride from the centre, then backward rolled into the water. As we were about to descend I looked down and saw a huge school of fish swimming around beneath me - this looked like it was going to be good.</p>
		<p>We spent 50 minutes on the dive, and went down to 13m. It was very nice to be able to wear a shorty wet suit rather than a dry suit! It also meant I needed far less weights. There was loads of colourful coral, and beautiful fish everywhere. I didn't know what most of them were, but I recognised clown fish swimming through the arms of sea anemones, and spiny black sea urchins with cool glowing blue centres were all around. They encouraged you to maintain good buoyancy control. We also saw the head of a small moray eel, a big hornbill sea turtle which swam right underneath me, and best of all a shark! I was swimming along, looking at the coral, and when I looked up, there it was, just swimming towards me. It was probably about 1.5 to 2 metres long, and it circled all the way round us. I got a little nervous when it started coming back again, but it just ignored us and swam off into the murk. The visibility was reasonably good, but there seemed to be a lot of coral sperm floating around!</p>
		<p>After the dive we returned to our room, and were just getting ready to go for a swim. Martin had gone out to buy some goggles, and when he got back he said that he had bumped into the masseur, who was free. We decided to go and have a massage instead! We thought it would be both of us together, but there was only one masseur, so Martin went first. I thought I should wait back in the room until he'd finished, but the guy brought a chair inside and said I could wait. After a while though, I feigned needing a drink and left - it was getting quite dodgy! He had been trying to get Martin's pants off, but Martin tactfully declined. However, he was really working his buttocks, and I couldn't take it any more! The massage went on for an hour, and according to Martin got much more explicit, especially when he was flipped over onto his back. The masseur knows our room number, and I think he's going to come after me at some point - I'm going to have to keep a low profile!</p>
		<p>For dinner we went to a restaurant in the resort called Sri Nelayan, which was by the main pool. It seemed very nice, and I had a big hot dog! We also got our complimentary soft drinks. It's very expensive compared to what we were used to paying in Malaysia. Still a bit cheaper than England though. After dinner we went to the beach bar, which is literally right on the beach front. The drinks are really expensive here! I had a Singapore sling, then Martin and I shared a jug of Carlsberg. It's a shame we came out of season, because it looks like a really fun place when it's busy, but the place was a little quiet. We finished the evening off with Martin beating me at a game of pool on a table with what seemed to be a concrete surface.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="18-04-2002">
		<p>We were due at the dive centre at 7:30, so we went for breakfast first at the Sri Nelayan restaurant. There was a big buffet breakfast, but we weren't that hungry, so I just had a few sausages and an apple. Little did we realise that it would cost £6 each! After this rather expensive start to the day, we went over to the dive centre for our first dive. We were actually scheduled to do two dives today, and they took us out on a boat to an island about 30 minutes away. Kai was with us again, and another man called Joseph who was an ex army paramedic from Lincoln. The first dive was lots of fun, involving a swim through a coral tunnel.</p>
		<p>For lunch we were dropped on a nearby island, where we sat on the beach and ate our packed lunches of sandwiches, chicken, muffins and an apple. After relaxing for a while I decided to try a bit of snorkelling. The reef started about 20m out from the shore, and there were fish everywhere. At one point I just lay still in the water and they all came up to see what I was. I could feel them brushing against me, and it was quite nice until one of them decided to try and have a nibble. From then on I didn't float sedately too much!</p>
		<p>After lunch we had our second dive, which was also lots of fun. The water was so warm and clear it was lovely. Towards the end of the dive a small, long, black and white fish came towards me. It looked a bit like a small dogfish. I thought it wanted it play, as it came up really close. Little did I realise that it wanted to feed! These little blighters became the bane of our dives here, always seeming to turn up at some point. They're the fish that feed off larger fish like sharks. Once they get an interest in you they just don't leave off, and they can give a nasty nip as Martin found out, with a bloody ankle after one dive.</p>
		<p>When we got back we bumped into Simon, our friendly masseur. We can't help bumping into him, seeing as his 'parlour' is almost opposite our hut. Anyway, I decided to give it a go, so I had a quick shower first (I was particularly sweaty!). I'm not quite sure what to think of it. I don't know whether it was relaxing, it certainly was quite painful though! He seemed to dig his fingers into all my myofascial trigger points, including loads I didn't know I had. It was like Mike Cummings at our acupuncture course gone mad! Also, I was starting to burn a little, and having him rub the burnt patches was a bit uncomfortable. At least I know what it's like now.</p>
		<p>We were very hungry at about 5 o'clock after all this diving, so we went for a snack in the restaurant. I had some crab and chicken wrapped in fried pastry which was very nice. However, it was actually quite a lot, so we didn't eat again for dinner.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="19-04-2002">
		<p>We started our PADI Advanced Open Water certification today. It involves five dives, and some book work, but no exam. We were planning to do three dives today: a deep dive, a multi level dive, and a night dive. For the deep dive we took a boat out to the same area we had been diving yesterday, just off the coast of Coral Island. We went down to 30m at first, and spent 50 minutes overall. There was a lot of coral around, and although I couldn't identify most of it, I did recognise fire coral which is supposed to really burn if you touch it - I stayed away! Our instructor was called Nazri, and we were also diving with a man called Thomas who was French but lived in China.</p>
		<p>We were dropped off on the same beach as yesterday to have our lunch, but we were starting to get a little burnt, so we put on lots of sun cream and stayed in the shade.</p>
		<p>After lunch we went to another nearby site to do our multi level dive. There were a lot more fish on this dive, and we saw a cuttlefish. In the evening we went on our night dive which was lots of fun. We saw a barracuda going for another fish - I don't think it got it though. We also saw a big prawn and a couple of squid.</p>
		<p>For dinner we went to a poolside restaurant for a buffet dinner. We ended up buying a bottle of wine which turned out to be really expensive, and the buffet was almost finishing as we had arrived quite late. We did get some very tasty barbecued seafood though. There was a live band playing, who occasionally sounded quite good, but usually were quite bad! We went to the karyoke bar afterwards to have a go ourselves, but it had just closed for the evening. Oh well, maybe another night.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="20-04-2002">
		<p>We had a day off diving today, to try to get over some of our sunburn. Martin's back is very red, and I've been burnt a bit on my back, arms, knees, and feet! We had a bit of a lie in, then went for lunch at the Sri Nalayan poolside restaurant. We looked on enviously at the swimmers enjoying the sunny pool, while I ate a big chicken burger. We went to get a board game from reception, but the selection was rather limited - they only had scrabble. Instead, we played 'Blood 2' on my laptop!</p>
		<p>We had dinner at quite a nice Chinese restaurant in the resort. We had aromatic duck for starters, then I had won ton soup noodles, which strangely was made with fried won tons. The owner was very chatty, and told us he had lived in Oxford about 8 years ago. He was asking whether the Liasons was still there, and the Opium Den and Oriental Condor.</p>
		<p>We had a drink at the beach bar, sitting at a table right on the shore, which was very relaxing.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="21-04-2002">
		<p>I got a quick breakfast of some Pringles before heading down to the dive centre for a 9am start. We met Nazri and went through our plan for today - a wreck dive and then a navigation dive in the afternoon. The wreck was fantastic. It was a Thai fishing boat that had been caught coming in to Malaysia illegally, and sunk when the owner couldn't pay the impound fine. It was pretty big, and as we approached it loomed out of the water. The visibility was very good, and we could see pretty much the whole ship at once. It was slanted over to its side, but was completely intact, with just a few wooden boards come loose off the side. There were fish all over it, and in the old bridge, which was now just a skeletal remnant, a huge shoal of tiny fish were darting in and out. We were joined by our old friends, the really annoying biting little fish. Fortunately they left us alone after a while. I also saw a sea snake which just dropped out of the water in front of me. I thought it was a piece of rubber tubing at first, until I saw it slithering away across the sea bed. Towards the end of the dive we saw three black tipped sharks swimming around the reef, and a large turtle.</p>
		<p>We had lunch at the same Chinese restaurant as last night, where I had some Singapore noodles. After this we had an ice cream, then went back to the room for a while. I watched some bad film on TV while Martin had a sleep.</p>
		<p>We went back to the dive centre at 2:30 for our navigation dive. The dive site was just off the shore, so we went in a little boat, and rolled off the side backwards into the water. We had to do a few manoeuvres, such as swimming in a straight line and back, and swimming in a square. Afterwards we had a little time for fun, so we swam along the reef, and along with the normal array of colourful fish we saw a huge moray eel poking its head out of a hole in the reef. It had beady purple eyes, and I kept my distance! When we got back to shore we were given our Advanced Open Water certificates, and had our photo taken for the local paper! The resort owner came to shake our hands - I'm not exactly sure why this was newsworthy, but it was quite fun.</p>
		<p>We went for a nice swim in the evening, just as the sun was going down. For dinner we had steamboat at a place by the shore. We had to wait about three quarters of an hour for our food, but it was very tasty. Lots of fresh seafood, chicken, beef, and vegetables.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="22-04-2002">
		<p>We got up reasonably late this morning, and lay in bed watching a film on TV. It was called Barton Fink, and was very odd. Once we dragged ourselves outside, we went for lunch at our local Chinese place again, where I had some spring rolls and some noodles with chicken and squid which was very nice. We always seem to order too much, as the portions are huge! After lunch we checked our e-mails and I sent one of the pictures from my digital camera to go in the medics yearbook. After this we got an ice cream, went back to the room and played on the computer for a bit.</p>
		<p>In the evening we went out for another swim at dusk, and sat in the jacuzzi for a while this time. Very bubbly! After drying off we went back to the Chinese restaurant for dinner, where we shared some fried rice and chicken with ginger and spring onion. We had a couple of beers there, in anticipation of having a few more at the karyoke bar. Luckily, there were only two other people doing karyoke this evening, so we got to sing lots of songs!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="23-04-2002">
		<p>We checked out of our room at 9:30, then went for some breakfast before catching the resort bus to the airport. I had an omelette and some roti paratha with chicken curry. The flight back was very smooth, and when we arrived Rodney took us back to Aunty Nancy's. We showered and had some noodles for lunch, then sat and watched Nancy's collection of 'Sex and the City' videos until 4 o'clock.</p>
		<p>Brendan was going to school to have an exam, so we caught a lift with him into town. We spent a couple of hours shopping - Martin bought some ties and a silk shirt from another shop where they tried to convince you to buy everything they had. They were trying pretty hard to convince us to buy some tailored suits!</p>
		<p>We then found a scuba shop and spent about an hour trying on different wet suits. A bit yucky, seeing as our sunburn was starting to peel. The changing room floor was quite grim afterwards! We eventually bought a wet suit each, and a bag. Martin indulged himself by buying a delayed SMB and an underwater laser pointer! Should come in very handy.</p>
		<p>We met Aunty Nancy at Scott's plaza, and from there we went on to a hawkers centre called 'Chomp Chomp'. The food was very good. We ate oluak, char kwae teow, some prawn noodles, fried dumplings, and sting ray cooked in a banana leaf with chilli. When we got back home we finished watching the first series of 'Sex and the City' - very funny.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="24-04-2002">
		<p>We woke up at around 8am, and had a breakfast of glutinous rice wrapped in brightly coloured pastry. Rodney picked us up at 9 o'clock and took us to the zoo. It was very good, and well presented. We saw the sea lion show, and Martin got a kiss from one, which he said was very fishy. Unfortunately at one point some animal did it's business on my shirt from out of a tree, but otherwise it was really fun.</p>
		<p>We met Aunty Nancy at the Pine Tree Club for lunch, but they wouldn't let us in because of the dress code, so we went to the Shaw centre for some dim sum. As usual we ate far too much, but it was very tasty. We had to eat chicken feet though. We had some purple yam paste for dessert, which looked like wallpaper paste, but tasted nice.</p>
		<p>After lunch we said goodbye to Aunty Nancy, and Rodney dropped us back home. We packed our bags, and I played on the piano for an hour until it was time to go the airport. After we checked in, we sat and watched the Changi airport game show - 'What's Your Range', which was quite amusing. The contestants have to answer ten questions, and whoever gets the highest mark is allowed to open a box which contains a prize. The winner got a $50 shopping voucher. After this, we went to duty free and looked at the gadgets. Martin bought another gadget, which was a tiny personal organiser. Unfortunately, its innards got fried in the X-ray machine. We boarded our flight at 8 o'clock.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="25-04-2002">
		<p>I've decided that Qantus is much better than BA. For a start, the food is actually quite tasty (I had a nice vegetable lasagne), and the staff are all very friendly. The flight was very smooth, even for the smaller 767, and we touched down in Sydney at 5:30 in the morning. We spent just under an hour there in transit, then continued on to Cairns, which took about 2 hours. In Cairns, Martin spent nearly an hour with customs trying to convince them not to destroy his blowpipes. Luckily, they decided that they could keep them for him at the airport. They said that they'd have liked to keep his Kickapoo Joy Juice though, because they thought it was so funny.</p>
		<p>We caught a taxi to our new home for five weeks - the Reef Gateway Apartments. Our apartment is really fantastic for about £8 a night each. We have our own bedrooms, of which Martin has the big bed for the first half of our stay. There's quite a big kitchen, and our own washing machine and tumble drier, and of course air con. There are also three cable movie channels!</p>
		<p>After unpacking we talked to Peter, our host, and his wife Patricia about diving. Peter does quite a lot of diving, and so could recommend some companies to us. We then had a bit of a sleep for a couple of hours, as the flight had been quite tiring. When we awoke we went into town to explore. It's about a fifteen minute walk into the centre of Cairns, and although it's very hot, it is much less humid here, so was very pleasant. We had an early dinner at 'Fasta Pasta', and the portions were quite huge, so we didn't need to eat again.</p>
		<p>It was a National holiday - ANZAC day, which commemorates the first Australian and New Zealand action during the first World War, so most shops were closed. We came back to the apartment and watched the end of 'Battlefield Earth' with John Travolta, which was very bad! </p>
		<p>After this we needed a drink, so we went across the road to the Cock and Bull, a place recommended to us by Peter. It was more of a restaurant than a pub though, so after one drink we headed into town, and went to a busy pub. We watched the second half of a football match on TV, and had a few more drinks. Most of the people in here sounded English or American. We got back to our room quite merry, and went straight to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-04-2002">
		<p>I woke up at ten o'clock and went over to the nearby convenience store to get some breakfast. After getting back I woke Martin up and cooked some bacon, eggs and beans on toast - very nice. Filled up, we went into town and looked around the main shopping centre. We found an Electronics Boutique, and I couldn't resist buying the new Jedi Knight game. We had a drink at the food court, and then went to the cinema to watch 'Resident Evil'. It was very horrible - but a good film!</p>
		<p>After the genetically mutated undead horrors of the film, I got back to reality by having a haircut at the local hairdressers, the Style Cutters. I had a very chatty hairdresser who told us we should go to New Zealand while we're here - I think she was biased though seeing she came from there. I also bought a new Sci-Fi book, as I haven't read one for ages. It's called 'The Reality Dysfunction' by Peter F. Hamilton. We finished our trip to town by doing a spot of grocery shopping. In fact, more than a spot, as we needed to catch a taxi back to the apartment.</p>
		<p>When we got back we found out that James Choulton, Tim and Nish had arrived. They'd just flown in from a holiday in Brisbane, after working in Sydney. While they were settling in, we relaxed in the room, and I of course tried out my new game! The five of us went into town for some dinner, and finally settled on a place on the Esplanade. I hadn't been here for six years, but it still looked familiar, and I recognised the hostel I had stayed at the last time.</p>
		<p>After dinner we went to the Woolshed for a few drinks. It was quite busy, but surprisingly there was no queue to get in. We had a couple of jugs of Fosters, but as Martin and I had to be up early tomorrow for diving, and the others were feeling pretty tired, we left early and went back. It was very nice to see familiar people from Oxford though, and interesting to hear what they'd been up to. I got a call from Mum just before I went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-04-2002">
		<p>We were picked up from our apartment by the Reef Dive minibus, to take us to the marina where we boarded our boat for the day, the Scubaroo. We were going to spend the day on the outer edge of the barrier reef, doing some diving. We didn't realise that the outer reef would be so far away. It took around an hour an a half through rather choppy water to get there. I didn't feel too bad until other people started having to use the sick bags. I managed to control myself though! They gave us some ginger tablets to stop sea sickness, and the unusual recommendation of sticking cotton wool in your ears.</p>
		<p>When we finally arrived, we moored next to the company’s liveaboard, the Reeftel. We had a quick dive brief, then got straight in the water. Martin and I were buddies, and didn't need a guide. The reef wasn't quite as nice as Tioman, and although there were some impressive coral walls and formations, there didn't seem to be as much animal life. It was very nice to be able to swim around where we wanted rather than having to follow a guide though. We had lunch aboard the Reeftel, then had a second dive. It was pretty similar to the first, but we did see some big fish this time! There were also quite a lot of fish doing poos in the water, so we had to dodge the falling faeces. I managed to take lots of photos on our new underwater camera.</p>
		<p>The trip back to shore was much calmer, thankfully. When we got back we were given a lift home, and after having a shower and cooking some dinner I read my new book for a while - it seems very good. We watched a couple of bad films on TV, including one called 'Witchblade', before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="28-04-2002">
		<p>James, Tim and Nish went on a trip to the Kuranda rainforest today, but we didn't join them as the diving had been a bit more expensive than we had thought. We slept in quite late, then had lunch at home. I cooked some spam noodles. After lunch we wandered into town and bought some tickets for the first showing of Star Wars Episode 2 in a couple of weeks time. I found a prepaid Internet access CD at Electronics Boutique. We bought a few more groceries and then walked home.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon we just watched some TV and played on the computer. I spent a while setting up my internet connection, but it all works fine now. I cooked some tomato pasta for dinner.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="29-04-2002">
		<p>We went in to the hospital to meet David Bossingham and Brian Fowler at 9:30 this morning. They made us feel very welcome and showed us round the hospital. Nish and James were taken off to the Emergency Department to meet the team they'd be working with. David Bossingham was originally from England, and came out to Australia for the heat. We spent the morning on his ward round, did a mini-mental state examination on a patient, and examined a man with rheumatic heart disease who had had three valves replaced. That made the murmurs difficult to interpret!</p>
		<p>We had lunch in the canteen, where I had a nice spinach and feta cheese roll and a coffee. It was beginning to get a little rainy, as we went back to the apartment intending to do some revision. However, the curse of bad cable movies took us, and we sat through 2 films before we could get up and turn the TV off.</p>
		<p>Martin and I had dinner in the Cock and Bull tonight. I had a fisherman's platter, and the portions were enormous! We had a couple of beers and played darts for a while, then got back to the apartment in time for Buffy at 10:30. It was an episode I'd already seen though, so I read my book instead.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="30-04-2002">
		<p>We had to be in the hospital at 8 o'clock this morning for a patient handover meeting. There didn't seem to be much handing over of anything, but we got assigned to different teams. I was joining the renal team, headed by consultant Munty Mantha (I kid you not). I met two of the University of Queensland (UQue) students, Heike and Ben, who are very friendly. We waited in a seminar room for half an hour for the respiratory X-ray meeting to start, but it turned out that it had been replaced by a pathology meeting downstairs.</p>
		<p>By now it was time to join our morning ward rounds, so Heike and I went to find the renal team. We met the reg, Simon, and Kate the SHO. Cairns has a very big renal department, due to the high incidence of diabetes among the Aboriginal population. We saw lots of patients getting ready for dialysis, with fistulas being formed. Also, a lady with Eaton-Lambert syndrome, which I've never seen before.</p>
		<p>I met up with Martin, Nish and James for lunch in the hospital canteen. I had a huge steak burger with all the toppings. It was so big it needed a wooden kebab stick through the middle to stop it falling apart. After making a complete mess of eating it, and my face covered in barbecue sauce, I made a quick retreat back to the apartment to do some revision. I managed to get half way through rheumatology before I couldn't take it anymore. I moved on to reading my Sci-Fi book instead.</p>
		<p>Martin came back from an afternoon clinic, and we went on a mission to the local convenience store. Well, two missions actually: Martin was after chocolate, and I was hunting beer. Unfortunately they didn't sell alcohol, so I had to make do with a bottle of coke. We ate some of Martin's bolognese sauce of which he had cooked enough to last a week on Sunday. We watched Demolition Man as we ate. The evening news was a bit alarming, showing doctors refusing to go to work, as the Australian medical indemnity company had gone bust. The government wasn't giving any firm assurances to provide indemnity, and the Australian Medical Association was recommending that doctors stop practising.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="01-05-2002">
		<p>I got up at 6:30 this morning for a 7:30 start at the hospital. The morning news reported that the government had drawn up a written contract indemnifying doctors until the end of July, so it looked like the hospital wouldn't be empty after all! Munty gave an early morning talk on acute renal failure for the registrars. Some of it was quite interesting, but he did go into a bit too much detail for what I needed to know. I checked my e-mail in the library for ten minutes until the gastro registrar Mark Norris came to get me. We were driving up to Mareeba today, about an hours drive north of Cairns, for a rural clinic. We picked up one of the hospital cars, called a Magna, and drove up through the Kuranda mountains and rainforest. The road was very windy up the mountain, and looked quite fun to drive. The rainforest turned into a lush green plain on the other side of the mountains, with lots of sugar cane on either side of the road, and huge termite mounds. We also saw papaya and mango trees.</p>
		<p>The day had started off rainy, but by the time we reached Mareeba the sun had come out, and there was a nice breeze. The district hospital was pretty much like a community hospital in the UK. However, it was staffed by GPs instead of hospital doctors. There is quite a large Italian immigrant population in Mareeba, as you could tell from the hospital signs being in both English and Italian. I saw two patients by myself, then sat in on the consultations with the other three. I was told that there wasn't much of an Aboriginal population here, but three out of five patients happened to be Aboriginal. It was very hard to find out how long symptoms had been going on for, as Aboriginals have a different sense of time to Westerners apparently.</p>
		<p>We finished at around 4pm, and got back by 5. I spent the evening relaxing, listening to music and catching up on my diary. Martin was on a respiratory Outreach trip to Cooktown until Friday, so I had the apartment to myself. I had a nice talk with Mum before bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="02-05-2002">
		<p>I took advantage of having the apartment to myself to catch up on some revision. I went through rheumatology and some haematology.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="03-05-2002">
		<p>I went to the medical grand round at lunchtime. There were two cases, one on SLE and the other was about calciphylaxis in end stage renal failure - a bit over my head! However, Heike and I then met up with Simon who had some short cases for us. We saw a lady who had had a stroke and now had left sided neglect, but unfortunately she was feeling very drowsy so we couldn't really examine her. We then saw an aboriginal lady who was diabetic and on dialysis, with massive signs of right heart failure.</p>
		<p>When I got home, I found Martin had got back and was watching TV. He told me to look in a big white box he had brought back, as that was going to be our dinner. Intrigued, I opened the box and found a great big fish. He had caught it fishing this morning. We went into town to get some food to go with the fish, and Martin told me about his trip. He had had a very good time, although the consultant was a bit mad and got him to eat green ants! Apparently all the Aboriginal people he met were completely bonkers as well!</p>
		<p>We got our groceries, and seeing as we were going to get a taxi back I bought a crate of XXXX as well. When we got back, Martin started preparing the fish, and Nish came over to see it. He had gone on an introductory dive during the week with Tim and James, and although he was nervous he said he really enjoyed it. Maybe they'll do a certification course, then we can all go diving together.</p>
		<p>Martin's fish was really delicious. The oven doesn't work too well, so we had to wait an hour and a half for dinner, but it was worth it. He cooked it in a lemon sauce, with chips and garlic bread. We had a few beers, and Martin got me to try some of his newly acquired gin and tonic - apparently the best brand of gin there is. I still didn't like it though! We had been planning to go out to the pub, but we started watching Sliding Doors over dinner, and by the time it was over it was too late to go out.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="04-05-2002">
		<p>We had a lie in this morning, and then went into town for lunch. We were planning to have some pasta, and then go to the cinema, but the show was just about to start when we got to the cinema , so we bought tickets then had a quick burger before going in to see 'The Scorpion King'. It was actually quite entertaining, and not as bad as I thought it would be. Afterwards, we wandered around the shopping centre a bit, bumped into James and Tim going for a hair cut, and bought a map of the region as we were thinking of hiring a car.</p>
		<p>When we got back home, we booked a trip to the reef for tomorrow, and a visit to Kuranda on Monday. It had been quite hot, so I decided to go for a swim in the pool. By the time I got changed though the sun had gone in and it was a bit chilly. Never one to be put off, I had a quick dip anyway, and tried out my new snorkel. The other lady in the pool must've thought I was a bit peculiar!</p>
		<p>After my swim we were trying out linking up my laptop to the TV with some cables Martin bought, when suddenly there was a power cut. I had a quick shower, before it got too dark in the bathroom to see, then we had to think about going out for dinner as we had no power for cooking. The five of us went across to the Cock and Bull and had a drink while we played darts, but they didn't have any tables free for us, so we walked into town to find some food.</p>
		<p>We ended up going to the same place as before on the Esplanade, where I had a very nice minted lamb with potatoes. Nish wanted to get back to watch the build up to the FA cup final, so we caught a taxi back to the apartments, seeing as it was starting to rain quite heavily. I didn't want to stay up too late, as we had an early start the next day, so I read my book a bit then went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="05-05-2002">
		<p>We were picked up at 8am, and it was already starting to drizzle. The coach picked up a few more passengers then dropped us off at the marina. We boarded our boat for the day, the Big Cat, which was a two level catamaran. It was much larger than the boat that took us out last week. On the way to Green Island there was a video about how to snorkel, and what was available on the island. We talked to the dive instructors about arranging a dive, and luckily the conditions were just about good enough. It was quite rough going out though, but I didn't feel as ill as last time. It was only a 45 minute trip this time.</p>
		<p>We hired some fins, and when we arrived the two diving instructors Carol and Kristin and Martin and I transferred to a smaller boat to go out to the dive site. The visibility was quite bad, which made the reef very atmospheric, and once the fish and coral were up close we could see them perfectly well. It was a good dive, and we saw a giant clam. Although the ride back to the main boat only took five minutes, Martin felt sea sick and was throwing up over the side. He was glad we were moored at an island this time, so could get on to steady land.</p>
		<p>By the time we had changed out of our wet suits, lunch was being served. There was a nice buffet of various salads, and I had some barbecued reef fish which was delicious. After lunch we went on to the island itself. It was quite small, and the ground was composed entirely of coral, although it had been worn down so much that it looked like sand. There were a few shops selling handicrafts and clothing, and an island resort with a pool. We however went to the crocodile park. It contained lots of aboriginal wood carvings, a giant turtle pool, and of course lots of crocodiles. The biggest one was called Cassius, and he was almost 6m long. After looking around, they had a crocodile show, which started off with them taking photos of everyone holding a baby crocodile so they could sell them to us afterwards. Martin and I didn't have a photo taken though. They then fed the turtles with dog biscuits, and the crocodiles with bits of chicken. They didn't throw the chicken this time though, but had them attached to the end of long wooden poles. The crocodiles didn't seem to see that well, as they usually had to have a few goes before managing to snap up their dinner.</p>
		<p>We went back to the boat after this, and got on the Yellow Submarine, which was a semi submersible that looked very much like the Beatles' sub. Our guide was a girl called Chelsea, who was very nice (friendly that is!). It was quite choppy and one lady had to go up on deck to be sick, but I thought it was fine. The visibility was still pretty poor, but we managed to see loads of fish as they threw in lots of fish food by the sub. There were soon hundreds of huge fish crowded us, and I was quite glad I wasn't diving at the time, as they seemed to be in a feeding frenzy!</p>
		<p>Once we got back, it was time for the Big Cat to leave for Cairns. I bought a T-shirt to remember the dive, and the ride back was so smooth that I almost dozed off. We arrived back in Cairns at 5 o'clock and went back to our apartment. I had a shower and cooked some noodles for dinner, then we went over to see what the others were doing this evening. Jess and Paul had arrived and were chatting to Nish, James and Tim. They had been in Bali, then went to Sydney and travelled up to Cairns on the Greyhound coach. They were just settling in this evening, and the others were going to watch the Australian 'Big Brother', which they've become quite addicted to! Martin and I watched Return of the Jedi instead.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="06-05-2002">
		<p>The second part of our two day package was a trip to Kuranda village. We left at 8:30 in the morning, and were taken to the sky rail terminal just outside Cairns. From here, we got on board a cable car to take us to Kuranda. There were two women from England in the same car as us to start with. The trip was really nice, travelling above the rainforest canopy as it ascended over the great dividing range, dipping in and out of clouds. There were two stops along the way, the first being a short boarded walk around the rainforest. We had a guide who was very chatty and showed us what lots of different trees were. We then got the sky rail to the next stop, which had a lookout point over the Baron Falls and a rainforest information centre. It was starting to rain a little, and the whole day alternated between rain and sun.</p>
		<p>The final stop was at Kuranda, where we caught the free bus to the village. We hadn't booked anything to do in Kuranda, although some of the other people on the tour had arranged to see some aboriginal dancing. We wandered around the town, which was pretty small. For a morning snack we found a place selling 'Real German Tucker', and had a very nice crocodile hot dog. We then went into one of the many shops which called themselves aboriginal museums, but were actually just selling lots of aboriginal handicrafts and traditional artefacts, including didgeridoos. The owner of the shop was very friendly, and let us try out lots of the didgeridoos. He also spent quite a while teaching us the basics of how to play them. Martin ended up buying one, and I got a CD of how to play the didgeridoo.</p>
		<p>We left our purchases at the shop, while we spent the rest of the afternoon strolling around, looking at the shops. Just before lunch we went to the local shooting range, which was inside a big ship shaped building. We got to shoot Magnum 44s at targets, which was quite a lot of fun. I couldn't believe how much recoil they had. We then had lunch at the Rainforest restaurant, which overlooked the rainforest as you might expect. We had lasagne and chips, with some red wine.</p>
		<p>We caught the train back to Cairns, along the original railway line carved out of the rainforest and mountain side by men with pickaxes at the end of the last century. The carriages were quite old, and still had leather seats which was quite nice. There was an interesting commentary and the scenery was lovely. The trip took an hour and three quarters, and as we pulled into Cairns Central it started to pour down with rain. Luckily, we had a coach to take us back to Reef Gateway.</p>
		<p> ate some noodles for dinner, and chatted to Mum and Dad seeing as it was a bank holiday at home as well as here. In the evening we went over to the Cock and Bull for a game of darts, and met all the others, who were having dinner there. Martin and I then left to go to the cinema. We saw the new Arnie film, Collateral Damage, which was very disappointing, and surprisingly for Arnie it was quite boring. It quite interesting getting to the cinema though, as the shopping centre was closed, so we had to walk around the back through the dark car park to get in.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="07-05-2002">
		<p>I got into the hospital at 9am for the ward round. We started off with Simon and Kate, and Dr Mantha turned up at one point, said Simon was doing very well by himself, and then left. Heike joined us halfway through. By 11:30 Heike and I were very hungry, so went down to the hospital canteen for lunch. This was much cheaper than the cafe we had been going to, and I had a steak and mushroom dish with some rice. We then went to the lunchtime teaching session which was on antibiotic resistance. It wasn't that helpful to us. Kate had agreed to watch me examine a patient every day, so I did a respiratory examination on a man with lung cancer. She said I got a gold start for my performance! It was very helpful though.</p>
		<p>When I got home, Martin and I went into town. He got a prepaid SIM card for his mobile, and we bought another internet access card. I was hungry again, so I got a lamb kebab and then a McDonald's ice cream cone for 50 cents. I remember living off them last time I was here. We came back to the flat and lounged around until bed time, with a brief interruption where we tried to venture out to the cinema but it was raining too much.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="08-05-2002">
		<p>I stayed in today and revised haematology. Martin was in the hospital from 8am until 6:30 pm. In the evening we went over to the Cairns student digs for a wine tasting. It was quite fun, and we met lots of the local students, plus some of their friends. After the wine was finished, they went on to port. Martin and I were the last to leave at about 1am, after Rhianna, the host, had got very drunk and finished showing us all her photo albums.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="09-05-2002">
		<p>Martin and I had lunch in the hospital canteen, then went to the library for a while. In the afternoon I met Kate to practice cardiovascular examinations. We went into town afterwards, and I had a big hot dog from the shopping centre food court. We noticed that Ice Age was being shown in the cinema, so we went in to watch it. It had some funny moments, especially when the squirrel was on, but otherwise it was a pretty mediocre film. It was late night shopping, so by the time we got out of the cinema we were still able to get some groceries.</p>
		<p>When we got back to the flat, I went round to see the others who were watching Big Brother. They were excited about seeing the Big Brother Uncut episode later on tonight, but first we went over to the Cock and Bull. Unfortunately, the dart board was in use, so we sat outside and chatted for a while. We got back in time for Big Brother, which was quite funny. By the time it finished, I was quite hungry so I had a chicken thing with chips before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="10-05-2002">
		<p>I didn't do much during the day, but in the evening we went out to meet some friends that Nish, Tim and James had met while they were in Sydney. Raoul and Emily were medical students from Nottingham on their elective. However, they had already passed their finals, so were having much more of a holiday.</p>
		<p>We went to a pub on the Esplanade for dinner, which was very nice. I had a pizza, and we shared quite a few jugs of beer. Afterwards we went over to PJ O'Brien's, which was already pretty packed. There was a live band playing, and they were quite good, playing quite a lot of popular songs. We all played James at pool, and he thrashed every one of us. We also drank rather a lot, which probably had a bit to do with me thinking I hadn't tried Bunderberg rum for a long time... In any case, the end result was me dancing madly, with the others either shaking around a bit or looking at me bemusedly. I ended up dancing with this mad Australian woman, who seemed very excitable. You really had to be there to appreciate it.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="11-05-2002">
		<p>I spent the day reading my book. I've almost finished it now, and it's getting quite exciting! We went over to the others room to watch some TV in the evening, which was a programme about a crazy Australian wildlife expert wrestling with crocodiles and getting bitten by snakes and lizards! On the subject of crazy people, Nish, Jess, Martin and I watched 'A Beautiful Mind' at the cinema. It was about Russell Crowe going schizophrenic, and was very good. We seem to have broken our streak of finding bad films!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="12-05-2002">
		<p>We caught a taxi to the marina this morning to board the Falla, a sailing ship. We were going to spend a day on the reef, with a couple of dives thrown in. The boat was pretty large, but not as big as the Ragamuffin in the Whitsundays. There were about 20 guests and five crew - Eric, the captain; Becs and Andy, diving instructors; George, who was also a diving instructor, but spent the day serving drinks, and was also a girl despite the name; and Preston, a dive instructor trainee.</p>
		<p>The trip out was quite bumpy, despite the day being lovely. It was very sunny, with a light breeze, but the waves were still quite big. We travelled out to the outer reef again, and it took us two hours. Unfortunately, even though they put the sails up we had the motor running the whole time to help speed us along. It would have been nice to just sail for a while. However, it was quite exciting being on the deck of a sailing ship again, with the waves breaking over the bow (sometimes). I felt all right, but Martin was sick four times during the day. Once on the way there, once after a dive, another time during a dive (into his regulator!), and again on the way back. At the end of the trip he said he felt very hungry!</p>
		<p>Becs took us on the first dive, which was fantastic - the best one so far in Australia. The water was just warm enough, and visibility was pretty good. The most exciting part of the dive for me was near the beginning, where we saw a huge ray (it must've been as big as my car), swimming around in the distance. It was quite an awesome sight, especially when it noticed us and darted off with amazing speed. We also saw two white tipped reef sharks that were lying on the sea bed. One of them was about 3m long. When they saw us, they lifted off and glided away very elegantly. I also saw gobies, some barramundi, and lots of other reef life. We had a nice long dive of about 40 minutes.</p>
		<p>We got back to the boat just in time for lunch. There was a buffet of pasta, potato salad, cold meats and chicken breasts, which filled me up nicely. After we'd eaten the boat moved over to moor near a coral cay - a small sandy island composed of worn down coral that looked like a beach in the middle of the sea. Most of the guests went over to the cay to do some snorkelling, but we joined a couple from Germany who had just qualified, and Andy and Preston to do another dive. This one was quite different as we didn't go deeper than 3m the whole time. Sometimes it was difficult to make sure you didn't surface, and occasionally I had my head down by the bottom and felt my fins kicking in air - quite odd. We did see some good wildlife though - some lion fish, sea stars, clown fish, and a giant clam which I touched. I stroked my fingers along the edge of its mouth, which felt very smooth, and the clam closed up. It was quite slow though, so I wasn't really in danger of getting eaten.</p>
		<p>After the dive and getting out of our dive gear we were taken over to the coral cay on a small motorised dinghy. Captain Eric gave us a bit of a talk about the reef, telling us how big it was, what coral was composed of, and how the cay was formed. We then snorkelled back to the boat. It was quite crowded, with twenty of us snorkelling in a group, but we did get to see a blue spotted ray, and hold a sea cucumber and a sea pineapple, which is actually a knobbly orange sea cucumber.</p>
		<p>The trip back was a little bumpy too, but I didn't feel too bad. I met a girl on board who was originally from Bromley and went to Langley Park. She was six years older than me though, so we wouldn't have known any of the same friends. On the way back they gave us some fresh fruit, then some cheese and wine, which was very nice as we sat out on deck watching the sun lowering in the sky.</p>
		<p>In the evening we watched the Big Brother evictions, and then Tomorrow Never Dies.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="13-05-2002">
		<p>I had a breakfast of coffee and a sausage roll in the hospital cafe, and then went to renal outpatients for the morning and saw lots of interesting patients. Unfortunately, I learnt that Dr Mantha's first name is Murty, not Munty, which doesn't sound quite as funny. I met Heike and Rhianna in the canteen for lunch, and then went home. Martin had spent the morning in, and when I got back I found Tim sunbathing by the pool, pretending to revise some endocrinology. I finished off reading my book this afternoon, all 1200 pages of it. It was excellent, but now I have to read the next two which are just as big!</p>
		<p>Martin and I went to the Cock and Bull for dinner, where I had a lovely chicken Kiev. We played a few games of darts, and on the way home we met Tim, Nish and Paul just coming out. We all went back to the pub and had another drink.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="14-05-2002">
		<p>I woke up this morning at 8 o'clock with a phone call from home. It was very nice to hear from Mum and Dad, although I had been planning on sleeping in until the mid day teaching. As I was up I decided to go in for the ward round, but I did phone Steven first. The ward round wasn't too interesting, but the teaching was quite good on perioperative management of diabetes. The best bit though was the free pizza from the drug reps.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon Martin and I went into town. We went to a costume hire shop to look for some outfits for the preview showing of Star Wars tomorrow. The shop had some great Jedi costumes, and Martin looked very funny as Yoda. We reserved the outfits for tomorrow. I then went to have a hair cut at the same place as last time. The girl who cut my hair, Cathy, was from Ireland and was on a working holiday travelling round Australia. She took a very long time going over and over my hair, snipping off the tiniest bits, and it looked very good. Little did I realise that I was actually a guinea pig for the bosses to check whether she was a good enough hairdresser. When she finished, two other hair dressers came over and inspected her work to check it was up to scratch, which was quite embarrassing. However, I did get the hair cut for free!</p>
		<p>After this, we did some grocery shopping, then went back to the apartment. I cooked some dinner, and did some revision, and then we went over to the Cock and Bull again for some drinks.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="15-05-2002">
		<p>Star Wars day! The preview comes out at midnight, and we've all got tickets. We went into town to pick up our costumes from a shop behind the main shopping center. Nish and I dressed up as Jedi Knights, Martin was Yoda, and Jess was Darth Vader. She looked very funny - I'd never seen the Dark Lord with a handbag and a fluffy pink purse before! Before we got dressed up we went to the Cock and Bull for dinner. I had already eaten, so I just had a huge chocolate pudding. I could only eat half of it.</p>
		<p>We walked down to the cinema at about 11pm, so luckily there weren't too many people about. It was a bit odd walking through the town centre dressed up though. When we got to the cinema we felt much better. There was a news crew doing some filming there, and they asked to film us walking in. When we went in to the cinema we got a few claps, and then these girls came and asked if they could have their photos taken with us. This time when we stood up at the front of the cinema, everyone cheered! The film was really good, and the audience had a nice atmosphere. We caught a taxi home afterwards.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="16-05-2002">
		<p>I went to return the costumes at lunch time, then just had time to cook some lunch before Tim, Nish, Paul and I went to the beach. We caught a bus from behind the apartments to Palm Cove, which was about half an hour drive away. It was a gorgeous day, and we spent a nice afternoon playing Frisbee, swimming in the sea, and just sunbathing.</p>
		<p>In the evening Martin and I went to the Cock and Bull for dinner, and I had another chicken Kiev. We went back to Tim and Nish's room and watched some TV before bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="17-05-2002">
		<p>Tim and Nish left for Bangkok this morning, and Jess and Paul went to Kuranda. I did some revision, and played some more Jedi Knight. We went to Charlie's for dinner, and it hadn't really changed from last time I was there. We sat outside by the pool, and had a very nice buffet with enormous prawns, mussels and oysters.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="18-05-2002">
		<p>We didn't do much during the day. In the evening we went over to the Cock and Bull to play some darts, and then at 11 o'clock we walked down to town to go to PJ O'Briens. The live band was there again, and we had fun dancing 'til 3am.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="19-05-2002">
		<p>I woke up quite late, but surprisingly didn't feel too bad after last night. Jess and Paul had gone out to the reef to do some snorkelling, while Martin and I stayed home and did some reading. We went over to the others room to watch the Big Brother evictions in the evening, then went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="20-05-2002">
		<p>Not much happening these days. Just revising and reading my book. We went to an Italian restaurant on Lake Street for dinner called Damaris, and although we got there at about 8 o'clock the waiter didn't seem sure whether they were open or just about to close. After checking with the chef he decided that we could come in to eat. We were the only people there, and we sat outside on the covered veranda next to the street.  I had some mussels and a seafood pizza, with some wine. It was quite nice, and we got some vouchers for 10% off the bill next time we visit, so we might have to go back.</p>
		<p>After dinner we wanted to have a little walk, and so we wandered into the town centre. We ended up in PJ O'Briens again, but only stayed for one drink. There was no band tonight.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="21-05-2002">
		<p>It would have been a bit late if I was at home, but I went out shopping for a birthday present for Steven today. There wasn't really anything suitable for a proper present. I was thinking of getting some Koala cuff-links, but nowhere seemed to sell anything like them. I ended up getting him a beer cooler, in the hopes of finding something better later or when I get home.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="22-05-2002">
		<p>Still didn't go into the hospital, but we're getting quite a lot done at home. We went through one of the past papers on the internet, which wasn't too bad. In the evening we went back to Damaris to get our 10% discount. We had a nice starter of assorted nibbles, and then I had a lasagne. When we got back we found that 'The Evil Dead 3' had just started, so of course we had to watch that. Very entertaining as per usual. We then played cards for a while and listened to some music.</p>
		<p>I got an e-mail from Adrian saying how much he's enjoying listening to our CD collections on my hi-fi, and now I'm itching to listen to music on better speakers than my laptop's. We're also trying to organise a white water rafting trip with Chia, but she's not replying to her e-mail at the moment. I certainly hope we don't end up missing each other again.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="23-05-2002">
		<p>We went over to Jess and Paul's room this evening to watch Big Brother with them, and so they could give us some food as they're leaving tomorrow. No account of Australia could be complete without a mention of their television. In spite of having multiple channels, including three movie channels, there are very few good programs to watch, and they tend to be repeated every few days. The only good things we've found are Big Brother, Neighbours (just so we can spoil things for Neighbours watchers back home) and a daytime TV talk show called Beauty and the Beast. The adverts are still as bad as they were six years ago, although now they have awful advert programs which last half an hour in a shopping channel type format, and they're repeated almost daily. The most memorable adverts (and the funniest/weirdest) are the Bras Bras Bras ad, and the rug advert with the guy on a flying carpet. I can't wait to get back to good old Sky One!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="24-05-2002">
		<p>At last we heard from Chia! She had been waiting to see if her friend could come as well before she contacted us, and as it turns out she'll be coming alone. We booked some rafting for Sunday, and arranged for her to stay in our apartment. I had a good go at tidying up the flat, as it really looked like a pig sty. It's much better now, but I bet it'll be filthy again before we leave.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="25-05-2002">
		<p>I got up at 9am and read my book until Chia arrived at eleven. She brought over some chocolates. I cooked us all a quick lunch of corned beef noodles, then we left to get picked up by Blazing Saddles - YeeHaa! We were to spend the afternoon horse riding in the rainforest near Palm Cove. I had a horse called Bella, Martin rode a white horse called Jasmina who seemed to follow Bella everywhere, and Chia rode Peter.</p>
		<p>After a few brief instructions we set off. It was really fun, and once we'd got used to riding we got to trot and canter. I felt a little sore after trotting, but after two hours of riding it started to feel pretty comfortable. Halfway through we walked up to a lookout point with nice views across the sea. One of the guides pointed out Elton John's house to us. Martin's horse followed mine all the time, and tried to bite any other horse that came nearby! It was quite startling when my horse decided to have a wee - it wouldn't move when I wanted it to, then suddenly it sounded like a waterfall beneath me. It was also a bit disturbing when the horse in front of me went for a number 2!</p>
		<p>Once we got back to the stables we had some pizza slices and one of the guides played his didgeridoo. We had a go with some bull whips, trying to make them snap, and to avoid hitting ourselves with them.</p>
		<p>In the evening we went into town to find some dinner. After walking alone the Esplanade a few times, trying to find somewhere reasonably cheap and not completely packed, we ended up walking up to near the shopping centre and eating at a place called Verdi's. I had a nice spaghetti carbonara. We were quite tired afterwards, so we went back home.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-05-2002">
		<p>After a few changes to our plans we ended up spending half a day white water rafting on the Barron river. The reason we didn't spend the whole day is because Chia's friend from Darwin had flown in for the day, and had to catch a flight back in the afternoon. We had originally wanted to raft on the Tully river, which are Grade 4 rapids, but for some reason the Tully had been drained. Something to do with a hydroelectric plant I think. We drove up to the Barron river which is about 20 minutes away, and had a bit of a safety talk on the way there.</p>
		<p>The company we went with is called R 'n' R. The four of us were joined by a couple of Australians, and together with our guide, Jeff, we headed off down the river. The first couple of rapids were quite tame, but they got a bit more exciting as we went on. Jeff was very good, and we all managed to stay in the raft, apart from the very mild rapids which we could swim down. We saw another raft get flipped as it was trying to surf at the bottom of some rapids, which was quite amusing. On the way back we stopped off at a pub where we were given a burger.</p>
		<p>In the evening we went to Charlie's for dinner. Chia loved it, and couldn't get enough oysters. However, even she couldn't match my fifty oysters! The meal was really good.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-05-2002">
		<p>I woke up at six in the morning with Chia banging on the door. She was leaving for the airport, and reception hadn't opened yet, so she wanted to leave her key with us. She also gave us some ice cream which made it worth the early wakening. We were picked up by Foaming Fury this morning for another day of white water, although today we were going in kayaks rather than rafts. There were two guides, John and Connor (I think they were a bit too old to have been named after Terminator 2 though), four trainee guides, and an Austrian girl (who was very attractive - she won $500 in a wet T-shirt competition) on her gap year called Elizabeth, so the group was nice and small.</p>
		<p>We drove down to the Russell River, which is about an hour away, and John gave us a commentary about the countryside as we went. We arrived at their base camp, which was a big shack, where we were greeted by a friendly but very shaggy dog. If you scratched its bottom, its hind legs went all wobbly and it fell over. We had a cup of coffee to wake up, and a nice platter of cheese and crackers, and some sticky chocolate cakes. The trainee guides set off first with a lot of equipment, then we followed on. I had to carry one of the inflatable kayaks in a big backpack, which was a bit awkward seeing as I was trekking through the rainforest in my diving boots.</p>
		<p>Connor gave us a rainforest talk as we walked through, and picked some different fruits to taste. The walk took about forty five minutes, and by the time we got to the launching site we were all quite hot and sweaty. While the guides pumped up the kayaks, Martin, Liz and I went for a swim in the river. The water was quite cold, but very refreshing. When we got out I realised that I had a leech attached to my leg. Liz was laughing at my worried expression, until she realised that she was also being vampired. I pulled it off with some difficulty, and flung it into the river.</p>
		<p>Martin and I shared one kayak, with Martin steering in the back to start off with. We had a really great time, especially once Martin had worked out how to steer the boat, and some of the rapids were very steep and exciting. Admittedly though, the only time we were tossed out of the boat was when I was steering, going backwards down a narrow waterfall! There were thirteen rapids overall, and halfway through John took us to a small waterfall called Rainbow Falls, due to the rainbows that could be seen in it. There was an aboriginal legend connected with it, and we found some ochre which we painted on ourselves to stop the river god from pulling us in! The shaggy dog had followed us throughout the rainforest walk, so to get back it had to ride in a raft with one of the guides. It seemed to enjoy it, until its raft was flipped and it had to swim down one of the rapids. It tended to stick to the shore after that!</p>
		<p>We rafted for about three hours, and when we got back we had a good barbecue of steaks and sausages. In the evening we went to the Hog's Breath Cafe for dinner where we had some fantastic steaks. They cook them for eighteen hours and char grill them which makes them really tender and juicy. Mine came with a topping of cheesy salsa and jalapeno peppers. Delicious. After this we went over to the Woolshed to meet Liz, and to see the Miss Backpacker competition, which she said she would definitely not be taking part in! It was supposed to start at eleven, but nothing much was happening, so we went over to PJ O'Briens, where the music was really bad. In the end we ended up going home.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="28-05-2002">
		<p>We had a bit of a lie in today, and after some lunch and Jerry Springer we went into town. I bought some presents for people at home, and Martin went shopping for T-shirts for his brother. We bumped into Elizabeth in the department store, and when we asked her how the Miss Backpacker competition went last night she grinned and said that not only did she get talked into taking part, but she actually won it!</p>
		<p>In the evening, after catching up on the latest happenings in Big Brother, we went over to the Cock and Bull for dinner. I had another chicken Kiev, and finally the waitresses recognised us and actually smiled. We played darts after eating, and were joined by a guy called Steve who drives one of the coaches down to Alice Springs. We beat him quite soundly! We were about to go home when another guy, called Nathan, wanted to play 301 with us. He had trouble understanding my name, and after telling him a few times, he said, "Sorry, I don't mean any offence, but I can't pronounce your name. Is it all right if I just call you Ian instead!" I won that game too, but it was a bit closer!</p>
		<p>I gave Mum a call when I got back, to have a last chat before I leave, and to check that I was going to be picked up when I get home!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="29-05-2002">
		<p>Spent the day tidying the flat, which took a lot longer than we expected, and packing. In the evening we went back to the Hog's Breath Cafe for one last delicious steak. We shared some potato wedges stuffed with cheese and bacon for starters, and then I had a steak with an avocado and creamy sauce. I went to bed quite early in anticipation of an early start tomorrow.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="30-05-2002">
		<p>As always, knowing that I had to get lots of sleep because we were getting up at 4.30 in the morning, I of course couldn't sleep at all. We caught a taxi to the airport, and checked in at 5:20. Martin picked up his blowpipes which airport security had been keeping for him, and then had to pay a very hefty fee for his overweight luggage - £180! He almost left his didgeridoo behind as well. We had some breakfast in the departure lounge - I had a hot dog and a cup of tea, then we boarded our flight to Sydney. We were originally going on a 767, but that was cancelled, so we ended up on quite an empty 747. There was a girl put in the seat next to us, and when she tried to move to a free row one of the stewards told her off, saying that she had to stay where she was for take off otherwise the plane would be unbalanced!</p>
		<p>The flight was pretty uneventful. We had some breakfast, but there wasn't time for any inflight entertainment. I read a Terry Pratchet book to while away the couple of hours. We then had to wait in transit for five hours for our BA flight to Bangkok. On the flight we had emergency exit seats with an unbelievable amount of leg room. This bliss was only tempered by the two annoying small children sitting behind us. When they weren't kicking the backs of our chairs they were running riot round the plane, trying to play with the emergency exit doors. We didn't get much chance to rest. We had personal TV screens again, which could show a real-time map of our location. It seemed a bit ridiculous after a few hours into the flight to see that we hadn't even got back as far as Cairns!</p>
		<p>We spent an hour or so in transit in Bangkok, where there wasn't much to do, but we weren't there for long. I bought some tuk tuk shaped chocolates for Mum and Dad. I managed to sleep for about seven hours of the rest of the flight back to London, and Mum and Dad were waiting to pick me up from the airport. It was quite cold outside!</p>
	</entry>
</diary>
