<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Greece" date="09-2008">
	<entry date="13-09-2008">
		<p>We had an early flight from Gatwick, and so woke up at 4.15am. After a quick shower, the taxi came to pick us up at 4.45. He was a few minutes late, as he’d been driving up and down the wrong side of Warren Road. We had decided to stay at my parents’ house, partly because it would be cheaper than a hotel near the airport, and partly because Simon could sleep in the spare room, and so be spared from my snoring for an extra night! I had been trying to get used to a mandibular advancement device for the last couple of nights, but it was so uncomfortable that I hoped Simon’s ear plugs would be enough to let him sleep.</p>
		<p>The taxi took about forty minutes to get to Gatwick, and the driver was very talkative. Simon said I did well to keep the conversation going at such an early hour. I’d rather have been dozing, but suppose that would have been quite rude. He was rather overweight, and told us he had recently joined a gym to try and get in shape. I’m not sure how well he’ll do, with all the fried breakfasts he said he eats.</p>
		<p>We got to the airport at 5.40, two hours before departure, and were shocked to see the length of the check-in queue. We thought it might be pretty quiet at this time of the morning, but as all the Thomas Cook flights were grouped together in one queue it took us almost an hour to get through. A couple of times people tried to push in just behind us, and they were swiftly reprimanded by a harassed mother with two small children.</p>
		<p>Once through security we went looking for some breakfast. Simon bought a paper, then we went to a café for a fry up. There were some nice views of planes taxiing and taking off. We were dismayed when we discovered that we could have had an extra couple of hours in bed. Our flight was delayed until 9.10. There were lots of delays because the airline XL had gone bust yesterday, leaving thousands of passengers stranded around the world. We passed the time browsing round the shops, and had a coffee and read of the paper. Simon was glad not to miss his usual Saturday morning routine!</p>
		<p>We ended up eventually taking off at 9.50, with the captain promising to push the engines at make up some time. The flight was reasonably smooth, except over the Alps. They gave us a bit of breakfast, and I watched Iron Man on a small screen at the front. I wasn’t going to pay for their headphones though, so I watched it without sound!</p>
		<p>We touched down in Thessaloniki at about 3.15 pm, and after picking up our bags we went to find the Neilson rep. They had set up a stand outside the airport, with water, fruit and doughnuts. What a nice way to be welcomed! We were directed to our coach, and I listened to my iPod for much of the 90 minute to our resort – the Anastasia.</p>
		<p>On arrival we had a slight worry when the rep didn’t have a room key for us. However, he went off and found it, and we took our luggage up. Our room was on the first floor, with a balcony overlooking the sea. It was very pleasant, and had a small TV and a fridge.</p>
		<p>Dinner started at 7.30, so we had an hour or so to relax by the pool. It was still very sunny and hot, and we had a nice swim. The pool was very good. It was pretty big, with a smaller children’s pool attached to it. There were plenty of deck chairs around, and a bar off to the side.</p>
		<p>We were both very impressed with dinner. All but three of the evening meals were included in the holiday, and the followed the same basic format. Everything was buffet style, with lots of Mediterranean salads, cold meats, tzatziki, cheese, sundried tomatoes and olives. The cooked dishes varied each night according to the dinner theme. Tonight was a Mediterranean style evening, and I had some fantastic squid which was fried on a hotplate. We each had a beer with dinner, and then we headed off to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="14-09-2008">
		<p>We got up late and went down to breakfast at about 9.30. Again there was a huge amount of food to choose from. I had a couple of sausages and an omelette. Simon had cereal and a very big chocolate doughnut. My stomach was a bit upset, and I had to open my bowels several times of the next couple of days. We were quite shocked to find out that the plumbing was too narrow to take toilet paper, so we were expected to put the used paper into a bin instead. For the first few days we deliberately went to use the toilet in reception instead of using our own.</p>
		<p>At ten o’clock we had a welcome meeting by the pool bar. The reps introduced themselves and the various activities on offer. We signed up for beginner lessons in windsurfing and waterskiing. Simon decided to go for daily group tennis lessons, and I booked a couple of dives on Tuesday.</p>
		<p>By the time the welcome meeting was over, it was almost time for lunch. By now we knew that we were going to be well fed this holiday. I ate too much every meal, because I wanted to try a bit of everything on offer.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon we played a bit of badminton on the lawn between the resort and the beach. It was a bit windy though, so we couldn’t really play properly. We had a swim in the pool, and Simon tried using the Scuba gear. He said that he quite enjoyed it, but didn’t really want to go for a full blown dive. I read my book by the pool while Simon went for his tennis assessment. He was put into group C, and was a bit miffed that he hadn’t been assigned to the best group. We went to a mix and mingle cocktail party before dinner, where we had a couple of glasses of punch and several canapés. The tennis instructor was there, and asked Simon whether he would be liked to be moved up to group D instead.</p>
		<p>The dinner theme for this evening was a Greek night.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="15-09-2008">
		<p>We had an early start today, as our waterskiing lesson was booked for 8.40. We had a nice, filling breakfast, and then made our way down to the beach, only to find that the waterskiing had been cancelled for beginners. The water was too choppy. The weather was still nice though, so we spent most of the day by, or in, the pool. Simon had an afternoon tennis lesson where he covered ground strokes.</p>
		<p>Dinner was not included tonight, so we took a shuttle bus into the local village, Skioni. The village is very small, and we had a walk down to the shore front and out on to the harbour. There were lots of restaurants on the front, and most of them had diners from our resort. We went to a pizza place on another guest’s recommendation, and the food was excellent. A couple of reps from the resort were moonlighting there as waiters. The portions were huge, and I could only eat about half of my dinner. I had a big dish a baked cheese with meat and vegetables, and Simon had an enormous pizza.</p>
		<p>We sat next to a nice couple who were also staying at the Anastasia. Chris was a retired doctor, and his wife Maggie was a biochemist. They were very friendly, and told us about their company which provides medical aid to El Salvador.</p>
		<p>There are quite a few mosquitoes about, and I’d been bitten three times on my back and shoulder. The bits were inflamed and very itchy for a few days. We were also often pestered by wasps while eating or sitting out.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="16-09-2008">
		<p>I had to be in reception to be picked up for diving at 8.30. After dragging myself out of bed I managed to grab a quick chocolate doughnut for breakfast. Roy, the diving instructor, picked us up in his Land Rover and drove us to the dive hut on the other side of the peninsula. On the way we picked up a couple of other divers from a different hotel, and also stopped off at a bakery for a chance to supplement our packed lunches. I hadn’t thought to bring my wallet, as everything goes on our tab in the resort, so I had to make do with a cheese and tomato roll and a banana.</p>
		<p>It was a nice sunny day. We loaded the dive gear on to the boat, and it took about 10 minutes to get to the first dive site. There were four divers in our group, plus a couple of others doing their Advanced Open Water course. We had to do a short dive test, as none of us had dived in the last six months. This included clearing our masks, and I got a lot of water up my nose.</p>
		<p>The water was reasonably calm, warm and clear. Although we saw some interesting things, most of the dive was quite dull. Both dives were along walls, with sponges and a few fish. We saw an octopus, a disco doris, starfish, moray eel, and a big mussel. There was also a pretty cool thermocline, which is a level at which the water temperature suddenly drops. You could see it as a hazy sheet in the water. The second dive was similar, but I felt quite nauseous by the end for some reason, and it took me a while to feel better.</p>
		<p>In the evening we went back to Skioni, and back to the same pizza place. I had a massive calzone this time. A storm broke while we were eating, and it was quite dramatic watching the lightning over the sea. However, as it moved towards us we got a bit wet, until the staff lowered the restaurant shutters. We had quite q while to wait until the return shuttle, so we stayed for a coffee and some Greek yogurt and honey for dessert. We chatted with the reps, who asked whether we were still at university. One of them lives in Oxford, and his grandparents own Boswells. The coffees and desserts were on the house, as we were repeat customers.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="17-09-2008">
		<p>After breakfast we headed down to the beach for our windsurfing lesson. We were in a group with two other guests, Nick and Val. We recognised them, as they usually sat on nearby deckchairs at the pool. The first part of the lesson was on the shore, using a simulator. We were taught how to get up on the board, pull the sail up into a stable position, and how to catch the wind. Then we got into the sea to put it into practice. The air was not especially warm at that time of the morning, so I was a bit anxious that the water would be cold. It was actually quite nice though.</p>
		<p>It was quite hard at first to keep my balance on the board, but I soon got the hang of standing up. There was hardly any wind, which made it easier to balance, but hard to actually move anywhere. The instructor was in a motorboat, and the waves of his wake kept tipping me off.</p>
		<p>Next up was our waterskiing lesson. Again we had some instruction on shore, and then took turns out on the water. I started off by holding on to a bar attached to the boat, so the instructors could tell me what to do. They were a bit gruff, and not as encouraging as the reps on the shore. The first time I stood up too quickly and fell flat on my face. I was getting lots of water over my face and in my mouth. It took a while for me to realise that the instructors were telling me to let go of the bar! It took a couple of goes before I could stand up properly, and then they let me have a go using the rope. I found it easier than hanging off the bar, and was having great fun, but it was over very quickly. It felt similar to normal skiing, and they said I looked good for my first attempt.</p>
		<p>Simon didn’t really enjoy it, as the guys in the boat were too abrupt and critical. He had been waterskiing before, and so started off by using the rope. Unfortunately he kept falling over, until he moved on to the bar, where he managed to stay up.</p>
		<p>After another big lunch we went to sit by the pool. I finished my first book, Portent by James Herbert, so went back to reading Churchill’s account of the Second World War. Simon had an afternoon tennis lesson, and got an ice cream and watched him practicing his volleys. He had been slightly disappointed by the lesson, as they hadn’t actually played any matches yet. This evening they had some doubles games organised though. I went along to spectate, and got chatting to some of the other players, who were all really nice. They encouraged me to have a go, even though I hadn’t played for years. I really wanted to play though, after watching Simon, so I joined in a doubles match. I wasn’t totally useless, and someone commented that I may not have played for years, but how did they know that I wasn’t a pro before then! Simon and I then teamed up for a game against two good players, and we beat them 3-1. I surprised myself getting my serves in, and we actually won my service game!</p>
		<p>Dinner was an ‘ethnic’ theme tonight. There was some sushi, duck a l’orange, chilli con carne and burritos. We had a bottle of wine with dinner.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="18-09-2008">
		<p>We had an improvers windsurfing lesson this morning. It was quite windy, and even worse the wind kept switching direction, so it was really difficult to control the board. I think I must have slightly strained my back yesterday, as it really hurt to lift the rig up today. I had a few attempts, but then spent the rest of the time just sitting on the board. It was still quite fun, just to float around watching the others practice. If was especially fun to watch the girls squealing before being knocked off by a big wave!</p>
		<p>My back actually became very painful for the rest of the day. I found it hard to walk, and started taking some diclofenac. We decided to try out the spa this afternoon. We sat in the Jacuzzi, and then had a swim in a lovely hot hydropool. This really helped my back.</p>
		<p>We went back into Skioni for dinner this evening. We tried a different restaurant, as I wanted to try a Greek place while we were here. It was a bit chilly to be sitting outside tonight. The restaurant was quite empty. We had a cheese and pastrami pie to start, and then I had a sis kebab and Simon had mousaka. We were joined for dinner by a small cat. The waiter didn’t seem to want us to have dessert, as he kept avoiding eye contact. When we eventually caught his attention and asked for the dessert menu, he brought us the bill instead. He did give us complimentary sambucas and yogurt and honey though.</p>
		<p>We had some time to kill before the coach pick up, so we had a short wander around the village. We walked down to the beach and stood watching the sea for a little while.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="19-09-2008">
		<p>Simon was in a tennis competition this morning, so I went down to watch him. They played doubles, and the tournament went on for a couple of hours. It was very hot and sunny. Simon was playing with a very good played called Peter. They were unlucky and got knocked out in the quarter finals though.</p>
		<p>My back was feeling a lot better, but still quite sore today. After lunch we sat by the pool, had ice creams, and Simon did fifty lengths. We then went back to the spa for half an hour. There was supposed to be a waterskiing demonstration this afternoon, but it was cancelled due to the rough water. We watched the end of the staff versus guests volleyball match though. The staff just won it in the end.</p>
		<p>After dinner I wrote up my diary, and then we went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="20-09-2008">
		<p>Simon was lovely had had brought along some balloons for my birthday. He got up while I was still asleep to blow them up and put them around the room. He gave me my birthday presents in bed: a DVD of Les Miserables and a nice rugby shirt. We couldn’t lie in bed for too long though, as we had to check out by 8.30. We had a quick breakfast, paid our tab, and then sat in the lobby for an hour to wait for the coach. I took the time to get up to date with my diary. I think we had been very lucky with the weather during the week. This morning was quite cool and cloudy, and apparently the forecast is for storms next week.</p>
		<p>We got rolls for lunch at the airport, then had a smooth flight back to Gatwick. Mum and Dad came to pick us home and take us home.</p>
	</entry>
</diary>