<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Greece" date="09-2011">
	<entry date="24-09-2011">
		<p>Our flight was scheduled to leave at 6.55 am from Gatwick, and Dad kindly gave us a lift. We left the house at 4.30! We checked in very quickly, although at the check in desk we were told that there weren't any seats left next to each other. We we pointed out that we had paid extra to sit together, they seemed to magically find some more seats. We were interested in the new signage at the airport, after watching a series about the current renovations at Gatwick.</p>
		<p>We had time to get a book and a newspaper, and I had a McDonald's burger for breakfast, then we had to rush to the gate as it said the plane was boarding. Typically, it was the furthest gate from the entrance. Although we were apparently boarding, we had to wait around for half an hour before anyone started getting on board.</p>
		<p>We were flying with Monarch airlines, and the plane looked quite old. The CRT televisions hanging from the ceiling looked pretty antiquated. There was hardly any leg room either. Because the Greek airport workers had decided to work to rule, we were delayed for an hour sitting on the tarmac. The flight itself wasn't too bad though, and they gave us a good breakfast.</p>
		<p>We arrived at Mitilini airport at about 1.30, and then had a two and a half hour drive across Lesvos to our resort in Skala-Erresos. It was a Neilson resort, called the Aeolian Village. Because of the time we arrived we didn't get any lunch, but Simon had brought some apricot flapjacks which kept us going.</p>
		<p>We each had an unfortunate suitcase incident today. When I unpacked, I realised that my shampoo had leaked during the trip. Luckily it hadn't got on my clothes, but it had covered everything in my wash bag. I rinsed everything out in the bathroom sink, then put it out to dry. In the meantime, Simon went into the bathroom and thought that I had left a nice foam heart on the floor for him. Actually, it was just the drains regurgitating te foam from my shampoo!</p>
		<p>Simon had a moment of supreme doziness when he managed to lock his padlock keys inside his suitcase. After a moment of panic, we went down to reception to ask for some help. They sent up a maintenance man who broke the lock in two seconds using a couple of screwdrivers. It's a handy trick to remember. Simon's decided to use combination locks from now on...</p>
		<p>After settling in to our room, we went down to the pool for a pre-dinner swim. It was nice to have a rectangular pool, so we could do some lengths. The other Neilson resorts we've been to have had weird blob-shaped pools, which are difficult to actually swim in. The water was pretty cold, but got bearable after about 20 lengths. I swam 60 lengths to work up a good appetite.</p>
		<p>We had a buffet dinner in the resort, and then had a stroll down to the beach. By now it was pitch black, so we couldn't even be sure that we were actually on the beach. However, the conditions were perfect for stargazing, and we could even see the Milky Way streaking across the sky.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="25-09-2011">
		<p>We had a latish buffet breakfast: pastries for Simon; sausages and bacon for me. Then we went down to the pool bar for the welcome meeting. We signed up for a bike ride in the afternoon, and I also signed up for group tennis lessons, and a night dive on Wednesday. I would eventually end up cancelling the dive, as I felt a bit chesty from a cold last week. We then sat by the pool for half an hour, before catching the end of the beach safety briefing, at which we signed up for intermediate level sailing lessons.</p>
		<p>My first tennis lesson as at noon. Although it was sunny, it didn't feel that hot as it was extremely windy. It made tennis a bit difficult, as from one side you only had to touch the ball for it to go flying down the court, whereas from the other side it often didn't even reach the net. The group was a bit oversubscribed today, so we spent the hour getting used to hitting the balls around, rather than being taught any specific techniques.</p>
		<p>Simon came along to watch the end of my lesson, then we went for lunch. I thin we both ate a bit too much, as we had to have a short siesta afterwards! It was good to be out of the full midday sun anyway.</p>
		<p>Once we had got up, we went down to the beach and took out a Bahia for about an hour. I was a bit nervous, as I couldn't really remember anything about sailing, and suddenly we were being blown about in a little boat, confronted with all these mysterious ropes and levers. Simon was very good and picked it up again quickly, even with a nervous back seat sailor to deal with. The wind was reasonably strong, and we got some good speed up at points. It was made more difficult by having a dodgy rudder that kept lifting out of the water.</p>
		<p>We were just about to come back in when a gust of wind caught us and we capsized. I got a bit miffed, as I had managed to stay standing in the boat, but Simon couldn't right it with me inside, so I had to get wet! In the end, we needed a staff member in a power boat to give us a hand. Only later did we find out that the best way to right a Bahia is to have one person pushing from inside it after all! Once the boat was upright, we noticed that the rudder had completely fallen off! Luckily we got a tow back to shore from the power boat.</p>
		<p>We both had time for a quick shower before heading down to the bike shed for our guided ride. We got kitted out in helmets and cycling gloves, and then went out on some very snazzy mountain bikes. We were in a group of about twenty, with one guide. We did a 7 km loop, through some very beautiful scenery, around the local village, and then stopped at a bridge where we saw lots of turtles. The temperature had dropped a bit, so it was a very pleasant ride. I did have a saddle shaped bruise on my bottom for a couple of days afterwards though!</p>
		<p>Before dinner we went to the mix and mingle drinks at the pool bar. We had some free (very weak) punch, and treated ourselves to a couple of nice mojitos. We also ended up chatting to a couple of nice, but slightly strange girls, called Jackie and El. They were both in my tennis group.</p>
		<p>We had another buffet dinner at the resort, and then had quite an early night. Simon had a very disturbed sleep, as a cyst on the top of his head had become very painful and throbbing.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-09-2011">
		<p>In the morning I had a tennis lesson, we were learnt the ground strokes. The wind was much calmer today, which was good for tennis practise. I only hit one ball out of the court, but it landed in somebody's garden!</p>
		<p>We had our first sailing lesson today, in a group of six. Our instructor, James, first went through tacking and gibing with us in an onshore simulator, then we went out in individual dinghies. The idea was to navigate around a triangle of buoys, round and round to practice our steering. I really had no idea what I was doing. I capsized the boat, and I couldn't even find the triangle! Nevertheless, James was very encouraging, and said that we had all improved greatly.</p>
		<p>After lunch I took another look at Simon's cyst, and saw that it had become infected. I lanced it in our room, and squeezed out a good amount of pus. It bled quite a lot, so Simon had to press a napkin against his head for about half an hour. The pain much much better afterwards though.</p>
		<p>We had a nap in the afternoon, and then took out a couple of kayaks. The wind had picked up, and some of the sailors and windsurfers looked very impressive, speeding along. We paddled along the shore to some nearby rocks. On the way back, Simon tied my kayak to the back of his and towed me along for a while. Unfortunately, it made me feel a bit seasick, so he had to stop! When we got back, I did some lengths in the pool while Simon read his book.</p>
		<p>We walked into Skala-Erresos for dinner. There were quite a few creatures flitting about beneath the street lamps. I thought they were bats, but they may well have been birds. There were also lots of cats roaming around the village. We had an alfresco dinner at a restaurant called 'Aubergine'. Our pizzas were enormous, and I couldn't finish mine. The village was very nice, and many of the restaurants were on stilts over the beach.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-09-2011">
		<p>We practised serving this morning. I wasn't very good. Simon came to watch, and got some good photos. At the end of the lesson we played a game called 'serving golf'. The idea was to count how many attempts it took to get eight serves in. I took 36 shots, so I'm obviously as bad as this as I am at real golf! My shoulder was aching a bit after serving for an hour.</p>
		<p>Our sailing lesson today was more of the same. This time I was much better, and actually managed to sail a good course around the triangle. I didn't capsize, but I must practise getting into and out of the boat, as I fell in the water both times.</p>
		<p>We were a few minutes late for our sailing lesson, as Simon's head had become sore again, and a couple of his lymph nodes had come up. We decided to go into the village to see the local doctor. However, once we got there we discovered that both doctor's surgeries were closed, even though it was during their opening hours. In the end we went to the pharmacy, where the pharmacist kindly sold us some antibiotics when I said that I was a doctor.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon Simon went out sailing, while I read my book in the pool bar. He wasn't out for that long, as it was very gusty. The staff were quite naughty as well, and gave him a racing boat to take out, which was quite unstable. When he brought it back in, he was just helping to put it away when the boom was caught by a gust of wind and smashed right into his cyst! He came to find me in the bar, with blood pouring out of his head.</p>
		<p>We went to the poolside reception area, and used their first aid kit. It wasn't very well stocked, so I cleaned his would with saline and a handful of napkins from the bar. He then had to wear a fetching dressing that looked like a bonnet tied round his head. Because the bandage under his chin was quite tight, he decided to round off the mad butler look with a black napkin between the strap and his chin, that looked like a little bow tie!</p>
		<p>We went back to Scala-Erresos for dinner, with Simon wearing his funny bonnet. We are in Samadhi restaurant, which was one of the ones on stilts,. It was very busy, as the staff at the resort had been recommending it to everyone. We waited half an hour for a table, having a drink at the bar next door. The food was good, and there were lots of cats again.</p>
		<p>Samadhi's shrimp, tomato and feta bake: small prawns, garlic, tomatoes, chopped and softened, chilli, olive oil and large cubes of feta, all baked in a dish. Yum!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="28-09-2011">
		<p>After breakfast we took a walk into Scala-Erresos. The weather was beautiful again today. I think we've been lucky, seeing as we came quite late in the season. We had a walk along the shore front and took some photographs. There were a couple of interesting statues, and still a lot of cats. We had to hurry back to catch the beginning of our sailing lesson. As Simon was injured, and I had a tennis lesson, we only went for the theory part of the lesson and left when they took out the boats.</p>
		<p>We covered volleys in the tennis lesson today. The group is nice, and everyone is very friendly. A lot of my shots were a bit wild, but I got a few good ones in. The lunch was a buffet as usual, and we took our time, having a coffee afterwards. Then we sat out in the reception lounge and played backgammon for a couple of hours. It took us a while to remember how to set up the board, which I thought was funny after I'd worked on a backgammon computer program for several months! It was very close, but Simon beat me three games to two.</p>
		<p>I had a long swim in the late afternoon, and then we went to a sailing theory lesson in the pool bar. It wasn't very interesting. We had dinner in the resort, and then wandered down to the pool bar to listen to some of the pub quiz. We were in time to hear the TV theme tune round, and got 7 out of 10. Wherever we go we seem to bump into Jackie, who always looks a bit drunk. Simon's getting rather irritated by her now!</p>
		<p>We watched a bit of the trial of Michael Jackson's doctor on Sky News before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="29-09-2011">
		<p>I'm writing this entry relaxing on a sun lounger by the side of the pool, just contemplating whether to go for a swim or have an ice cream. Decisions, decisions... On the other side of the pool the chefs have just started a hog roast for this evening's dinner. It's pretty quiet. There's only one person swimming, and many of the loungers are free. We've been surprised how quiet the pool has been all week, but I suppose most people are down on the beach. We've just had lunch, and played some more backgammon. Simon won again, 2 games to 1.</p>
		<p>I got the wrong time for my tennis lesson this morning, so ended up with the beginners rather than the improvers groups. That suited me just fine! We practised rallying, and running up to the net to volley. At the end of the lesson we were encouraged to sign up for the tournament tomorrow. I'm not going to, as it lasts over 3 hours, and I'd almost certainly be out very early on. It's funny how the staff are acclimatised to the weather. I thought it was hot this morning, but Chris the tennis coach was wearing a jumper.</p>
		<p>We had our final sailing lesson this morning, where we learnt how to come alongside another boat. Simon just came for the theory session, then went to the pool to read his book. I really enjoyed it, and felt much more confident today. At one point the wind dropped off though, so we spent about 10 minutes just drifting around. I hadn't realised, but doing these lessons count as a RYA level 2 yachting qualification, so I'll have to get a log book and get it it stamped tomorrow.</p>
		<p>I briefly examined a girl's foot that had become swollen, and advised her to see the doctor for some antibiotics.  Simon and I had a quick tennis knockabout before lunch, which was good fun. We had some nice rallies, and I was getting quite a few serves in. Unfortunately, Simon was wearing his flip flops, so he decided to play barefoot. After 10 minutes he had worn a large blister on his foot, so we had to stop.</p>
		<p>In the end, I went for a swim rather than have an ice cream. The water was pretty cold! We went back to Aubergine in Skala-Erresos for dinner. We were planning to go to a place on the waterfront that did nice looking burgers, but they were out of beef. Aubergine was also out of beef, and also out of hummus, salmon and lamb! I had a dish of extremely spicy baked feta for starter, and then chicken in a creamy sage and ouzo sauce. At first they forgot about our starters, so when they arrived with the main courses they had to take them away again. I think they remade fresh ones for us, but can't be sure. We were both pretty tired, so had a slow walk back to the resort.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="30-09-2011">
		<p>We took out a Bahia this morning, which is a two person dinghy. We took turns sailing up and down. It was very windy. We estimated it to be about a wind force 6, so the sailing was a little tricky. It didn't help that we were holding the tiller incorrectly, as we hadn't realised it should be done differently to a Pico. We managed to stay upright though.</p>
		<p>We moored the boat to a buoy, and were picked up in a power boat. However, instead of going straight back in, we had to zip around while the staff member helped beginners who had capsized their Picos. Everywhere we looked there seemed to be someone in the water. We felt particularly sorry for a man who kept struggling to right his boat, for it to then go over immediately on the other side. In the end, he climbed in the rescue boat with us, but ended up losing a shoe. We left his dinghy completely upside down in the water. Although we didn't fall in, we got pretty drenched by the spray from the power boat as we went back to shore.</p>
		<p>After lunch we played some backgammon over coffee, and then went down to the beach to watch the sailing regatta. It was very blustery, so we were glad we hadn't entered ourselves. We saw lots of boats going over, but it was hard to follow the race, as it all looked very chaotic from the shore. Nevertheless, we had a nice time watching, and each had an ice cream.</p>
		<p>We went up to the tennis courts for a knockabout, and ended up playing for two hours. We played one set, which Simon won 6-0, then had loads of rallies. My shots were improving by the end. I was very hot and aching afterwards, so I had a nice swim in the pool to cool off.</p>
		<p>In the evening we went to the awards presentation, which went on for ages. We really just wanted to get our level 2 RYA certificates, but had to wait until the end to pick them up. We then packed our suitcases ready for tomorrow.</p>
		<p>Jackie and El won an award for 'moaners of the week'...</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="01-10-2008">
		<p>We left the Aeolian Village at 9.30. It was actually a little chilly this morning, so we were glad to have had such great weather all week. The coach took a different way back, which was very twisty, and we both felt slightly queasy by the time we arrived at the airport.</p>
		<p>The flight was on time, and we got a meal on board. Amazingly it was hotter when we got back to England than it was when we left Greece. Simon's dad kindly picked us up.</p>
	</entry>
</diary>