<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Hong Kong and China" date="03-2008">
	<entry date="21-03-2008">
		<p>We had a flight from Gatwick in the evening. We were flying with Oasis, the budget Asian airline, and little did we know at the time but we were very fortunate to get back at the end of the holiday. The airline went bust the day after we got home!</p>
		<p>We had seats at the back of the plane, and it was very cramped with little leg room. Adam was very unfortunate, and had a child sitting behind him who kept kicking the back of his seat the whole way to Hong Kong. I didn't manage to get much sleep, but I did enjoy watching the monitor displaying the plane's location. I thought the graphics were cool, and it looked like was flying in towards the plane from outer space!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="22-03-2008">
		<p>We got to Hong Kong at 4pm, and caught the MTR to Hong Kong city. I commented on the LEDs in the train that showed it's current location. I thought they were cool! We caught a taxi from the train station, but our Chinese wasn't very good, as the taxi driver had trouble finding Ramin's building. On the way it started to bucket down. It didn't really matter though, as it was still warm enough to go out in just a T-shirt.</p>
		<p>Ramin's flat is on the 33rd floor of Hollywood Towers, in Hollywood Road, just by Mon Ma temple. It was nice to see a friendly face at the end of our journey, and also to have a nice shower. After freshening up we all went out to a local bar. We stood outside and had a beer. While we were chatting, a beggar came up and pestered us for ages. He didn't quite seem to get the whole begging concept though, as he kept on trying to give us a coin.</p>
		<p>Later, we caught the Star Ferry over to Kowloon and went to a bar near the top of the Peking One building. It was a very classy bar, although getting there was a bit disorientating as the stairs were very dark, and there were lots of bright LEDs and mirrors. We had a bottle of champagne and some peanuts and watched the laser show over the harbour. It seemed a bit lame, but it may have just been a bit too misty to see it properly.</p>
		<p>Afterwards we went for dinner in a restaurant inside a shopping center. We sat in a smaller part of the restaurant, as a wedding party had taken over the main room. We had some sweet and sour deep fried prawns, seafood noodles, vegetables, and pork dim sum. Ramin's vegetarian, but he'll happily eat seafood.</p>
		<p>Once we finished dinner, we caught a taxi to Lan Kwai Fong. There was a great atmosphere: lots of bars bustling with people, and drinkers spilling out over the street. We had a beer in an Irish bar called the Whisky Priest, where there was an English football match on TV. I have no idea who was playing though! Then we walked to another bar above Lan Kwai Fong. This place was heaving with Westerners, and playing some cheesy 80s music. We had a couple more drinks here, and by now I was getting quite drunk. Finally we went to the Feather Boa. This was a surprisingly hidden Bohemian den, tucked away behind an unmarked door. The place was painted all blue, and seemed to contain a lot of antique furniture. I thought the Chinese barmaid looked a bit like Wiebke, but that may have just been the drink. I had a lychee daiquiri, followed by a quite horrible Martini. They didn't really like me taking photos in there.</p>
		<p>We staggered out of bar and went to get kebabs. There were some peculiar people in there, who told Ramin that he couldn't have been a man in his previous life, because he didn't have a skin crease in his elbow. I remember the chilli sauce being really rather hot. We went back to Ramin's and watched Max and Paddy's Road to Nowhere while eating up the chocolate fingers I'd brought from England. I then gave Simon a call, and went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="23-03-2008">
		<p>I slept very well. It seems that getting blind drunk is a great way to get around jet lag! We all got up at 11am and went to a cafe for some brunch. I had corned beef hash with poached eggs – just the cure for a hung over stomach. The cafe was Western style, with big mugs of coffee, marmalade on crusty toast, and a selection of papers on the bar. It was just off the middle level escalator.</p>
		<p>After filling up we walked down to the harbour to catch the fast ferry across to Cheung Chan, one of the islands. It wasn't particularly choppy, but didn't feel too great with a hangover. It was pretty cool and cloudy today, but at least it didn't rain.</p>
		<p>On the island we hired some bikes, and spent a while trying to find somewhere to buy a torch, as Ramin was planning to take us into a cave. We eventually found one, but it was a bit temperamental, and only worked when the mood took it. We pretty much cycled around the whole island, stopping off to see a couple of temples. One of them had a small whale's spine displayed in a cabinet for some reason. Near the beginning of the route the track was really steep, and I felt quite sick after the exertion. It took a while to feel better, but I recovered myself while we waited to enter the cave. The queue didn't seem to move for ages, and I thought someone must be stuck inside the cave. While we waited, a rescue helicopter flew around, and hovered very close to us. It lowered someone down to the beach on a winch, and we think it must have been some kind of exercise.</p>
		<p>The cave was absolutely pitch black, and very narrow. It wasn't long, but would have been very trick to get through without the torch. We think that's why the people in front were taking so long. We hoped to find some pirates' treasure in the cave, but Ramin only managed to find a weird little doll. I scraped my arm on the cave wall when I was posing for Adam to take a photo.</p>
		<p>We cycled back round to the bike rental place, swerving around the hoards of pedestrians and rickshaws. We then had a walk around the main part of the village, saw a fish market, and lots of shops selling live fish and lobsters. There were several groups of people playing keepy uppy with shuttle cocks. The good ones looked very graceful, almost like performing martial arts. We had dinner at a restaurant by the water front. We ordered steamed fish, langoustines, crab and seafood fried rice. It was all delicious, but very messy to eat!</p>
		<p>We caught the slow ferry back to Hong Kong, which took an hour. We sat outside at the back, where we could see the clouds of black smoke and oil pouring out of the ferry. Once back we walked to Ramin's and changed from shorts into jeans before heading out again. We caught a taxi to Causeway Bay, where I was surprised just how lively everything was for a Sunday night. This was a main shopping area, and all the shops and malls were still open. There were so many lights it was almost like daytime. We wandered over to Victoria Park to see if anything was going on, but it was just the Hong Kong flower show. We didn't go in. However, we did smile at the poor person dressed as a giant corn cob, standing in the road handing out leaflets.</p>
		<p>After walking around for a while we went to a Chinese dessert shop in a shopping mall. Ramin dared us to have durian pancakes. It was worth it just to see Adam's face after his first, and only, mouthful. Unfortunately you're reminded of it every time you burp for the rest of the day!</p>
		<p>We had a quick coffee in a small cafe. It was nice to sit down in some comfy chairs, but we had to rush as they were closing in 15 minutes. We then caught a tram back to Ramin's. I called Simon to wish him a happy Easter, then we watched some TV before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="24-03-2008">
		<p>I woke up at 5am because of jet lag, and couldn't get back to sleep. We left Ramin's at 9am and caught a taxi to the tram station, to go up to the Peak. It was nice and sunny today. I noticed a lot of people on a P&amp;O tour on the tram, and I think they must be from the Aurora. The tram was really steep, and bounced backwards and forwards whenever it stopped.</p>
		<p>At the top, we walked all the way around the Peak. It was cool at the top, and the path was leafy. There were lots of people jogging and walking their dogs. The path was about 3km round, with lots of places to stop for good views. Once we got back to the start we went up to the top of the Peak shopping center for a look around.</p>
		<p>We caught a taxi from the Peak to the Hong Kong Football Club, where we were meeting Ramin's friends, Becky and Phil, for brunch. The club was very swish. We had an amazing buffet with as much Champagne and food as we wanted for £10. I had oysters, sushi, omelette, congee with pork and weird bony fish, chicken curry, crispy pork, baked chicken, fruit, and chocolate mousse. I could barely move for the next few hours.</p>
		<p>After lunch we went back to Ramin's for a quick change, and then caught a taxi to South Beach, right on the other side of the island. It was nice and warm, and I listened to my iPod and dozed in the sun for a few hours. I got an iced tea from a beach bar, and we played some frisbee. Ramin's work friend Maresh arrived and played with us, and then we were joined by two random girls, Jamie and Fiona. Adam managed to throw the frisbee into Jamie's nose, but luckily she seemed ok! At one point Maresh threw the frisbee into the sea. Even though they had swimming shorts, none of the boys would go in to get it, as the water was too cold. So I heroically plunged in wearing just my pants and swam out for it. The girls seemed very impressed!</p>
		<p>We had a couple of drinks in the bar, and when went back to Ramin's to get changed. We were still quite full, so just went out to a local street cafe for dinner. We had steamed grouper, chilli squid and salt fried pork. At the end of dinner we saw a huge cockroach climbing up the wall. Yuck!</p>
		<p>We went back to Ramin's and watched the film 'Knocked Up' before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="25-03-2008">
		<p>Ramin went back to work today, and Adam and I left the flat at 9am. We walked down to the ferry terminal and had a quick breakfast in a cafe. I had a chicken and leek quesadilla. We then caught the ferry across to Macau, which took about an hour. We were surprised to see that there were huge queues for Hong Kong nationals to get through immigration, but foreigners didn't have to wait at all.</p>
		<p>We planned to follow a walk in the Lonely Planet, so caught a taxi to the main square, which was where the walk began. It was very Portuguese, and reminded me of Ponta Delgada. We went inside a church, which had displays of religious relics upstairs, and also went into an old house where a man was doing miniature carving and tiny Chinese writing on blocks of stone. It was quite impressive.</p>
		<p>It was overcast today, but quite a pleasant temperature, especially as there were lots of steep roads and steps to climb. We walked right up to the old fort, which is now a museum, but unfortunately it was closed for refurbishment. There were some good views over the city, but it was quite smoggy. We then walked down to see the ruins of St. Paul's church, of which just the façade remains. There was another small display of religious artefacts, and a crypt with human bones on show.</p>
		<p>We were getting a bit hungry by now, so we each got a very nice traditional egg custard tart from a street vendor. There were loads of shops selling sheets of sweet barbecued pork along the streets. We followed the walk all the way down to A-ma temple. At one point Adam though we were on the wrong road, so we back tracked, only to find that we had been right to start with, and had almost got there the first time! The temple was built into the side of a hill, so we could climb up and see it at different levels. I commented that when Chinese people are having their photo taken, they always seem to put on a very serious expression. The temple was pretty much like all the other Buddhist temples I've seen before.</p>
		<p>After this we caught a taxi to Fernando's restaurant in Coloane. This is a small island connected to Macau by a bridge. The restaurant was Portuguese, and I ate a nice suckling pig and had a couple of beers. It started to rain when we left the restaurant, but fortunately we had brought our umbrellas. We got a taxi to Coloane village and had a nice short walk. There wasn't much to see, other than run down houses and a couple of temples. There were a couple of people taking lots of pictures of their car, which I thought was a bit odd.</p>
		<p>We asked a taxi driver to take us to Taipa village, but he obviously didn't understand us, as he dropped us off back at the ferry terminal. It wasn't a problem though, as we caught a free shuttle bus to the Venetian hotel on Taipa. This is the cousin of the Las Vegas Venetian, and is apparently the second biggest building in the world. It was very similar to Vegas inside, with gondolas on canals, and a simulated sky. We stopped in the food court for a coffee, then had a look around the enormous casino. I played on the poker machine for a while, getting up to $80 at one point, but then losing $40 in the end.</p>
		<p>Adam wanted to do a walk around Taipa village, which looked very close on the map, so we decided to walk there. Unfortunately we couldn't actually find it, and ended up walking all the way round the Venetian in the pouring rain.</p>
		<p>We got the ferry back to Hong Kong, arriving at a quarter to ten. We were starving by now, so met Ramin in Lan Kwae Fong for dinner in a Chinese cafe. This place was clean and modern, so we didn't have to share our dinner with the cockroaches tonight! I had a nice bowl of beef and prawn dumpling soup noodles, and some deep fried won tons. We were pretty tired after all the walking today, so went straight back to the flat after dinner.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-03-2008">
		<p>We had some breakfast at The Brunch Club – a cafe just up the road from Ramin's. I had eggs Benedict and a grapefruit juice. We then followed the Sun Yat Sen Heritage Trail up to the Dr Sun Yat Sen museum. The trail had photos of Hong Kong from the late 19th century, which were interesting to see. The museum itself was in a restored old town house, which was very impressive. It took us a while to work out exactly who Sun Yat Sen was! The museum displays explained that after training as a medical doctor he went on to lead the Chinese revolution, and deposed the Emperor. As such, he is a revered figure to the Chinese. Unfortunately he proposed his friend to be the first president, who then went on to try and make himself King, so Sun Yat Sen had to depose him too! The displays were interesting, and there was a nice video about the construction of the house, and the family that had lived in it for several generations.</p>
		<p>Afterwards, we made our way down to the ferry terminal and caught the Star Ferry across to Kowloon. Once there, we walked along the waterfront promenade and saw lots of large lanterns shaped like pandas playing sports. They were there for the upcoming Beijing Olympics. There were some funny pandas, including a weight lifter, and one packing a gun.</p>
		<p>We walked up Nathan Road and had some dim sum lunch in a restaurant at the top of the Miramar Center. We were sat at a round table with a couple of girls and a couple of old women. We were virtually the only Westerners in there, which was a good sign that we were in for some good local food. However, our waitress didn't speak any English at all. I ordered the food by pointing at the menu, but we only actually got about half the stuff we ordered. The other half we got was very nice though. We had some lovely paper wrapped prawns with peach, prawn dumplings, minced pork dumplings, deep fried crispy char siu pows, and lotus seed balls. They were only about £1 each.</p>
		<p>After lunch we followed a walk from the Lonely Planet, which took us up to a bird market. On the way we saw a temple and stopped at a jade market. Whenever we even half glanced at anything, the stall owner would pounce and ask us to make them an offer. Adam bought a metal pipe, which looked like it had been rusting in a bin somewhere. He did a good job of haggling though. She said it was $180, and he went straight in at $100. She said, “Oh no, much too low! $150”. Instead of meeting her halfway, he stuck to $100, and she accepted. It was probably only worth about $30 though! We also walked down a road full of pet shops. There were loads of fish in plastic bags, and about 30 baby hamsters in a cage, all trying to get on the wheel at the same time. They were very cute! At the bird market I was looking at some budgies when a bird pooed on Adam's head! I called home and spoke to Mum for a few minutes.</p>
		<p>We caught a taxi to the Peninsular Hotel, and went for high tea in the lobby. There was a rather bad string quartet playing medleys from the musicals, often not quite in time with each other. Fortunately we were seated at the other end of the lobby to them. The tea was very nice. We had cucumber sandwiches, scones and creams, and some small cakes. We stayed there for an hour or so, and then went up for a drink in the bar. Afterwards we went back down to the promenade again. We sat up on a raised viewing platform to watch the laser show again. It was much better this time, being a clear evening, and we could appreciate the music that went with the show. About thirty buildings lit up and flashed lasers in time to the music. The pandas were also lit up now, so we took some more photos of them.</p>
		<p>I called Ramin to arrange to meet him at the night market, but then my phone ran out of battery. We ended up waiting for each other about a block apart. Eventually we bumped into each other and went to a street cafe for dinner. The food was very good. We had ol-wah, choy sum, aubergine and fish hot pot, deep fried squid, and deep fried duck tongues with chilli. We had a quick walk around the night market, then caught the MTR back to Sheung Wan, where we had a drink with Nick, one of Ramin's friends.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-03-2008">
		<p>Adam and I had breakfast at a health food cafe. I had an omelette and a mixed fruit juice. They were promoting a healthy-eating service, whereby they provided and delivered all your meals every day. After breakfast we walked down to Central MTR station and caught a train to Tung Chung station on the island of Lantau. We then rode a cable car up into the hills. It was quite cloudy today, so the views were unremarkable. They are supposed to be spectacular on clear days. When the cable car arrived at Ngong Ping village there was a model monkey that took our picture. They sell the photo to you later. I didn't even notice it was there though, so the photo was of the back of my head.</p>
		<p>The 'village' was recently built, for the benefit of tourists, in an old Chinese style. There were loads of tourists buzzing around. Although it was mostly cloudy, there were moments when the sun broke through, which was very hot. We bought some postcards and walked up to see the giant bronze Buddha. This is apparently the biggest bronze, seated, outdoors Buddha in the world. There was a little exhibition in the base of the Buddha, but we didn't have much time to look around, as we had a lunch ticket for 2pm. We thought we would be eating in the monastery, having the same food as the monks, but it was actually just a vegetarian restaurant. There was no choice of food, but it was all very nice. We had a soup, some mushrooms, vegetables and spring rolls.</p>
		<p>After lunch we began our walk up to Lantau peak. There is a 70km trail around the island, of which this walk is a small part. It was quite steep and hard going, and on the way back down afterwards I counted around 1,500 roughly hewn steps. It was nice up at the top, but unfortunately it clouded over so there was absolutely no view. I hadn't realised that we would be doing this hike, so I had worn jeans today. They were rather unpleasantly sweaty by the end of the walk!</p>
		<p>We caught the cable car back down to Tung Chung, and there was a very cute baby on board. We then got the MTR back to Central, and went back to Ramin's for a shower. I wrote my postcards while we waited for Ramin to get home.</p>
		<p>Adam and I took Ramin out to dinner at the Peak Lookout restaurant. It was quite an upmarket place, and we had a table outside. This was very nice, except that leaves and twigs occasionally fell on our heads. We shared some nice Thai fish cakes and calamari for starters, then I had an excellent steak with Bearnaise sauce, French fries, and Hainese chicken rice (without the chicken). I had some really good profiteroles for dessert.</p>
		<p>Once we got back to the flat I realised that my phone was missing. It must have slipped out of my pocket in the taxi. Stupidly I had been wearing my trousers with zip pockets, but hadn't zipped them up. I tried calling the phone, but it was switched off. I used Ramin's phone to call 3 and have the SIM card blocked.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="28-03-2008">
		<p>I didn't sleep well, because there was a lot of loud banging coming from the street. I don't know what it was, but I had a dream that the window cleaners were outside banging on the windows. We went out to find the police station today to report my lost phone. We had a lot of difficulty finding it, and walked up and down a lot of wrong streets, When we eventually got there, we discovered that it had been closed for 3 years! There were some directions for another station though, so we walked there instead. The police man at the desk was very abrupt, and not very helpful, but we found out that there was another station up on the Peak. I though the taxi driver might have handed it in there, so we got another taxi up there.</p>
		<p>The police woman at this station was very helpful and friendly, although she may have been bored before we arrived, as it was really quiet up there. When I told her the model of my phone she started asking me how good it was, because she was thinking of getting one herself. Unfortunately it hadn't been handed in, but she gave me a police report for my insurance.</p>
		<p>Afterwards, we walked up towards the peak. We wanted to get there by walking, but after a while we thought we were lost, so hailed a taxi. It literally just drove round the corner and we were there! We went back to the Peak Lookout for lunch, and I had a nice, but quite posh chicken rice. We then had a look in the Peak Galleria, and saw an Easter display with lots of live cuddly bunnies in it. We caught the tram back down to the bottom, then walked to H&amp;M for Adam to buy his costume for tomorrow. They are all going to the rugby sevens dressed as characters from A Clockwork Orange. I bought some spare pants and socks.</p>
		<p>We went back to Ramin's to dump the shopping, then caught the MTR to Causeway Bay. We then walked up to the Hong Kong Stadium to see the sevens. As we were going in, I saw Jeremy just in front of us. I ran up to say hello, then he went off with the rest of his rugby team. We saw them later in the rowdy area of the stadium!</p>
		<p>We watched a couple of games, then went for a walk round the stadium. Adam got some souvenir shirts, and I got a jumbo hot dog. The atmosphere was great, and there were 20,000 people in the stadium, but I was still reminded of watching rugby at school. Ramin and his friends turned up, and we got some seats together. They bought quite a few jugs of beer for us. It was really lively, and I got quite into the games, especially when England were playing. We beat the Canadians!</p>
		<p>Afterwards, we all went to Lan Kwai Fong for some drinks. It was absolutely packed, and we all stood out on the street. Adam, Ramin and I got kebabs, then went back to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="29-03-2008">
		<p>Adam and Ramin set off for the sevens at 8am today, dressed as droogs. I wanted a quiet day, so didn't go with them. I slept in until about midday, then went out to find a hairdresser, My hair was definitely getting too long! My legs were still aching from the climb to Lantau peak, and if anything they felt even worse today. I booked a haircut at a salon on Wyndham Street, then found a book shop while I was waiting for my appointment. I bought a set of books on learning Chinese characters. The books are quite interesting, but are written with a very peculiar sense of humour.</p>
		<p>After my haircut I got some abalone and chicken congee for lunch, then went back to Ramin's to read my new books. I got a craving for junk food, so went to the corner shop to get Pringles, M&amp;Ms and a Snickers bar. I then watched a couple of episodes of Curb Your Enthusiasm at the flat.</p>
		<p>Ramin called at about 7 o'clock to say that the sevens had finished, and they were all heading over to the sevens village for a party. After getting lost looking for Sheun Wan station, I caught the MTR to Causeway Bay then walked up to the stadium. The tube and streets were full of people in crazy fancy dress. The sevens village was a lawn with a big marquee. Adam, Ramin and his friends were in the tent, dancing to cheesy music. The place was absolutely packed with drunk people, all very happy and having a good time. It was incredibly hot, and everyone was really sweaty. There was a live band and a DJ, and all the music was good for dancing to. People were dressed as dragons, Super Mario, Roman senators, a couple looked like the 118 men, and a few people weren't wearing very much at all! </p>
		<p>I stayed for a couple of hours, then Adam and I left as we had to be up early the next day. We were both pretty hungry by then, so got pizzas from Pizza Express. Adam wanted to get takeaways, as he didn't fancy sitting in the restaurant dressed as a droog! We took the pizzas back to Ramin's and ate them while we watched a DVD. We got to bed at about 11:30.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="30-03-2008">
		<p>We woke up at 5am today, to get down to the airport for our flight to Beijing. My legs were still hurting, and I was limping a bit. We planned on walking to Sheun Wan station to catch the MTR, but we just couldn't find it! A taxi pulled up and offered to drive us there for a 'special price' of $200. As we didn't have that much cash on us we told him we'd just get the MTR. At this he suggested $150 instead. This would probably be cheaper than the MTR fare, so we accepted and got to the airport in comfort. Oddly, he seemed to have his laundry hung up to dry in the boot of his car!</p>
		<p>We checked in and went through immigration very smoothly, and I got some ham noodles for breakfast. After browsing around the shops we boarded the plane. We ere fortunate to get emergency exit seats, so we could stretch out our legs. I think I managed to sleep for most of the flight.</p>
		<p>In Beijing airport Adam found someone to write down the location of our hotel for us in Chinese, to show to the taxi driver. I changed some Stirling into Yuan. The taxi driver seemed quite confused about where the hotel was, and kept stopping to call someone on his mobile for directions. We finally got there though, and checked in. We were staying at the Redwall Hotel in North Shatan Street, which is pretty much next to the north end of the Forbidden City. The hotel only has two and a half stars, but seems very nice. The staff speak reasonable English, and are very helpful.</p>
		<p>Our room is quite pleasant, although we were surprised to find, sitting next to the tea and coffee, a tray of sex stuff including a vibrating condom and some 'Private Parts Lotion'. We were slightly worried by the sign in the toilet warning, “Beware, landslide!”.</p>
		<p>After settling in we went for a short walk to find some late lunch. It was a beautiful day. Although it was apparently only 11 degrees, the sky was blue, the sun was shining, and it was very agreeable to walk about without a jacket. We wandered through a huton next to the hotel, which was a maze of shanty buildings functioning as a small community. It was very relaxing after the hustle and bustle of Hong Kong. We found a restaurant, and realised once we were seated that it was a steam boat place. We ordered mutton, beef, fish balls (which were delicious), tofu, beef dumplings and spinach. There were no nets, so we had to fish everything out with our chopsticks. Out waitress was very good, and helped us to catch the food. There were a couple of very noisy birds in cages in the corner. The meal was lovely and came to just over £5 each.</p>
		<p>After lunch we walked back to the hotel, which involved walking along the outside wall of the Forbidden City. It looks very imposing. A number of touts approached us offering guided tours, but we weren't interested. We bought four bottles of water from a roadside stall. The man didn't speak any English, so I had no idea how much to pay him. I offered him 10 Yuan, which is about 60p, and he seemed very happy with that! Back at the hotel we booked a tour to the wall and the Ming tombs, and also to see some Chinese opera. </p>
		<p>In the evening we caught a taxi to the Bianyifang roast duck restaurant, which is on the ground floor of the Hademen Hotel in Chongwen district. Out hotel supplies cards to give to the taxi drivers. One side shows how to get back to the hotel, while on the other the hotel staff can write your destination in Chinese. It's always a bit concerning whether the driver understands what has been written, but at least this time it worked and we got straight there. This restaurant was recommended by our AA city guide as one of the best places for Peking duck.</p>
		<p>The place was packed when we arrived, with people taking tickets to get seated. It was very hectic, and we both stood there waiting to get noticed. An American woman approached and asked if we spoke English. She was also a tourist, and had just been to Hong Kong to cover an art festival, as she was a professor of art. She asked whether we would like to join her, and we got a table almost straight away.</p>
		<p>We ordered a whole roast duck and some vegetables. The duck wasn't crispy like aromatic duck, but was nicely roasted with crispy skin. It was in chunks, rather than shredded, but still came with pancakes. It arrived on a plate with carved duck heads on the ends, and was accompanied by the head, sliced in half with the brains showing! It was nice, but I wouldn't say it was any better than the duck back home. Our dining companion was called Toby, and she was very chatty, which made for a fun dinner.</p>
		<p>Afterwards we caught a taxi back to the hotel, and I had a soak in the bath to try and soothe my aching calves. The bath was so short that I couldn't even straighten my legs when I sat completely upright. Nevertheless, I felt better afterwards.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="31-03-2008">
		<p>We planned on getting up early to go down to Ti'ananmen Square for sunrise, but when the alarm went off at 6am we made a unanimous decision to stay in bed! We eventually got up about 9.30, then walked down to the south entrance of the Forbidden City. It was another lovely day, with bright, clear skies. The Forbidden City is huge, and it took us a good 20 minutes to walk round to the entrance. We heard a lot of noise coming from nearby, and someone told us that Ti'ananmen Square was closed today for a celebration. We later found out that it was for the lighting of the Olympic torch.</p>
		<p>While we were waiting to buy tickets for the city, a young looking Chinese girl came up to us and asked if we wanted a tour. She was very insistent that we would be missing out if we didn't hire her. I asked whether she was an official guide, and she said, “Of course I am, I'm here every day!”. She couldn't show us any ID though, and we later saw that the official guides wear uniforms. We didn't hire her.</p>
		<p>Because of the upcoming Olympics a lot a renovation work was being carried out within the city. This was a shame, as some of the most impressive halls were hidden behind layers of bamboo scaffolding. There were descriptions in English by every hall and room, although most of them ran along the lines of, “This is the hall of eternal tranquility. It was originally called the hall of eternal serenity until emperor so and so of such and such dynasty changed it...”.</p>
		<p>There were quite a lot of tourists around, but the courtyards were so massive that it didn't seem crowded. We had lunch in a small cafe that was so overstaffed they had four people waiting to open the door for us! I had beef curry with rice, and I bought a small box of biscuits to munch on later.</p>
		<p>The city was truly massive, and after seeing all of the main grand halls we explored down a side passage and found another area, just as big, but full of winding alleys and smaller rooms. This was where the imperial family used to live, and it was very serene. It was especially peaceful because there were far fewer people round here.</p>
		<p>There were several exhibitions throughout the city, from musical instruments and weapons, to imperial wedding finery. At one point we were approached by a very enthusiastic Mongolian girl who wanted to show us her paintings. Apparently she was an art student here for a month, and selling paintings from her art school. Some of them were very nice, so I bought a painting of some pandas for Simon. I also bought him a nice glass vase with a picture inside it.</p>
		<p>The imperial gardens were very nice to stroll around. They are at the north end of the city. There weren't many flowers, but lots of gnarly trees and interestingly shaped rock formations. We left the city by the north gate, which was very close to our hotel.</p>
		<p>I had another bath before dinner, then we walked to the Ba Guo Bu Yi restaurant on Di'anmen Dongdaje. According to our guide book, the interior is laid out like an old Peking inn. This seemed unlikely from the gaudy neon strips outside, but the inside was all wooden and very nice. The staff didn't speak any English, but were very helpful. We ordered far too much food, including squid cooked on hot stones, a basket of deep fried chillies wrapped in pork, and an aubergine and dried dace hot pot. It was very tasty, and extremely filling! We staggered back to the hotel and went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="01-04-2008">
		<p>We were picked up by our tour guide, Analisa, at 7.40 this morning for our trip to the Great Wall. It was colder today, and raining. We had been told that our tour group would be about 30 people, but it turned out that it was just us and four others – a Canadian couple and their grandchildren. The grandparents were originally from Penang, and could speak to Analisa in Cantonese.</p>
		<p>We first drove out to the Ming tombs, where 13 Ming emperors were buried. This took about an hour, and it had stopped raining by the time we got there. It was nice to drive our of the city and see some countryside. It was quite rustic, with people working out in the fields. Again, due to the upcoming Olympics parts of the tombs were closed for renovation. However, we did walk up to see Chang Ling tomb, were emperor Yongle was buried in 1424. There were some nice buildings, and an exhibition of relics from the Ding tomb. The Chang Ling tomb itself has never been opened, and is a vault beneath a man made hill.</p>
		<p>After this we were taken to a Jade workshop, which was pretty boring. We had lunch at the restaurant there, and they brought us too much to finish. After lunch we drove to the Great Wall at Badaling. It was very touristy, and we had to fight our way through stall keepers trying to sell us tatty souvenirs. There were several large pits in which we were surprised to see lots of black bears. I suppose we should have expected it, as Analisa said she'd meet us in the bear garden. I thought she'd said 'beer garden' though! The bears seemed quite happy, and were playing on climbing frames.</p>
		<p>To get up to the wall we rode a bizarre uphill toboggan run. The toboggans were on rails, and were winched up to the top. It felt like going up on a roller coaster, and seemed very incongruous. It was very blustery on the wall, but the sun occasionally came out to warm us up. This particular section of the wall was very steep, with a mixture of uneven steps and slopes. It was also packed with very noisy tourists. We climbed up to the highest point, and then walked a little way down the next section where there were hardly any other tourists. It was very peaceful here, and I sat for a while listening to some music on my iPod and enjoying the tranquility. The landscape views were breathtaking and very beautiful.</p>
		<p>We spent about an hour on the wall, then rode the toboggan back down again. The next stop on the tour was a Chinese traditional pharmacy, which seemed quite odd. They gave us free foot massages, while the Chinese doctor felt out pulses and looked at our tongues. One of the doctors gave us a talk about how their medicine is better than Western medicine, and how the herbs have no side effects because they are all 'natural'. They tried to sell me a concoction of herbs for £40, but I declined. The Canadian family spent about £600 on herbs! I think the doctors are charlatans, and no better than homeopaths and clairvoyants. I didn't say that to their faces though!</p>
		<p>On the way back to the hotel we drove past the Olympic park and saw some of the buildings they will be using, including the bird's nest stadium. Adam and I went to the restaurant opposite the hotel for dinner tonight. We ordered by pointing at pictures in the menu, and I'm still not quite sure what we got, but it was very tasty. I had a nice talk with Simon, and told him how much I miss him, especially when I'm seeing something amazing like the Great Wall and want to share the experience with him.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="02-04-2008">
		<p>This morning we walked down to Ti'ananmen Square. It was another beautiful sunny day. Apparently we have been really lucky to get all this good weather, as you rarely see the sun in Beijing because of all the pollution. On the way down to the square we bumped into Toby, walking the other way. It seemed quite a coincidence, in a city of 13 millions people to bump into the only other person we'd really met before. We stopped to look in the window of a small souvenir shop, and instantly the owner pounced and invited us in. Adam was thinking of getting a funny hat, so we went in to have a look. I ended up buying a small cuddly dragon, and Adam got a paper model of a turtle. He tried to haggle her down by threatening to leave the shop, but she just shrugged and put the turtle away again, so he ended up buying it at the original price. I don't think we have a chance, haggling with the Chinese!</p>
		<p>We walked through a nice little garden, and then came out into Ti'ananmen Square. There were so many people here that we could hardly move. As we were walking, two Chinese girls came over to talk to us. They said that they wanted to practice their English so they could apply for jobs at the Olympics. I've become quite cynical about strangers coming up to talk, because they usually end up wanting your money. These girls looked quite upset when we declined their offer of going for a cup of tea with them.</p>
		<p>We spent some time walking around the square, which is the biggest in the world. There were lots of soldiers taking pictures of each other. Although it is so massive and has historical significance, I didn't really find it that interesting. It was just a huge square with a couple of monuments.</p>
		<p>We caught the subway from the square to meet Jeremy at Wudaoku. There was an interesting LED display on the tunnel walls outside the tube, that changed frames according to the speed of the train. It was showing adverts, and looked like an old fashioned flick book.</p>
		<p>We got to Wudaoku a bit late, and I found that I had no credit left on my SIM card to call Jeremy, but luckily he was waiting for us there. He took us to an upmarket restaurant for lunch where we had a delicious Peking duck. This was much better than the first place. The duck was sliced into wafer thin pieces, with lots of fat and crispy skin. Yum! They even gave us a commemorative card to tell us which particular duck had been roasted for us.</p>
		<p>Afterwards we went back to Jeremy's flat and had a cup of tea. I offloaded the cowboy boots I had been carrying for him, and he was over the moon to get some Harribo sweets. He then took us to a local phone shop to recharge my credit. We left him to get ready for a Chinese lesson, and went back to Ti'ananmen East station. Walking back to the hotel we were accosted by numerous people offering Rolexes, Omegas, postcards and tatty toys. Another couple started walking with us because they wanted to practice their English. We gave them the slip when Adam invented a friend we had to be going to meet.</p>
		<p>At 6.30 we were picked up by our tour guide, Paul, to go to the Peking opera. This was at the Liguan Theatre, which is part of a Peking opera themed hotel. We had seats at a table right in front of the stage, which meant we had to turn out heads to see the surtitles. We had some snacks provided for us, and some Chinese tea which was poured from pots with ridiculously long spouts. The tea pourer flicked the pot around dramatically, and poured the tea in weird ways, like from over his shoulder, or from under his arm.</p>
		<p>The opera was very good. We saw two acts. The first was a story about a young woman who needed a boat to chase after her lover, but the old boatman played tricks on her to hold her up. The woman had an unbelievably screeching voice. I think 'caterwauling' is the technical term. The second story was about 18 gods trying to fight the monkey king. The gods were really weird. There was one with really long arms, a drunk one, a really tall one, and a really short one. Some of the fighting and acrobatics was good, but it went on for a bit too long.</p>
		<p>When we got back to the hotel, we bought some beers and played cards in our room.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="03-04-2008">
		<p>This morning we took a taxi to the Summer Palace. We'd had a couple of small cakes for breakfast, which we'd got from the small shop by the hotel. It was another lovely day. The taxi ride took about half an hour, and the roads were clear, as we'd left after rush hour.</p>
		<p>The Summer Palace is actually an enormous lake, with a path running around the outside, and an island in the middle connected to the shore by the seventeen arch bridge. It was quite busy today. There were groups doing tai-chi to music, and at least one man flying a kite. There were also quite a few pedalos out on the lake. Apparently the lake freezes over in the winter, and is used for skating.</p>
		<p>There were several exhibitions within the grounds, which provided an opportunity to get away from the crowds. There were displays of imperial furniture, bronze jars and jade carvings. We sat by the side of the lake and had cup noodles for lunch. I also had an ice cream.</p>
		<p>There wasn't much to see on the island, especially as some of the buildings were being renovated. We walked all the way around the lake, which was lined by attractive willow trees. To cross the lake we walked over a causeway comprised of seven bridges, with names like the jade bridge, the silk bridge and the mirror bridge. They were apparently named from the lines of a poem.</p>
		<p>We climbed up to quite a high point and saw a temple with a large seated Buddha, and then walked down through some courtyards back to ground level. There was an interesting street with a canal running down the middle, on which gondoliers were offering rides. It looked like an Eastern Venice. All the buildings on the street were souvenir shops, and as we passed each one someone would shout out to us: “Come in!”; “Have your picture taken with the Emperor!”; “Have tea! Have tea!”.</p>
		<p>We left the park at 4pm, which was unfortunately already during rush hour. The taxi took an hour to get back. We were kept entertained by a very catchy and rousing song on the radio. The only words we could pick out were 'Lie! Lie! Lie!', which was sung over and over. Adam and I keep singing it to each other now!</p>
		<p>We were picked up by Paul outside the hotel at 6.30 to go and see some Chinese acrobatics. The theatre was covered in scaffolding, and looked a bit deserted, but once inside it was a very big and full auditorium. The show was fantastic. The special effects were great, with smoke and lasers, and the acrobats were incredible. Guys were catapulted into the air from see saws, lifting each other up and balancing in amazing positions, doing flying leaps through tiny hoops. Extraordinarily bendy women wrapped their legs around their heads, balanced hundreds of spinning plates, and at one point about twenty women were balanced on one bicycle. I was really impressed.</p>
		<p>We played lots of cribbage when we got back to the hotel.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="04-04-2008">
		<p>This morning we walked to Baihai Park, which is just around the corner from the hotel. It was the hottest day yet, and gloriously sunny. This park also has an enormous lake with an island in the middle. It was even busier then the Summer palace, and there were so many boats out that I'm surprised they didn't all crash.</p>
		<p>I got a frankfurter on a stick for breakfast. It tasted a bit odd though. I think it must have been made with Chinese spices. We walked around the island, and climbed to the top where there was a temple. We walked through some caves which had lots of little statues of Buddha. A man behinds us was making a funny clicking noise. Adam thought it was something mechanised, but I think he was carrying around a bag of live crickets.</p>
		<p>We were going to have lunch at an expensive restaurant on the island, but there was a long wait for a table, so we got lunch at a much cheaper place. Two bowls of noodles, a plate of 20 steamed pork dumplings, and 10 spring rolls for less than £5!</p>
		<p>We had a nice walk through the gardens after lunch. There were loudspeakers piping out relaxing music, and men writing calligraphy on the pavement with big brushes dipped in water. It was so hot that the characters were starting to evaporate by the time they had finished. There were loads of families out having picnics, and the children seemed to find the two of us quite fascinating, either grinning at us, or cowering behind their fathers! A lot of babies were peeing on the pavement.</p>
		<p>Adam bought a kind a feathered shuttlecock toy, and we played keeping it in the air for a while, until we were both tired and very sweaty. As we were walking we heard the unmistakable sounds of a woman singing Chinese opera. She had quite a crowd gathered to listen.</p>
		<p>After the park, Adam needed to buy a new rucksack, which he got from a shop near our hotel. My rucksack was starting to fall apart, so I got a very good replacement for a bargain £10. We went to another restaurant across the road from the hotel for dinner. We had half a Peking duck, ma po tofu, a kind of meat stuffed roti paratha, and some broccoli. We then went back to the hotel and packed before having an early night.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="05-04-2008">
		<p>We woke up at 4am to go to the airport. After checking out of the hotel we had a driver to take us there. Even at this time of the morning, with virtually clear roads, the few cars that were about were driving with reckless abandon. It's usually much worse than this during the day. We arrived at the check in desk a few minutes before it opened, and were the first in line. We managed to get seats with extra legroom. Before boarding we went to Pizza Hut for breakfast, as it was the only place open. I had frankfurters and fried eggs.</p>
		<p>I slept for most of the 3 hour flight back to Hong Kong, and we arrived at 11.30. We wanted to check in for our flight back home tonight, but the desk didn't open until 9pm. Instead we left our luggage in a locker and then caught the MTR into Kowloon.</p>
		<p>We phoned Ramin, who had just got out of bed, and arranged to meet him at the promenade by the Olympic pandas. It was quite a walk from Kowloon station to the promenade, and it was very sunny and humid. While we waited for Ramin I answered a questionnaire for some school children who were doing a project. They wanted a picture with me as well.</p>
		<p>We went for lunch at a nice restaurant behind the Miramar shopping centre. We had samosas and calamari for starters, and then I had a seafood char kwai teow. After lunch we caught the MTR back to Sheung Wan, and got some ice creams to take back to Ramin's. We spent the afternoon watching a DVD of Curb Your Enthusiasm.</p>
		<p>Adam and I left at around 8pm, and got to the airport just before check in opened again. There was already a short, but growing, queue. I was getting anxious, as I was certain all the people in front would be snapping up the emergency exit seats. Fortunately there was one left, but it meant that Adam and I would have to sit apart.</p>
		<p>We got some wanton soup noodles in an airport restaurant for dinner. Each table had a small TV on it, and ours was showing a Roger Moore Bond film in Chinese. By the time we settled down at the gate, we didn't have too long to wait until boarding. We had an uneventful flight back home.</p>
	</entry>
</diary>