<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Italy" date="09-2013">
	<entry date="21-09-2013">
		<p>Our flight was not due to leave until the afternoon, so we spent the morning packing, followed by a Costa coffee in Beckenham, and lunch at the fish and chip shop next door. I had a very nice deep fried skate wing, and Simon had a big breakfast. We drove over to mum and dad's house and had a cup of tea, then Judy took us to Gatwick. We had both been feeling under the weather for a few days, and I had a sore throat.</p>
		<p>Our flight was delayed by about half an hour. We had a drink while we waited. Although they've done a great deal of work on Gatwick, there are still no interesting shops to look around. We were flying with Easy Jet, and we were pleased that they had just introduced allocated seating on their flights. In the past it would have been a scramble on board to get to sit together.</p>
		<p>The flight to Pisa was just under 2 hours. We ate some sandwiches that we had bought in advance, and I listened to my iPod. The man sitting next to me noticed that I was listening to Bach's B minor mass, and commented that it was nice to see someone listening to 'serious music' for a change! We got to Pisa at 9.15 pm, but didn't get to drive away until gone midnight. Getting our baggage was fine, but picking up the rental car was a bit of a nightmare.</p>
		<p>We had booked insurance to cover the car rental excess before we left, deliberately so that we wouldn't have to pay the rental company's extorionate rates. The woman at the desk was extremely aggressive and unhelpful, and eventually bullied us into taking their insurance as well. It didn't help that this was extremely late, and so we couldn't speak to our own insurance company to clear things up. She then took the payment from my card twice. So I had to call Metrobank, and even then the woman said she couldn't refund the money until their head office opened on Monday.</p>
		<p>One slight comfort from all of this came when I drove the car out of the car park. I hadn't realised that there were two low concrete blocks on the ground in front of the car, so I ended up driving straight into them. The car ended up with several good scrapes, which I don't feel too bad about!</p>
		<p>The drive to the hotel should have taken about an hour. We were very lucky that our phone operator, Three, had abolished all roaming charges to Italy just before we came out. This meant that we could use the Sat Navs on our phones, which was a great help. However, once we got to the general area of the hotel, we couldn't actually find it. So we ended up driving round and round this small Tuscan town at 2 am, just wanting to get to bed. We eventually stumbled across the hotel, and were very relieved that it seemed to be a lovely place. We were shown to our room, and dropped into bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="22-09-2013">
		<p>We both slept soundly, and got up at about 9.30. I still had a sore throat. After a shower we went down to a breakfast of cold meats and pastries. We had a much needed coffee. The Hotel Villa Bianca is just outside the village of Gramsci Terme, kind of midway between Pisa, Florence and Siena. The town is on a hill, and the hotel is even higher than the town, so the views over the Tuscan countryside are really amazing. It felt like we were finally on holiday, waking up to sunshine, blue skies, and great scenery. The hotel staff are really friendly too.</p>
		<p>After breakfast we had a little walk around the hotel grounds. The hotel is very small, having only 8 bedrooms, so the grounds are small as well, but they're very pretty. There are a couple of secluded gardens, and a very enticing swimming pool. After this we walked down into Gramsci Terme to have a look around. We bumped into another couple of hotel guests, and walked with them for a while. They also booked the holiday through Secret Escapes, and had had a similar experience with the car rental company. I didn't ask whether they'd crashed theirs yet though!</p>
		<p>The town is very small, but really lovely. There don't seem to be any other tourists around, so it has a real local feel. The peaceful atmosphere, coupled with pretty buildings, narrow streets and fantastic views were a winning combination. After walking around the whole town, we found a bench in a beautiful small park, and just sat in the shade for a while, watching the world go by. It was pretty hot in the sun today, but in the shade the temperature was perfect.</p>
		<p>We had lunch in a small cafe. I had a ham and mushroom sandwich and a cappucino. Simon had a salami sandwich and a Coke. I felt pretty pleased that I managed to order the lunch and pay the bill all in Italian.</p>
		<p>After our late night, we were both feeling pretty exhausted, so we had a snooze in the afternoon. Then we went down to the pool. Simon went for a swim, but it was rather cold so I just had a paddle! We sat in the sun for an hour or so, reading our books. I was reading the Lonely Planet guide to Tuscany, and trying to brush up on my Italian vocab. I'm sure it will come in useful to be able to ask for a spoon at some point!</p>
		<p>We had a drink sitting outside the hotel bar, watching the sun go down over the Tuscan hills, before walking up the road to the Ristorante Al Mirador for some dinner. I had a nice, big, octopus stew to start, then a seafood risotto, and Simon had smoked salmon followed by pizza. We watched a bit of Italian television back in our room before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="23-09-2013">
		<p>My sore throat was better today, but I'd developed a bit of asthma. Simon discovered that he'd been bitten several times during the night. On the positive side, the weather was really nice today. The receptionist told us that we were lucky with the weather, as it had been cold and raining just a couple of weeks ago.</p>
		<p>We took the car out to San Gimignano this morning. I'm starting to get the hang of driving on the wrong side. No crashes today. We decided to stay on minor roads rather than the motorway. This turned out to be a good idea, as the route was very scenic. Unfortunately we had a mosquito trapped in the car with us, so both ended up with quite a few bites.</p>
		<p>We found a very busy car park just outside San Gimignano, but managed to squeeze into a space. We made sure to slap on some sun cream, and Simon picked up his proper camera before heading into the town. San Gimignano was really very nice, but extremely packed with tourists. We were both desperate for a wee, so ended up joining a queue of elderly American women while we waited for the cleaner to finish up in the public toilet. She then only let two people in at a time, and made sure that we used the cubicles that she directed. It was 50 cents well spent though.</p>
		<p>The town was very hilly, but right at the top was a lovely walled garden, with fabulous views. There weren't as many people up there either. Simon said that was because the Americans were too fat to make the climb! We spent a while taking photos. There were a couple of local artists up there, painting and selling their works. We had a drink, but weren't really hungry, so decided to press on to Siena for lunch.</p>
		<p>It took about 40 minutes to get to Siena, and we arrived at about half past one. We found somewhere to park a little outside the city, so had a bit of a walk to get there. I wanted to show Simon where I had lived when I was working there, but my memory wasn't very good. We walked all around the city until we eventually found it (I think). We also found my favourite Sienese restaurant, Due Porte, but it was closed on Mondays. We were really desperate to relieve ourselves again, so just went into the first restaurant we could find for lunch. It wasn't too bad, even though it was advertising a tourist menu! I had a pretty nice spaghetti vongole.</p>
		<p>After lunch we wandered over to the duomo. We decided not to go in though, as it looked like it would have been very crowded. The centre of Siena was also packed with tourists. We had a look in a couple of shops, and I managed to find the best gelato place in Siena again. We each had a three scoop cone, and walked down to the piazza to eat it. On the way back to the car we picked up some insect repellant, and on the drive back I managed to squash the mosquito, so it looks like the battle is turning our way.</p>
		<p>We went to a very nice restaurant near Gambassi Terme for dinner. It was called Il Tre Casa. I had ravioli, and Simon had a really good pizza. I could see into the kitchen to watch the chef cooking. It was slightly disturbing to see him drop a prawn on the floor, and then chuck it into the saucepan anyway, but it all gets cooked hey. I had creme brulee for pudding, then we headed back to the hotel.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="24-09-2013">
		<p>I had a croissant filled with custard for breakfast. We had a nice drive down to the town of Volterra this morning. The roads are very nice around this area, with lots of bends and hardly any traffic. I've yet to run into the infamously bad Italian driver. However, the speed limit of 50 kph seems extremely slow for these open roads.</p>
		<p>Volterra is a beautiful town perched on top of a large hill. We parked just outside the old part of town, and walked in. Our first port of call was the public toilet, again! Must be the strong coffee we get for breakfast. As we wandered through the town, we came upon the Palazzo Viti, which looked like a National Trust stately home. We spent a very enjoyable hour wandering around, and were particularly impressed with the library room. It's given us ideas for when we get our house!</p>
		<p>We had lunch in a very nice, but quiet, restaurant in Volterra. At first we were the only customers. I had a steak with truffles, and Simon had penne with salmon and gorgonzola. It was the first time I had tried truffles, and they were quite nice, but did tend to repeat on me throughout the afternoon. I got to use my spoon phrase again.</p>
		<p>After lunch we walked around the rest of the town. We were amazed how peaceful and quiet it was. Where were all the tourists? We looked in some shops, which were selling alabaster sculptures, and Simon bought an alabaster picture frame. The town had fantastic views over the surrounding countryside, and was very charming itself, with pretty little lanes and attractive houses. We both agreed that this was our favourite Italian place so far. They also had a Roman amphitheatre, which we viewed from the city wall abouve. A Spanish man was playing his guitar, and we bought some of his CDs.</p>
		<p>We stopped for a quick coffee before leaving. I had a strong double espresso, which actually made me feel a little queasy afterwards. We dropped in at a supermarket on the way back to the hotel, and got some bottles of water and some Italian cakes to take back home. Simon had a little snooze when we got back, then we headed out to dinner.</p>
		<p>We ate at a restaurant about 5 minutes walk from the hotel. The inside was all pink, and it felt like we were having dinner in a girl's bedroom. I had wild boar pasta, then a tuna and onion pizza. I'm getting a little fed up asking for spoons all the time! Posso avere un cucchiaio? We had a very nice bottle of local white wine, produced in San Gimignano.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="25-09-2013">
		<p>We moved rooms this morning. Simon finally worked out what was causing my asthma. The wall in the bathroom was covered in mold. Our new room was a bit smaller, but mold free. Each of the rooms has a different painting on the walls. We moved from the olive tree room to the butterfly room.</p>
		<p>We had decided to have a quieter day today. This morning we drove out to a local vineyard, hoping to have a tour. The place was desserted though, apart from a couple of kittens. At least it wasn't a long drive.</p>
		<p>We went into Gambassi Terme for lunch. Simon got a sandwich from a cafe, then I had spaghetti vongole in a restaurant. Although we initially thought it was nice that the town was quiet, it now seems more like a ghost town. The locals seem very unfriendly, the restaurants are all pretty much empty, and there's a general atmosphere of weirdness. Other than in our hotel, none of the Italians we've come across have been very welcoming.</p>
		<p>We spent the afternoon having a doze and reading our books by the pool. It was a bit cooler today. I went for a quick swim, but the water was very cold! We had a reasonably long drive to find somewhere for dinner tonight. We stopped to look at a few restaurants on the way, but they were all empty and didn't look very inviting. We finally found a nice place in a town called Iano. We managed to get some phone reception, and looked up some reviews on TripAdvisor, which were generally positive. I had duck pasta, then beef cheek in pepper sauce. Again the resturant was virtually empty, but at least the waitress smiled.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="26-09-2013">
		<p>We drove down to Castelfiorentino this morning, to get a train into Florence. One of the other guests had advised us to get the tickets from a newsagent instead of from the station, as then we could get open tickets. The trip to Florence took about 45 minutes.</p>
		<p>The first thing we did in Florence was to visit the Capella de Medici, which has all of the Medici marble tombs. It was pretty impressive. We also saw some Michelangelo statues of Dusk and Dawn, and Night and Day. They were still doing refurbishment work in there, with scaffolding up, since 1999. The Italians don't do anything in a hurry.</p>
		<p>We crossed the Ponte Vecchio to find lunch on the other side of the Arno, where it was a bit less crowded. Simon picked up a panino from a delicatassen and ate it in a sqaure. I recongised it as the square where I had listened to live music with Sarah, before getting shut out of our hostel! I was looking for somewhere to get bistecca alla Fiorentina, and came upon a nice looking restaurant called Sant'Agostino 23. The smallest steak they had was 900g. Simon helped me out, and had about 100g. The steak was beautiful, but I had no room for dessert! Simon took a triptych of photos, showing me before, during and after.</p>
		<p>We had a bit of a walk after lunch, down to the southern city gate, and then had a wander around the Palazzo Pitti. You now have to buy seperate tickets for the palace and the Boboli gardens, so we just went into the palace. I had forgotten how big it was though. It was very impressive, but there was just too much artwork to look at, and we ended up a bit overloaded. THey had an exhibitiion of modern art on the top floor. I didn't think I'd be that interested, so we thought we'd just have a quick look, but it turns out that their idea of modern art was anything from the 18th century onwards!</p>
		<p>We had a brief look in some clothes shops on the way back to the station. I must have good taste: the only stuff I liked was around 1000 Euros! We got back to Castelfiorentino at about 7 pm, and decided to get some dinner in a restaurant that had been recommended to us. However, we discovered that it was closed on Thursdays. This is about the third time that we'be gone to a restaurant on the one day of the week that it's not open! Instead, we went back to the hotel for a quick shower, then back to Le Tre Case. I had some weird prawns in rum mayonnaise for starter, then a seafood spaghetti.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="27-09-2013">
		<p>We had a nice drive over to Greve in Chianti today. We drove through lots of vineyards and olive groves, and went past several tractors laden with grapes. Some of the roads were uite narrow, and at some points we were driving along single lane dirt tracks, so I felt like I was in a rally.</p>
		<p>We had lunch at the Gabello Nero (the black cockrel), in Greve. I had fried crostini covered in pork lard and truffles, follwed by spaghettit bolognesse. I'm going to need to go for a few runs when I get home! We then spent a very enjoyable afternoon walking around the wine museum, which was very interesting. They had a lot of barrels, grape squashers, pumps etc, and good descriptions of the history of winemaking in the region. We then went over the road to La Cantina wine tasting cellar. It's the biggest wine tasting place in Europe, with over 100 wines to try. You buy a card which is charged with credit, then use it to automatically dispense wine from taps. I was designated driver, but had fun watching Simon try a dozen different wines.</p>
		<p>Simon had an uncomfortable trip back, as the effects of the wine took hold, and there was nowhere to stop for the toilet. He was convinced the fates were conspiring against him, when we got stuck behind a tractor for a while, and then went past a farmer with a hose watering his crops. When we got back to the hotel, he sprinted up to the room, and weed for 76 seconds! He was happier after that.</p>
		<p>We went back to the girl's bedroom for dinner. I had a delicious crab penne, and a mixed salad. We shared a massive chocolate and mascapone pizza for dessert, and I had an amber grappa to finish, which I think was nicer than the clear variety.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="28-09-2013">
		<p>We had breakfast in the hotel as usual, accompanied by the regular soundtrack of Pavarotti and Michael Buble. My favourite items are the rock cakes coated in cornflakes and icing sugar. Then we finished our packing and checked out. We drove back to Pisa on the minor roads, and stopped off at a couple of places on the way.</p>
		<p>Our first stop was a small town called Cescina, where we had a coffee in the main square. Then we went on to the coast, and had lunch in Viareggio. We each had a massive calzone, sitting alfresco with a nice view of the beach and the sea. After lunch we had a walk along the sea front, and looked in some very expensive clothes shops. I saw a nice jacket, but I wasn't going to stretch to 350 Euros.</p>
		<p>We spent the second half of the afternoon in Pisa, after we'd driven round it several times looking for somewhere to park. We did the obligatory photos by the tower, then had a quick dinner. I had a pretty reasonable penne al'arrabiata, and Simon had some revolting bruschetta, which was so salty it tasted like it had been soaked in sea water. We returned the car, and discovered that they hadn't refunded me for the double charge on the insurance, so I'll have to take it up with the bank when I get back. Then we checked in at the airport and sat by the gate until we were ready to go. There were no interesting shops to look at, and we were both just looking forward to getting home. The holiday had some nice moments, but was marred by several irritating moments, so on the whole I'd say it's been an average sort of week.</p>
	</entry>
</diary>