<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Malta" date="09-2010">
	<entry date="07-09-2010">
		<p>When looking for the holiday we had the choice of leaving very early and returning at a reasonable time, or leaving at a reasonable time and getting back very late. At the time, the first option had seemed the least hard, so we found ourselves struggling out of bed at 3am for our taxi to Gatwick.</p>
		<p>I was surprised that all of the airport shops were open that early in the morning, but at least we were able to get a coffee and look round Curry's while we waited for the plane.</p>
		<p>The flight was on time, and took about three hours. We had some nice views of London and Kent at dawn, and of Malta in blazing sunshine.</p>
		<p>At the airport we found the Thomas Cook rep, who organised a taxi to take us to our hotel. The driver told us to expect some great weather. Apparently it hadn't rained since April, and the temperature was about 30 degrees.</p>
		<p>We were staying at the Radisson Blu - a five start hotel in St. George's Bay. The hotel was very nice, and was designed to give the impression of being on a cruise ship. Our room was nice and large, with a balcony looking out over the pool and the sea.</p>
		<p>After settling in, we explored the hotel a bit, down by the shore and around the three pools. We then took a walk down to St. Julian's, via Paceville, to find some lunch. We were surprised by the predominance of English signs and adverts by the roads, and even more so when we passed a Marks and Spencer Simply Food shop. We later saw many UK shops, including Next, Debenhams, and BHS.</p>
		<p>We had lunch at an al fresco restaurant looking out over Spinola Bay. The view was lovely, with clear blue water and colourful local fishing boats moored alongside expensive looking yachts. I was struck by the number of people smoking at their tables. On a table next to us sat a solitary man, with a bottle of wine and a large cigar, just enjoying the view. I had a bowl of pasta with ground Maltese sausage and a delicious blue cheese sauce. It was very rich though, and the portion size was massive. I managed to get a student discount with my Birkbeck card, which obviously made the meal all the nicer!</p>
		<p>After lunch we continued along the coast to the next bay, where there was an imposing limestone church and a lido packed with swimmers and sun bathers. All around the bays were people swimming in the sea, or relaxing on the shore. Most of the beaches were completely rocky. However, the one closest to our hotel was made of sand imported from Jordan.</p>
		<p>We got back to the hotel in the afternoon, and nipped down to the sea water pools for a quick dip. The water was pretty cold, and there was a bit of a wind, so we didn't stay too long, especially after we were invaded by a huge crowd of noisy Frenchmen. We thought we would try the indoor pool instead. I thought it would be relaxing to sit in the jacuzzi for a while. However, the water was freezing and felt more like an ice bath! We didn't stay there long either.</p>
		<p>We headed out to a nearby parade of restaurants to find some dinner, and ended up at an American burger bar called Harry J Beans. The food was reasonable, and we had our first tastes of the local beer, called Cisk. We thought it tasted pretty weak, but it must have been watered down, because whenever we had some subsequently it tasted fine.</p>
		<p>We got to bed in good time, as we were both pretty tired from our early start.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="08-09-2010">
		<p>The hotel serves a buffet breakfast, with a good selection of cooked food, pasties, waffles, fruit and cereals. I pigged out a bit on sausages and eggs. We then went to the Bridge Bar for a welcome talk from our Thomas Cook rep, Christine. She didn't actually seem to know very much, and it was hard to hear her over the noisy chattering of a French couple in the corner. We found out that she had only been here for two months after quitting her IT job in England and moving out here with her partner. We booked a night tour of Malta for this evening.</p>
		<p>After the briefing we decided to catch the bus to Valetta. The buses are quite infrequent, coming every half hour or so, and there are no timetables at the stops, so you have no idea how long you will have to wait for one to arrive. A few of the stops do have a sign with numbers on them, but they don't particularly seem to correspond with the actual buses that stop there. The buses themselves are ancient contraptions, that were used in Britain in the 1950s. With no air conditioning, cramped seats, and generally filled to standing capacity, they were not amazingly comfortable. However, they were extremely cheap. Christine had told us that they were planned to be decommissioned next year and replaced with modern vehicles, so I suppose we could consider ourselves lucky to have a ride on a bit of Maltese history!</p>
		<p>Considering the diminutive size of Malta, I was constantly surprised at the length of time it took to travel anywhere. Of course, this was partly due to the fact that the buses tended to follow the coastal roads, and so wound in and out around the numerous bays. They also virtually came to a standstill when they tried to climb any kind of hill, and I sometimes thought we might have to get out and give it a helping hand.</p>
		<p>Valetta was an imposing sight as we drove round the coast towards it. Perched on a promontory, surrounded by formidable stone walls, the church domes and spires rose from a sea of golden limestone buildings. The bus dropped us off at the terminus, which was actually just a massive roundabout with a statue in the middle. The entrance to the city was across a huge ditch, and standing on the bridge it was hard to imagine and invaders successfully breaching the defences. Although crammed full of tourists, the city itself was very impressive. It had been built on a grid system, with tall buildings and narrow streets to shield the citizens from the sun. A cooling breeze blew through the streets from the sea.</p>
		<p>We stopped to look around the church of St. Francis of Assissi, which was entered by an unassuming door right on the main street. The inside of the church was beautiful, and markedly tranquil away from the bustling crowds on the other side of the door. We spent a while here, and I gave Simon some tips on using his SLR. He now knows how to use a custom white balance!</p>
		<p>Our next stop was the museum of archaeology, which was not especially interesting. It had some information about early settlers in Malta, from around 6000 years ago, and displays of stone chippings and pottery fragments. There were also some stone carvings of figurines from a later period, and an interesting model of the hypogeum, which is the massive underground necropolis.</p>
		<p>By the time we finished at the museum I was getting very hungry, so we stopped for lunch at a cafe. I had a chicken burger, and an iced tea. After lunch we went to look at the co-cathedral of St. John, so called because it supplements the cathedral of St. Paul in Malta's original capital, Mdina. Unfortunately the cathedral was closed as it was a public holiday.</p>
		<p>We then walked down to the end of Valetta to visit the National War Museum. As capital cities go, Valetta is tiny, being about 1000 metres long by 500 wide, so everything was within easy walking distance. The war museum was composed of two parts. The smaller part was about the first world war, while the second was covered in the larger section. There was some general information about the wars, along with a lot of Maltese-specific history. There was a lot to see, and we spent over two hours looking around.</p>
		<p>We made our way back to the bus terminal, and were fortunate to arrive just in time to get the bus going back to St. George's Bay. It took a longer route back though, so we didn't get to our hotel until early evening. We decided to eat at the hotel, as we were slightly pressed for time before our tour. The restaurant was very good. I had an excellent risotto with smoked chicken and asparagus.</p>
		<p>We were picked up by the tour bus at eight o'clock. Unfortunately for us, we then had to stop several times to pick up other passengers, and the tour didn't really start until about nine. Our tour guide was a Maltese lady, and she wasn't very good. On the coach she mainly pointed out irrelevant things like, "on your left you will see Dorothy Perkins and Marks and Spencer", or, "quick, look everybody. There's a limousine!". On the walking parts of the tour she started speaking before everyone had got off the bus, and then spoke so quietly that hardly anyone could hear her.</p>
		<p>Our first stop was at the Upper Barrakka Gardens in Valetta, which a good view over the Grand Harbour. As it was a feast day, many of the churches were illuminated and we saw quite a few fireworks. We next stopped at the 16th century hospital of the Order of St. John, where another guide showed us around the two massive chambers which used to be used as the wards for rich nobles and for commoners. I was slightly dubious when the guide started telling us about the beneficial effects of mercury injections, and that they had to treat AIDs patients in the 16th century!</p>
		<p>The coach then took us to Mosta, to see the church of Santa Maria, which had a Roman style facade and an enormous unsupported dome. We stopped in a cafe for a quick drink, and thought that the owners must make a killing from these buses of tourists. It was then a short drive to Mdina, which was absolutely lovely at night. The city has only three hundred residents, and apart from a couple of other tour groups it was pretty deserted. We had a short walk around the entire city, pausing to admire the extensive views from the walls, and then the coach took us back to the hotel.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="09-09-2010">
		<p>As we didn't get back to the hotel until 12.30 last night, we took the opportunity to have a lie in and a late breakfast. Suitably refreshed, we made our way down to St. Julian's to catch a bus back to Mdina, as we wanted to see it in the daylight. The city was still very pleasant, although we had to get past a gaggle of locals trying to sell us tours or horse drawn carriage trips around the streets. The main street was noticeably busier, with plenty of tourists, but they didn't seem to like to stray off the beaten track, as the back streets were all empty. This suited us, and we walked around feeling the city was all ours!</p>
		<p>We had a quick look around a glass shop, as Mdina was supposed to be famous for its glass. There were plenty of colourful glass ornaments and vases, but we didn't want to buy anything. We had lunch at a cafe with a great view out over the surrounding countryside. The weather was clear, and we could see for miles. I had a ham and cheese sandwich and some water. There were lots of irritating flies that we had to keep swatting away. Fortunately there don't seem to be any biting or stinging insects around though.</p>
		<p>After lunch we had a look round the cathedral and its museum. The cathedral was pretty similar to the one we saw in Valetta. The museum was vaguely interesting, with many silver pieces of Catholic religious vestments, and some centuries old documents from Popes and Kings.</p>
		<p>There wasn't much more to see in Mdina, having decided not to visit the tacky looking dungeons, so we had a short walk into Rabat, which is the next village along. We came to a nice looking church, but didn't go inside. Instead we went to a street vendor, where I got a bottle of water and a very nice chicken arrancina.</p>
		<p>By the time we got back to the hotel it was getting quite late, so we showered and headed out to dinner. Simon had spotted a recommended restaurant in the Lonely Planet called The Avenue, in Paceville, so we gave it a go tonight. The food was good, quite cheap, and came in enormous portions. We sat next to an impressively fat man, and Simon couldn't take his eyes off him as he devoured a massive rack of lamb, followed by the remains of his partner's rack of ribs.</p>
		<p>We walked back through Paceville, along the main road of bars and clubs, which were arranged on a set of stairs down a hill. The place was bustling with party-goers. We then walked alongside the Jordanian beach, and were surprised to see a man sitting on a bench with an owl on his hand.</p>
		<p>We had quite an early night.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="10-09-2010">
		<p>We spent the morning by the pool, and then headed down to Paceville for lunch. We had arrancini at a small cafe in a shopping centre, where there was a television showing a National Geographic programme about hermit crabs.</p>
		<p>We had heard that there were lots of shops around Sliema, so we spent a couple of hours walking there along the coastal road. When we first arrived in Malta, we were often startled by the sounds of screeching tires, as though there was just about to be a horrendous accident. However, we soon discovered that most of the cars seemed to screech whenever they went round a bend. It was still a bit unnerving though.</p>
		<p>During our walk we stopped for a few minutes to watch some boys jumping off a high wall into the bay. It was quite a drop! When we got to Sliema we had a look for polo shirts in Next, but they were all 50% more expensive than in England. We were surprised that all of the clothes shops were so expensive. Most of the restaurants we went to were quite reasonable though.</p>
		<p>We got a bit lost coming back, as we ended up on the wrong side of the bay with a huge shopping centre blocking our way. However, we did get a lovely view of Valetta across the water in the afternoon sun. We stopped off for an ice cream on the walk back, at a place that our night tour guide had recommended. I had two scoops in a large waffle cone, which was very nice.</p>
		<p>After a total of about four hours walking we got back to the hotel, and showered before heading out to dinner. We decided to use our voucher for a free bottle of wine in the hotel bar before going out to a restaurant. We were a bit dubious about the voucher, as we thought it might somehow be attached to a time share promotion, but there were no strings attached. We had a nice bottle of white wine, sitting in comfortable big leather chairs, looking out over the sea. At first we were the only people there, but it soon got quite crowded, as a wedding reception was taking place there.</p>
		<p>We had dinner at a nice local restaurant, where Simon had a lovely risotto with asparagus and pork belly.</p>
	</entry>
</diary>