<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diaries title="St. Lucia" date="04-2013">
	<entry date="09-04-2013">
		<p>It's finally arrived! I've been looking forward to this holiday for ages, and especially as it's still snowing in London. Snowing in April. That's not right! I can't wait to see the sun. The holiday is to celebrate Judy's 60th birthday, and they are very kindly taking Simon and me, and Kathryn and Heath with them.</p>
		<p>I had quite an early start, but it wasn't too bad. I caught the bus from outside my flat at 6.45, and met Simon at Beckenham Junction. We went up to Victoria, then got the Gatwick Express train. I had time to buy a lock for my suitcase from WH Smith in Victoria. The train was very quite, and we pretty much got a carriage to ourselves. We met up with Nick and Judy in Costa Coffee, and then went to drop off our luggage. Nick rather optimistically tried joining the Premium Economy queue, but we all travelled Economy despite Judy's best efforts to wrangle an upgrade.</p>
		<p>Judy and Nick went duty free shopping while Simon and I had breakfast in Cafe Rouge. We got a very nice table by the window, so we could watch the planes taking off. I had a nice plate of eggs Benedict, and Simon had a croque madame. After breakfast I went shopping for a pair of sleeping shorts, as I'd forgotten to pack mine. Simon had a coffee and a read of the paper in the meantime.</p>
		<p>We boarded out place on time, but were delayed taking off due to a couple deciding that they didn't want to go at the last minute. I didn't mind though, as one of them was due to sit next to me, so I ended up with a bit more room. Simon sat next to the window, with me next to him. We were very close to the entrance, and right next to the galley. They didn't close the galley curtain during the flight, so it was a bit noisy, and one of the stewardesses kept dropping things on the floor.</p>
		<p>We were flying with Virgin Atlantic, and had been a little anxious beforehand, since we'd read that they have the least leg room of all the main carriers. It was actually fine though. The seats were pretty comfortable, with adjustable leather head rests. Each seat had a touch screen monitor, with films and music on demand. The picture was good, but the screen wasn't very sensitive to touch, so it took a few attempts to get to see the film you actually wanted. Also of interest, they had just started offering the ability to use your own phone while in the air. I expect the call charges would have been quite high though.</p>
		<p>Simon and I watched Les Miserables together. I'd seen the stage show a couple of times, but Simon hadn't seen any of it before. We synchronised to start the film at exactly the same time. It's a rather long film, so helped to while away a few hours. It was a bit embarrassing though, as we were both in tears quite a lot! I was afraid the meal would arrive halfway through one of the tear jerkers.</p>
		<p>I had chicken curry for lunch. It was alright, but nowhere near as good as we'd got accustomed to flying with Monarch Airlines. The flight was uneventful, which I suppose it what you really want from a flight. We arrived in St. Lucia at  about 5 pm. We had some great views of the island as we came in, including a fantastic view of the Pitons.</p>
		<p>When we arrived we had to wait for ages to let all the first class passengers off the plane first. However, they all got soaked in a tropical downpour, which just stopped by the time we got off. It took a long time to go through immigration, and even longer for our luggage to arrive.</p>
		<p>We were met by a driver who took us to the resort. It couldn't have been further. The airport was on the southern tip of the island, and our resort as far north as you can go. The drive took about 90 minutes. We drove up the west coat, then cut across to the east, drove through the capital, Castries, and finally arrived at Le Sport. It got dark very quickly, so there wasn't much to see for most of the drive.</p>
		<p>We were giving a list to a tour guide who needed to get home. He was pretty talkative, which was nice, but we were all really tired. We had a brief stop at a view point, supposedly to let us stretch our legs, but I think mainly because he wanted a cigarette. He had quite a passionate discussion of cricket and football with Nick and Simon.</p>
		<p>When we got to the hotel we were greeted with cold flannels and a glass of lemonade. There had been some problem with two of the rooms, so Nick and Judy, and Kathryn and Heath have to move into temporary rooms first, and then into their proper rooms a few days later. However, as they were getting complimentary room upgrades they didn't seem to mind the inconvenience.</p>
		<p>We settled in our room, then met up with the others for a pre-dinner drink in the piano bar. All the food and drink is inclusive. I had a Kir Royale. Nick asked the waitress for some crisps, but she told him that it would spoil his appetite! The piano bar has a white Yamaha baby grand. The resident pianist was bashing out a few tunes, but it really needs a good service. There are loads of music books though, so I'm looking forward to having a play on it sometime.</p>
		<p>We had dinner in the Cariblue restaurant. Our table was about twenty metres from the sea. I thought it a very nice touch that they had lit the edge of the shore, so you could see the surf coming in at night. I had battered prawns for started, and then some grilled mahi mahi. It was nice, but a little bland. I also had a glass or two of wine. We then went back to our room and collapsed into bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="10-04-2013">
		<p>We woke up quite early due to the jet lag, but lay in until about 8am. We met the others for breakfast in the Cariblue restaurant. They had all been up for ages, so were just finishing up. The restaurant is very nice. Although there's a ceiling, there are no walls, so it feels like sitting outside. There are lots of wild birds around, and if you're not careful they could land on your table and make off with a sausage! Most of the birds are very attractive, but the black birds with big claws look quite sinister. During the day you can always hear birds singing, whereas at night it's pretty noisy with the ribbiting frogs.</p>
		<p>Breakfast is buffet-style. All the food is in an enclosed, air conditioned room, which is great for keeping it away from the wildlife. Our eyes were popping out of our heads when we saw how much food was on offer. There were sausages, bacon, beans, eggs, potatoes, fried chicken, omelettes, pancakes, several types of fresh fruit, porridge, cold meats, a selection of cheeses, smoked salmon, muffins and pastries, including delicious pain au chocolats that seemed to contain more chocolate than pastry! They also serve very good coffee.</p>
		<p>After breakfast, Nick, Simon and I went up to the archery range for a beginners lesson. The hotel grounds are lovely. We walked past a couple of good quality tennis courts, and a nicely tended golf chipping green, The archery was pretty good fun. There were a lot of us in the group, and only one right handed bow, so we had to wait quite a while between turns. We all at least managed to hit somewhere on the target. It was already getting very hot by 9am, especially in the sun. The sun seems a lot stronger here than in the Mediterranean. I'm being diligent with the sun cream.</p>
		<p>After the archery Simon went swimming, while I made a booking the Heath, Simon and me to go on the introduction to Scuba course on Monday morning. I then saw that the piano bar was empty, so I played for a while. Simon and I had lunch in the Cariblue. It was a buffet again. I had some grilled fish, and a Mexican tortilla wrap. I also discovered the local hot yellow pepper sauce. It's tasty, but extremely hot! Oh, and before lunch Nick and I went to a cookery demo by the head chef. He showed us how to make a Spanish tortilla. Now I know why some of the food is a bit bland: the nutritionist was there as well, and the chef told us that she had to approve every meal. Every time the poor guy wants to do some proper cooking, like frying something, or using some butter, he gets a telling off! So the tortilla had no seasoning, and instead of frying the potatoes and onions he boiled them. It was alright, but tasted far too healthy!</p>
		<p>In the afternoon I went snorkelling with Simon. The guardian of the snorkelling gear was a big fat man who seemed very reluctant to give out any equipment. He made us promise that we would go snorkelling immediately, and then return everything the instant we finished, as he didn't want them left out in the sun. We had a really nice time though. There were loads of fish, even right at the edge of the shore where we put on our fins. The sand is also very nice here. Apparently they spent a million dollars shipping it in to build the beach, as the local sand wasn't good enough. The sea was nice and warm.</p>
		<p>Once we'd finished, Simon went to the piano bar to attend one of the talks, while I rushed back to the beach hut to return our snorkelling stuff. I was going to come to the talk with Simon, but by the time I arrived they were all sitting in a little group, so I didn't want to interrupt. I waited until they'd finished, then I played some songs on the piano while Simon sang. A staff member came in and said that we were very good!</p>
		<p>At 5pm we went for our first treatment. The holiday includes a spa treatment every day. It was up at the wellness centre, which was styled like an Indian palace. It had a very tranquil atmosphere. We had already been there briefly, earlier in the day, for a free skin consultation. The therapist popped some blackheads out of my nose, then tried to sell us some expensive treatments. My nose felt quite sore afterwards!</p>
		<p>Our first free treatment was a aloe vera body wrap. It didn't start off well when I almost kicked the therapist in the face. She should have asked whether I had ticklish feet first! I lay on a sheet of cling film, and she rubbed some cold lotion on me, then wrapped me up to stew for a while. While I was so restrained she gave me a face massage. It felt like a Vulcan was trying to mind meld with me. Once I'd got nice and sweaty she unwrapped me and let me go.</p>
		<p>We met the others for a pre-dinner drink in the piano bar. The pianist wasn't there, so I played a couple of songs and Simon sang. I can't help myself when there's a piano around. We got a nice round of applause though. Dinner was in the Cariblue, followed by another early night.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="11-04-2013">
		<p>It was very hot again today. Walking on the sand in bare feet is pretty painful! After breakfast, Simon and I went up to the wellness centre for a stretching class. We spent three quarters of an hour stretching, and I felt quite achy afterwards. I then went for a waterskiing lesson while Simon found a sun lounger on a patch of grass by the beach. I had three circuits on the water skis and only fell over once, although it was quite an impressive face first splat into the sea.</p>
		<p>Before lunch I tried out one of the hammocks by the beach. It was quite comfortable, but I was a bit scared that a bird might poop on my face! I then sat in the jacuzzi with Simon, and had a nice banana and coconut milkshake.</p>
		<p>We had pizza for lunch. It was quite nice, but we could tell that the nutritionist had got her claws into it! After lunch we discovered the library, which was a lovely big room with board games, books, a big television showing The Masters, and a nice pool table. We must have spent a couple of hours playing pool.</p>
		<p>Our treatment today was a lime and ginger body scrub. It felt a bit sore getting rubbed with an abrasive lotion, but it felt heavenly when she was scrubbing all over my itchy mosquito bite. Apparently Nick fell asleep during his treatment and was snoring.</p>
		<p>We went for afternoon tea after our scrubs, and I had a scone with jam and whipped cream. Then we had a few drinks in the piano bar, so dinner was quite late. I had a crab and salmon terrine, then some steak. I also had several  glasses of rum and coke. Well you can't come to the Caribbean without trying the local rum!</p>
		<p>After dinner we played some more pool. This time it was doubles with Nick and Judy. I had some more rum. I'm sure it made my playing better. When Nick and Judy went to bed another couple asked if they could play with us. We beat them quite soundly! The it was time for us to go to bed too.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="12-04-2013">
		<p>We sat by the pool for most of the morning. Somehow I wasn't feeling too hungover! We had to get some sun loungers quite early, as people tend to leave their towels down to reserve them for the whole day. Fortunately we managed to get a space in the shade, as the sun was blisteringly hot. Simon read a book while I just relaxed. I had a nice gin and tonic, then a banana milkshake. I saw a lizard, and a small hermit crab scuttling along beside the pool.</p>
		<p>We had a little swim in the pool. Simon practised diving to the bottom and trying to equalise his ears. He has a bit of a cold, so is slightly worried about trying diving on Monday. There was an Indian themed buffet for lunch today, which I thought was very nice. The others had been off playing golf this morning. Heath won the same, but said that it had been really hot. Kathryn enjoyed driving the buggy.</p>
		<p>After lunch I played pool with Simon, then had a couple of games of backgammon in the library. Even though we play pretty much every holiday, we can never remember how to set up the board! Maybe we should carry some instructions around with us.</p>
		<p>My back was quite sore today. I think it was due to the combination of the vigorous stretching and the waterskiing. I was meant to be diving this afternoon, but I had to cancel.</p>
		<p>We had hand and foot massages this afternoon. At last no scraping or mind melding. I found it very relaxing. Simon said that he could hear me chatting to the therapist from next door. I hadn't realised you were supposed to be quiet! It feels a bit weird to just lie there like a slab of meat while someone works on you. Judy caught herself snoring during her massage. I think massages have the opposite effect on me. I ended up think about work!</p>
		<p>We had some afternoon tea, then I played on the piano while Simon sang. The bar started to fill, but everyone seemed quite happy, so I carried on. Another guest asked if he could sing while I played, so Simon went for a shower while I stayed in the bar. I found a book of Les Mis songs, so I couldn't help myself singing along. I got lots of rounds of applause, and some people asked if I did this professionally! I lost track of time and was a bit late for dinner.</p>
		<p>We had a barbecue in the bar by the beach. It was so hot and humid that I really didn't have much of an appetite, so I just ate a chicken wing and a strip of beef. After dinner we all went to the library to play pool. We took turns playing doubles. Judy says she's never played before, but like with golf she must be a bit of a bandit! Simon was feeling really hot and had a sore throat, so we didn't stay out late. Luckily our room is nice and cool, and the bed is really comfortable. They leave a nice tea pot with herbal tea for us every evening, but we've always been too tired to make it.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="13-04-2013">
		<p>Simon hadn't slept very well, having to keep getting up to blow his nose. Judy had booked both tennis courts for us at eight o'clock. We got up around half past seven, and I Skyped mum and dad, who had just got back from their holiday with uncle Brian and aunty Hazel. They were round at Steven and Nikki's. Steven was just putting Sam to bed, so we didn't get to see him.</p>
		<p>It was already really hot by the time we got down to the tennis courts. I started off playing with Nick, while the others made up a foursome. He beat me three games to two. I started getting the hang of it again after a while. I then teamed up with Heath, while Simon played with his dad. They had us down three games to nil, but we made a massive comeback and won 4 – 3!</p>
		<p>I had an extremely softly boiled egg for breakfast. In fact it was pretty much still raw. I didn't eat it. I did have a few glasses of refreshing coconut water though. Then we went back to the room and I Skyped mum again. This time Sam was up, so we showed him the view of the sea and the pool from our window.</p>
		<p>Simon was feeling under the weather, so he stayed in the room and had a snooze while I went for a walk with Nick. We walked all around the resort, which is actually quite big and hilly. I took a lot of photos and a few videos. I then went to the library and had a banana milkshake ad an iced tea while I caught up on writing my diary. Simon came down and we played a bit more pool before going to the barbecue place for lunch. Simon had a pepperoni pizza, and I had some grilled pork. We had a bit of pudding in the Cariblue restaurant.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon we got a bed by the infinity pool. This was not just a sun lounger. It was a full four poster bed. There were about six of them around the pool, each with drapes you could lower to shade from the sun. Simon read his book while I went and sat in the pool. Then I did some sunbathing on the bed, and watched Judy doing an aquarobics class in the pool. It looked far too energetic!</p>
		<p>I found Simon in the library watching The Masters. We played some pool, and I had a couple of cocktails. We both then had a swim in the infinity pool before heading up for our daily treatment. Today it was the full body massage. We were given the option of a calming massage, or an invigorating one. I opted for invigorating. It was very good, but a bit painful. There was also quite a lot of slapping, which Simon and some other guests said they could hear from their own treatment rooms. I think it's helped to loosen up my back though. Simon went for the calming massage, but it sounded like his therapist was a bit brutal too.</p>
		<p>We went back to the room for a shower and change of clothes, and I took some photos of the sunset from our balcony. Then I went round to Nick and Judy's room for a pre-dinner bottle of bubbly. Simon was feeling exhausted, so he stayed in out room and had a sleep. Fortunately he was feeling well enough to come for dinner, as we had booked in at the Tao restaurant. The food is still inclusive there, but is better quality than the regular restaurant. The service was extremely slow. It took two and a half hours to have a three course meal. The food was really lovely though.</p>
		<p>We started with an amuse bouche of a single sushi roll with ginger, soya sauce, and a little ball of wasabi. Luckily Kathryn told Judy to avoid the wasabi, as she didn't know what it was, and had already found the pickled ginger to be a bit hot. The wasabi would have blown steam out of her ears!</p>
		<p>I had a really tasty clam for my starter, on a bed of sesame glazed glass noodles. Simon had chicken satay. I then had a delicious Thai seafood laksa. By the time we'd had dessert we were feeing really tired, so we left the others to have coffees, and went back up to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="14-04-2013">
		<p>By the time Simon and I got down to breakfast the other had already played tennis and had a stretch class. They were just getting ready for aquarobics while I was tucking into my corned beef hash. Judy and Nick's friends, Philip and Jenny, had arrived at the resort and stopped by to say hello to Simon. Simon was still feeling unwell, but a bit better than yesterday.</p>
		<p>We found a couple of sun loungers by the pool and spent the morning reading our books. It's very decadent having drinks brought to us by the pool. Someone wanders around every now and then with a tray of glasses of Pimms. If you want a drink at any other time you just put up a flag by your lounger, and a waiter will come to take your order. I've even seen a waiter swimming out into the sea to deliver drinks to people on lilos! It makes a big difference to know that the drinks are included.</p>
		<p>We had lunch in the Cariblue restaurant. I had  spaghetti bolognaise and some beef pie, with anchovies, stuffed vine leaves, and grilled fish. A nice eclectic mix. We spent the afternoon back on our sun loungers reading, then went up for our coconut back massages. We just avoided getting drenched in a downpour that came on suddenly, but only lasted about five minutes. Then we had afternoon tea, and Simon took some photos before getting ready for dinner.</p>
		<p>We had a few drinks in the piano bar first, before dinner in the Cariblue. I had calamari to start, and honeycomb cheesecake for pudding. The food wasn't amazing tonight. I was surprised at the big difference in quality between the regular restaurant the the Tao.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="15-04-2013">
		<p>We tried Skyping mum several times before breakfast, as we wanted to wish her a happy birthday, but we couldn't get through. I later found out that she was enjoying a three course lunch at Marco Pierre White's restaurant at the time.</p>
		<p>After breakfast I did the introduction to Scuba diving course with Heath. Simon was originally going to come as well, but was still feeling very congested. We had one other girl on the course with us. We sat through a PADI video about the wonders of diving, then spent half an hour in the pool learning how to recover our regulators and clear our masks. After this we went for a dive from the shore. The water was warm and calm, and I didn't need a wet suit. Almost straight away I spotted a stonefish, which I pointed out to the instructor. There were lots of fish and sea urchins. Most of the sea bed was covered in rocks, but there were also quite a few interesting corals. I also saw a trumpet fish, a bright orange crab that was hiding in the flute of a coral, and another crab that looked like a big spider. It wasn't a deep dive. I think we got down to about eight metres. Heath said that he enjoyed his first dive.</p>
		<p>While I was diving, Simon had been on a walk around the resort with Nick. Judy had suggested that they walk to Pigeon Island, but I think that sounded a bit too strenuous! Simon took quite a few pictures. I met up with him after my dive, and we played a couple of games of pool before I went for a shower. We had lunch at the barbecue grill, then went to the Cariblue for dessert.</p>
		<p>In the afternoon Simon went snorkelling while I had a doze. We had full body massages at five o'clock. I opted for the relaxing version this time. Afterwards Nick, Simon and I visited the little tourist shop to say hello to the shop assistant Rose. She is very friendly. Nick had fun flirting with her! She made me try on a Rastafarian cap with fake dreadlocks, and they all had a good laugh.</p>
		<p>We all met in the beach bar before dinner, and got another guest to take some group photos of us. We went back to Tao again for dinner tonight. It was excellent again. I had crab cakes to start, and gripped mahi mahi with risotto for the main course. The amuse bouche was some king of deep fried cream cheese. Nick was very happy was the head chef showed him around the kitchen. He bought us a round of Admiral Rodney rum, which was very nice. The service was slow again though, taking two and a half hours again.</p>
		<p>I got round to making our pot of herbal tea tonight. I did manage to get through to mum when I tried at lunchtime.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="16-04-2013">
		<p>Our last day. It's gone very quickly. We didn't do much in the hotel today. After breakfast Simon and I sat by the pool and read our books, had a swim, and sat in the jacuzzi. Nick, Judy and Heath played in a golf competition, which Heath won! He was given a polo shirt.</p>
		<p>We had pizza for lunch, and a last banana milkshake. Our driver got confused about what time to pick us up. It was meant to be at two o'clock, but he thought it was three. Luckily the hotel sorted it out, and he arrived at half past two. Nick and Judy waved us off, as they've got another three days to go.</p>
		<p>The taxi ride back took just over ninety minutes. It was nice that it was during the day, as we got to see a bit of St. Lucia. It was very bumpy though, and I felt quite car sick by the time we got to the airport. I bought some hot yellow pepper sauce from duty free, and had an ice cream. Out flight was delayed by an hour, which I suppose wasn't too bad. I spent the time catching up on my diary.</p>
		<p>The flight was uneventful.</p>
	</entry>
</diaries>