<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Tasmania" date="12-2003">
	<entry date="08-12-2003">
		<p>I am looking forward to Sam and Lynette coming to stay with me.  They’ve been in Australia for one week now, and are due to arrive today, to spend the next two weeks in Tasmania.</p>
		<p>The weather has recently been gloriously sunny, and I was hoping that it would stay that way for them, but unfortunately they were met by grey skies and cold winds.  In addition, their flight from Melbourne was delayed for several hours, and due to a misunderstanding I became convinced that they had actually flown into Launceston or even Hobart, rather than Burnie.  It was with some relief that I saw Lynette pop her head out of the airport door.</p>
		<p>The delays had been pretty tiring, so they looked slightly nervous when I said that I’d planned a busy evening for them.  They had in fact been invited to a barbeque at Caroline’s apartment, just down the road from where I live, and then I’d asked some friends to meet us in McKinties pub in town.  They had time to settle in and relieve the pressure on their bulging rucksacks, letting them disgorge their contents explosively over the bedroom floor.  This bombsite remained in pretty much the same state until some 10 minutes before they left, two weeks later.</p>
		<p>I dropped them off at the barbeque, as I was running late for choir practice in town.  After being locked out of the church, and forced to return home to retrieve my spare set of keys, they were none too impressed when I stumbled in 20 minutes late: it’s not too easy rehearsing ‘The Messiah’ unaccompanied.</p>
		<p>Once I got back to the party and had some left over food (I think they’d tried cooking for fifty!), it was getting a bit late to go down to the pub.  Besides, with all the free flowing beer and wine, who wants to drive into town?  Sam and Lynette seemed to be getting on well with everybody, although I did have to save them from the overly eager attentions of a certain doctor.</p>
		<p>The girls retired to bed around midnight, and I stayed another hour chatting with Caroline and Miriam, and catching up on the two hour’s drinking I’d missed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="09-12-2003">
		<p>Oooh, hangover!</p>
		<p>Fortunately I’d remembered to drink some water before bed, so managed to escape most of the alcoholic retribution.  And so it was that with bleary eyes and shaky hands I performed major surgery on Sam.  Well, I exaggerate slightly.  Sam had a small mole which had been catching on her belt, so after registering with the dragon receptionist in A&amp;E, the three of us wandered through to the procedure room.  Now you may be wondering why it needed three people.  Well, there was Sam, the patient; myself, the doctor; and Lynette, official photographer.  Picture the scene – Sam lying on the treatment bed, giggling like a woman possessed; the hung over doctor madly chasing the mole over the patient’s wobbling belly; the photographer turning an interesting shade of green, and trying to take pictures with her eyes covered.  Good thing my consultations don’t usually unfold this way!  I left Sam with a small wound, edges neatly opposed with four stitches, and the troublesome mole winging its way to the lab.  After all that, Lynette needed a good strong cup of tea.</p>
		<p>By lunchtime my headache had passed, and Lynette was looking less nauseated, so we decided to head for the Groovy Penguin café for lunch.  This was to be found in Penguin, a small town along the coast from Burnie.  The thing about Penguin, is that it’s penguin mad.  There are penguins everywhere, from small black and white rubbish bins with wings, right up to the monolithic giant penguin on the foreshore.  Throughout the year this may be the forbidding guardian of the town, but today it was wearing a giant Santa costume, and it would be a struggle not to find it adorable.  Our search for lunch was proving tricky, as the Groovy Penguin was closed, and there didn’t seem to be anywhere else serving food in town.</p>
		<p>Undaunted by this black roll of Fate’s dice, we continued along the scenic coastal drive to Ulverstone.  This is the next town along the coast, and is slightly bigger than Penguin.  Other than that, there’s not much else to say about the place.  The weather had picked up, and my stomach was demanding attention.  By the harbour side we found a nice seafood restaurant called Pedro’s.  I ordered a plate of fresh Tassie oysters, of which Sam was game enough to try one.  From her expression I don’t expect she’ll be ordering more oysters any time soon.</p>
		<p>After momentarily satisfying my eternally hungry belly we drove back to Burnie, and to the Lactos cheese factory to sample their produce.  I had expected some kind of tour, but we had to make do with the shop and free samples.  We bought some cheese, smoked salmon, and Sam had an ice cream of which Lynette ‘tasted’ a very large portion.  Stocked with provisions, we then drove next door to Fernglade reserve, on a hunt for the elusive platypus.  After looking for a couple of minutes, we gave up.  The creatures are obviously too wary of us.  (We later found out that we had been looking in the wrong spot, and that there were plenty to see 200 feet further along the river.)</p>
		<p>Before returning home for the day, we drove up to Ridgely to have a look at one of my favourite waterfalls – the magnificent Guide Falls.  They weren’t as roaringly exciting as on my last visit, as there has been a recent dearth of rain, but it was a very pleasant walk, and interesting to see the falls in a new light.  Lynette noticed a rather large ant, and spent the whole walk looking at the floor, and scratching herself.</p>
		<p>alk looking at the floor, and scratching herself.
	Although I said that I had nothing more to say about Ulverstone, I lied, and will mention it one more time.  Before leaving the town we picked up some black hair dye from there.  On arriving back home, Lynette deftly changed the tips of Sam’s hair from blonde to, well not quite black, but an interesting shade of purple.  Everyone was satisfied with the result, so we had a nice civilised dinner of smoked salmon and cheese salad, washed down with a glass or so of vino rosso.  I left the girls to entertain themselves at home, while I went for another choir rehearsal, this time in Wynyard.  Lynette found my ‘Mr. T in your PocketTM’ personal Mr T. impersonator device, and Sam was pretty much tearing her hair out by the time I got home, from being told to ‘shuddup fool!’ and ‘quit your jibber-jabber’ all evening.  What a great toy!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="10-12-2003">
		<p>I’ve got a few days’ respite from choir commitments, so we have decided to spend some time away from Burnie.  And so it is that we find ourselves back on the road by late morning, heading for St. Helen’s on the east coast.  There is to be a significant amount of driving over the next few days, and with this in mind I have burnt a few music CDs from my laptop to keep us occupied.</p>
		<p>Now, all was going well until we changed discs – uh oh, that sounds remarkably similar to the first CD.  Try another disc – Double ‘uh oh’! What crazy fool has made three identical CDs?  However, the situation was not as bleak as the picture I’m painting, as fortunately only the first few tracks had been duplicated.  We were very sick of ‘The Waifs’ after just a few hours!</p>
		<p>We arrived in a picturesque town called Deloraine in time for lunch.  We parked by the river, and made our way up to an Italian-style restaurant which had caught our attention on the way in.  The food was pretty good, and once finished we made our way back to the car through a light drizzle.</p>
		<p>This soft pattering of rain soon became a deluge, so I aquaplaned the car to a stop outside the Leatherwood Honey Factory at Mole Creek.</p>
	</entry>
</diary>