<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Turkey" date="09-2014">
	<entry date="13-09-2014">
		<p>Just to put this holiday in context, I finished moving all the furniture out of my flat in Bromley yesterday, having only exchanged contracts on Monday. So it's been a bit of a stressful week; I really need a holiday!</p>
		<p>Mum and Dad gave us a lift to Gatwick, picking Simon up from Beckenham on the way. We got to the airport at about 11:30, and went to Frankie and Bennie's for lunch after checking in, where we had burgers and macaroni cheese. We didn't have much time to look around the shops before boarding.</p>
		<p>Our flight left just about on time. The plane seemed pretty new, and we had plenty of leg room. We were a bit worried when a family with two young children sat in front of us, but they turned out to be very sweet, although one of them kept licking the top of his seat. They seemed to be happy watching Ben and Holly. Simon was happy playing a game on my tablet.</p>
		<p>When we landed at Dalaman airport we had to wait quite a while for a bus to arrive to take us to the terminal. It seems that they hadn't been expecting us. We then had to wait ages for our bags. We ended up leaving on the coach at half past nine, and didn't get to the Andirake resort in Demre until just before 1 am. We were given a glass of wine on arrival, and then went up to our room. We had booked the trip quite last minute, and so I think we got just about the last room. The hotel is completely full. This did mean that we managed to get a suite on the top floor at a good discount. We were amazed at the size of it, with a massive bedroom, lounge, and two bathrooms. It's also got a balcony with a lovely view over the pool and the sea.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="14-09-2014">
		<p>We both slept very soundly last night, although it wasn't long enough! We went down to breakfast at about a quarter to nine, where there was a typical Neilson buffet. We sat outside to eat, and it seemed like everyone had come down at the same time as it was really packed. We then had to sit through about 45 minutes of welcome chat, which was a bit boring, especially as we were tired.</p>
		<p>After the welcome meeting we queued up to book several activities, then went down to the beach for a safety briefing. We had a quick snooze before lunch, then made our way to the spa for our hammam experience. We sat in a marble steam room while Curly and Sparticus (not their real names) scrubbed us, covered us in warm bubbles, then tipped bowls of hot and cold water over us. It was quite fun.</p>
		<p>We spent the afternoon by the pool, sunbathing, reading and swimming. The pool is Olympic sized, so seemed like it took for ever to complete a length! We had ice creams and a beer, then had a shower before dinner, where I had a pretty nice barbecued seabass. We then chilled out in our lounge (in the west wing of our suite!), before heading to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="15-09-2014">
		<p>We both slept very well, and had a bit of a lie in. After breakfast we took our books down to the pool, and found a couple of free sunloungers. We were surprised that there were so many free spaces, seeing as the hotel is pretty big, and wondered where everyone goes. I did twenty lengths before lunch, but got some water in my ear which I couldn't shift, so was pretty deaf on one side for the whole rest of the day.</p>
		<p>We had a long lunch, and sat afterwards having a nice chat and coffee. Then we played some table tennis, before heading back to the pool. The weather has been very good so far. It's about 32 degrees, but low humidity, and with quite a nice breeze coming onshore from the sea. We haven't seen a single cloud yet.</p>
		<p>Before dinner we went to a short talk on the nearby sunken city, which we were planning to visit the next day. It was given by a young guy called Cemil, which is pronounced 'Gemil', so most people called him Jimmy. The city was Lycean, and sank into the sea about 3,000 years ago, during a series of earthquakes. We also learnt that Cemil is training to be a freediver, and he impressed us with some diving facts, such as the world record for someone holding their breath was 17 minutes, which is the same as a beaver.</p>
		<p>Dinner was a buffet again. Some of the food is nice, such as the freshly grilled fish, but a lot of it is overcooked. I had some beef stew which was pretty much unchewable. Because we've got two toilets in our suite, we've decided to keep the smelly business in the one furthest from the bedroom. As this is in the west wing, we now refer to 'going to brief the president', and hope he doesn't need to declare defcon 1!</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="16-09-2014">
		<p>I still couldn't hear in my left ear this morning, so I was feeling quite unhappy that. Simon was very empathetic, but unfortunately there was nothing he could do to help. We headed down to reception at 9:30 to catch a minibus to the harbour, which was about 10 minutes drive away. Outside the resort the countryside is very dry and dusty. Demre is an agricultural town, with an emphasis on growing tomatoes, so there were rows of plastic growing tubes all over the place.</p>
		<p>There were about twenty of us on the sunken city tour today. The sea was very calm, so we had a lovely smooth ride along the coast, looking out for loggerhead turtles. Interestingly, the Turkish seem to call them by their scientific name of Caretta caretta. We did see a few briefly popping up their heads, which got everyone very excited. The sunken city was quite interesting, although you couldn't see much beneath the water. However, there were quite clear stone steps leading down from the shore into the sea, and some walls with square indentations cut into them, where beams would have been sited to make two story houses.</p>
		<p>On the way back we stopped off in a secluded cove to do some snorkelling. We were told to look out for octopuses and turtles, but there wasn't a great deal to see. There were a reasonable number of small fish, and I saw a long black tube-like creature on the sea bed, which was probably a sea cucumber. I had hoped that doing some duck diving might clear the blockage from my ear, but all it managed to do was block up my other ear as well, so now I was really quite deaf. Simon also suffered from the snorkelling. He scrapped quite a bit of skin off his feet and toes from the fins. Other than that we had a nice time though!</p>
		<p>When we got back I went straight in the shower, and aimed the spray into my ears. After a minute, I could suddenly hear again. What a relief!</p>
		<p>We had initially booked to go on a bike trip to the Myra tombs this afternoon, but cancelled it when we realised we wouldn't get back in time for the excursion out for dinner. So we spent the afternoon reading, before catching a minibus back the the harbour at 17:30. It was quite windy by now, but the water was still pretty calm, so we stood right up on the roof of the boat to enjoy the view and the sunset. The captain said that he would point out any turtles that he saw, but as we drew near to the village he hadn't seen any. As he turned to face us he said, "I'm sorry we haven't seen any turtles this evening", at which point Simon shouted out, "There's one behind you!". The turtle had popped its head up with perfect comic timing.</p>
		<p>We stopped off for dinner at a small island. Simon and I explored a little first, climbing up to the fort at the top of the hill, then walking along a track to see some ancient tombs that were shaped like tiny houses. As it got dark we headed back to the restaurants by the shore, and saw a few bats.</p>
		<p>We had dinner at a small place where pretty much the rest of our party were, down by the sea. We had lamb kebabs and chips, along with a couple of Efes beers. The food was quite nice, but not as good as Uskudar back in Petts Wood. We had to hang around until 21:45 for the boat trip back. This was rather special, lying on the roof of the boat looking up at the stars. It was a moonlit night, and with little light pollution there were lots of stars to see. We could even make out the Milky Way quite distinctly. We got back quite late, and went straight to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="17-09-2014">
		<p>We spent the morning by the pool, had lunch, then played some table tennis. The forecast was for storms today, so we were a bit worried about sunbathing this afternoon, but the onshore wind just managed to keep the clouds off us. We did hear a few crashes of thunder though.</p>
		<p>At 4 pm we headed over to the spa for our massages. Simon went for relaxing, and I opted for vigorous. The therapist said that I had very knotted shoulders, and she certainly had a determined attempt to relieve them. It felt very nice when she was rubbing over the mosquito bite on my arm.</p>
		<p>We stayed out by the pool until the sun went down, then had showers before dinner. Simon got excited by a large, elaborate chocolate truffle cake, but was disappointed by the taste. After dinner we headed down to the sports bar by the tennis courts to see if they'd be showing the Champions' League Chelsea match, but were scared away by the fact that the bar was in darkness, with just the Turkish bar man slouched on a chair watching TV. I played the piano in the reception for a while, but couldn't remember much off by heart. The piano was also badly out of tune, but Cemil was tonight's receptionist and he seemed to appreciate it.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="18-09-2014">
		<p>We kept an eye on BBC news today, to see what was happening with the Scottish independence referendum vote, but there wasn't much of any substance yet. The weather was very nice again today, and we spent most of the day either by the pool, in the pool, or playing table tennis. I finished the second of my Ben Aaronovitch books. We had beers and ice creams sitting by the pool.</p>
		<p>Dinner tonight was a barbecue. It was slightly oversold on the brochure, with descriptions of sizzling sausages and succulent prawns. There were no sausages, and the prawns were overcooked. We did have a nice bottle of wine though.</p>
		<p>Afterwards we played a bit of table tennis, then went to reception where Cemil printed out the Pathetic Sonata for me. Simon was my page turner. Cemil was looking very tired, apparently as the receptionists aren't allowed to sit down during their eight hour shifts.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="19-09-2014">
		<p>We checked the news over breakfast, and found out that the Kingdom would still be United when we got back. We were pleased to see Alex Salmond resigning later in the day!</p>
		<p>The weather was nice this morning, so we decided to take out a boat. As we hadn't been sailing for a couple of years, we asked for a stable boat. The Turkish staff member didn't understand, so called over one of the British reps to help. This was one of the problems with the resort: government regulations specified that they had to employ 80% local staff, and a lot of them couldn't speak much English. In addition, some of them were quite surly and really looked like they didn't want to be working there, which was a bit of a shame.</p>
		<p>We took out a Hartley two person dingy, and had great fun sailing around the bay for an hour and a half. We took turns steering. I almost capsized once, but somehow managed to keep us upright, although did let out a panicked yelp of, "We're going in!". And then I did capsize, just as we were coming in to the shore. Well, I had to keep things exciting!</p>
		<p>After lunch there was the most almighty thunderstorm. The lightning was striking very close, and we'd never heard thunder so loud. It was very dramatic. It absolutely tipped down for about half an hour, then the afternoon was sunny again.</p>
		<p>We went to the in-resort shop and purchased some goodies to take back as presents, then played some more table tennis. I was getting better, but Simon still thrashed me. We had a nice swim, then brought some drinks up to the room, to have in our lounge before dinner. Simon's double gin and tonic cost as much as a litre of the stuff in duty free.</p>
		<p>After dinner we played a bit of table tennis, then watched TV before going to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="20-09-2014">
		<p>I woke up this morning to Simon doing a little dance and singing Happy Birthday. I then had a lovely surprise of birthday balloons in the lounge, which Simon had cunningly blown up during the night. He gave me a funny card of a dog dressed like Superman, jumping out of a plane, and a game for my new PS4. He had actually bought me two games, but the day before we left he saw that I had already bought the second one. He's going to let me choose a replacement when we get home.</p>
		<p>We had a nice breakfast, and then went out to play tennis. The court was AstroTurf, and nice to play on. It was quite hot, but we had a really good time. I was happy with my serve, which was getting pretty consistent. Afterwards we went straight to the pool. Simon even jumped in with his tennis shorts still on! The water was refreshing but quite chilly, so went didn't stay in too long.</p>
		<p>We spent the rest of the morning by the pool, and Simon got me a birthday Pina Colada. What a nice birthday, sitting by the pool drinking a cocktail! Simon was lovely, and kept saying, "Happy birthday" to me the whole day.</p>
		<p>After lunch we packed our suitcases and checked out, then got on the coach back to Dalaman. The journey was nice, with very pretty countryside. We made a stop off at a device station, which we were surprised to find contained a swimming pool with sun loungers. It seemed to be doing quite good business.</p>
		<p>We got to the airport in good time, and had some dinner at Pizza Hut. We shared a pizza with sucuk: a Turkish sausage. It seemed to be exactly the same as pepperoni. We were slightly alarmed when the boarding status for our flight switched from 'check-in open' straight to 'last call', but we think it was just a ruse to get us to the gate quickly. We were on the same plane as we had on the way out. I know because I recognised the stain on my seat. We took off about 10 minutes early, and dad picked us up from a chilly Gatwick.</p>
		<p>I had a lovely birthday, and a lovely holiday.</p>
	</entry>
</diary>