<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<diary title="Vienna" date="04-2003">
	<entry date="02-04-2003">
		<p>We woke up hideously early (well, 5.30am), and Sam very nicely brought me a cup of coffee.  I drove to Heathrow, and luckily the traffic was pretty good, as we had left quite late.  We parked at the off site car park, and were driven in by a mad Italian (or possibly French) driver.  He was listening to Classic Fm, and couldn’t stop conducting the music with his head.</p>
		<p>We checked in pretty quickly, and I had a thorough frisking to wake me up (I had forgotten to take my phone out of my pocket), then we had breakfast at Café Uno Pronto.  We had a little time left for duty free shopping, where I impulsively bought a new laptop from Dixons.</p>
		<p>The flight was with Austrian Airlines, and left pretty much on time.  Lynette was sitting next to me, and I realised she didn’t care much for flying when her sweaty hands started slipping off the seat rests.  The flight was an hour and three quarters, which we passed by watching Disney cartoons.</p>
		<p>On arrival at Vienna, we briefly considered catching a train into town, but gave up when we couldn’t understand any of the German instructions.  We caught a taxi instead, which was reasonably cheap, and took half an hour.  The weather was pretty gloomy, but it hadn’t started raining yet.</p>
		<p>Our hotel was called Tourotel, on Mariahilfer St.  Our room was nice, but quite basic: no mini bar!  We had bought a guide book at Heathrow, and now decided to have a wander down to one of the Churches mentioned.  It had started to rain, and the whole city seemed very bleak and dirty to us – not what we were expecting at all.  We had a late lunch at a place called Café Westend.  It was quite smoky (a lot of the people here seem to smoke, and there’s a noticeably large amount of cigarette advertising), but the food was quite nice.  The waiter recommended some Viennese specialities – Sam had a Schnitzel, and Lynette and I had some boiled beef with apple and horseradish sauce.  We tried walking down to the river, but it turned out we had read our map wrongly.  Instead, we found an imposing looking church with dark red spires.  I don’t think it was a tourist attraction though, as all the lights were off when we went inside.  Eventually we worked out where we had gone wrong, and so made our way down to the river Vien.  This, we found to be a rather nondescript river, more like a dirty canal.</p>
		<p>After what seemed like hours of walking we neared our destination, and came upon an interesting looking building with a ball of gold laurel leaves on its roof.  This was the Secession building, created to house alternative art.  We decided to have a look inside.  Downstairs was a room containing the Beethoven Frieze by Gustav Klint.  It was a representation of Beethoven’s nine symphonies.  I wasn’t overly impressed, although it looked like a lot of it hadn’t been restored.  We then went upstairs to see a collection of photographs by a modern artist.  They were of everyday people and things, and although some of them were attractive, there were quite a few of slaughtered animals and other disturbing subjects.  My favourite was of a roast lamb dinner – yum!</p>
		<p>Once we had finished looking round the Secession, we made our way over to the Karlskirche (St Charles’ Church).  Unfortunately, the museum portion was just closing, so we had a brief look around the church.  It had an attractive exterior, with a smelly lake at the front, and interestingly, two large columns depicting the labours of Hercules almost identical to the one in Rome.  The interior of the Church was somewhat spoiled by the massive amount of scaffolding erected, to enable people to go up and have a close up view of the roof fresco.  We followed a couple of Priests and thought we were going out, but actually just managed to avoid entering a side chapel where they were about to conduct a service.  I don’t imagine sitting through Mass in German would have been a great experience.</p>
		<p>By this time we were getting tired, after our early start and all the walking, so we started to head back to our hotel.  On the way we stopped of in Starbucks and had a coffee, and in Virgin where I bought a cheap computer game (and the only English one in the shop) to have something to install on my new computer!</p>
		<p>We got back to our hotel, and after a struggle with our room door lock (it involves a lot of pushing, pulling and twisting to open), I lay down and slept for a couple of hours.  When I woke up we all felt too lethargic to go and find some dinner, so we watched a bit of TV then went to bed.</p>
	</entry>
	<entry date="03-04-2003">
		<p>We woke up late, at around 9am, and made our way down to breakfast.  The restaurant is attached to the side of the hotel, and I had some cold meats and cheese with a roll and coffee.  Our big achievement today was working out the public transport system – no more long walks!  We caught the underground up to Schottentor, where there were a couple of interesting places listed in our book.  The first was the Josephinium, a museum of the history of medicine created by Emperor Joseph II as an academy for military surgeons to study anatomy from wax models.  There were two main areas to the museum, the first having a lot of historical photographs and medical instruments, and the other containing the wax models.  These were imported from Florence, and were very detailed, so much so that Lynette had to sit down from feeling queasy!</p>
		<p>By the time we finished there we were feeling thirsty, so we went to a local café for a drink.  The weather was much nicer today, and we actually got to see the sun at points.  After we had quenched our thirst we wandered over to the Narrentum – a circular building constructed as a mental hospital, but now a museum containing a “gruesome medical chamber of horrors”.  Unfortunately it was shut.  Never mind, I should be trying to get away from work while I’m on holiday!</p>
		<p>On our way to lunch we stumbled across a magnificent cathedral in the middle of a square.  This was more like the Vienna we had expected.  Half of the cathedral was filthy with years of pollution, but the other half had been cleaned and looked resplendent in the sunlight.  Inside it was pretty dark, and quite plain, apart from some pretty stained glass windows.</p>
		<p>We had a very nice lunch in a café – I ate a beef goulash with dumplings, sausage and a fried egg.  The portions are pretty big, and I was well stuffed, to put it nicely.</p>
		<p>We had been looking forward to spending some time in a proper museum, and we spent the afternoon in the Kunsthistorisches – the Museum of Art History.  It was set in a fabulous building, opposite an identical building which housed the Natural History museum.  The ground floor contained an Egyptian wing, with a nice collection of statues, sarcophaguses and a small blue hippopotamus which our guide book listed as one of the highlights of the museum.  Upstairs was a nice collection of paintings, including pieces by Rubens and Raphael.  The top floor housed a selection of model buildings by a modern day architect.  He took his inspiration from birds, and his models looked very graceful. They were also interactive, with some models having buttons to push which would turn on lights or make bits move.</p>
		<p>We went back to the hotel for a short rest before dinner.  We were a little pushed for time, so we ate in the hotel restaurant, which was called Wienerwald.  It had a bit of a thing for chicken.  I had chicken soup for starter, then a chicken breast with rosti potatoes for the main course.  I didn’t dare try dessert.</p>
		<p>The reason we were rushing is that we had to make our way to the Schonbrunn palace.  We were actually visiting the orangery at the side of the palace, for an evening concert.  The orange trees had thankfully been replaced with chairs, and it was quite an intimate setting, with a reasonably small audience.  The small chamber orchestra included a piano, flute and clarinet, and they played a mixture of Mozart and Straus.  It was a very entertaining evening, and the orchestra played a lively selection.  There were a pair of ballet dancers for some of the pieces, and a very engaging baritone and soprano for the arias.</p>
		<p>We enjoyed our evening so much that we are going to try and book another concert before we leave.</p>
	</entry>
</diary>